<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lake on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/lake/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lake on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>ajka-andrej.com powered by [Hugo](//gohugo.io). Theme inspired by [PPOffice](http://github.com/ppoffice).</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 21:37:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/lake/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spitzingsee</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/02/01/spitzingsee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 21:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/02/01/spitzingsee/</guid>
      <description>Today, we went skiing to the lake Spitzingsee. The temperature dropped to -10 and predicted sunshine showed up just before lunch, but skiing was great. Good maintained slopes and only few people caused that we already had enough around the lunch and we returned back home quite tired. I didn&amp;rsquo;t took a lot of pictures, only one panorama after which I seriously had to warm up my hands. But I hope to fix that this summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/11/08/walking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 21:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/11/08/walking/</guid>
      <description>I love autumn from several reasons. It&amp;rsquo;s not so cold yet, but also not so hot anymore and so you can wrap yourself in a warm blanket and relish a cup of tea. The weather outside is just amazing and stable and the sky can be unbelievably blue. And those colours &amp;hellip; as we moved we travel about ten minutesto work through a forest and that is so wonderful look that fits well immediately after waking, but also to relax after work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ebersberg</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/08/31/ebersberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 07:19:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/08/31/ebersberg/</guid>
      <description>Recently, we spent some time searching for a new apartment and beside this activity we discovered various places where we haven&amp;rsquo;t previously been. We were fascinated by one such a district town at very first visit and so we went there during one weekend again to get to know it a little bit more. We already get used to the plane everywhere in Munich (I don&amp;rsquo;t count those few artificial hills there) and we were very pleasantly surprised by the hilly terrain of the town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olympiaberg</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/10/olympiaberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 13:11:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/10/olympiaberg/</guid>
      <description>We were already several times in the Olympia park, but we somehow never got to the highest hill there. To walk on its top is not really difficult, but either the weather didn&amp;rsquo;t work out for us, or we were already tired from walking through the town so we ended up just resting near the lake below. There is a nice paved walkway leading up to the top of the hill that is great view point as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easter trip</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/04/27/easter-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 21:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/04/27/easter-trip/</guid>
      <description>Last Friday we went to Easter trip. We had a beautiful warm weather, around 25 degrees and I saw a newspaper tip for a nice trip to a waterfall. I thought that in this lovely April weather everything is melting and so there could be a lot of water. After a small survey, I found two other even bigger waterfalls near the original one. From parking places it was up to 20 minutes walk to each one and so we decided to see all of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walchensee</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/03/31/walchensee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 08:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/03/31/walchensee/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend, we went on a trip to the lake Walchensee. It&amp;rsquo;s about an hour from our home by car in a beautiful environment surrounded by the mountains. This time we didn&amp;rsquo;t go alone, but we took our visitors as well. The weather was amazing and was also pleasantly warm although, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t warm enough to melt all the snow on the hills above. Near the lake we took a cable-car and we travelled four minutes about 800 meters higher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holiday in Grainau</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/30/holiday-in-grainau/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2011 17:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/30/holiday-in-grainau/</guid>
      <description>This time we traveled only about an hour and a quarter by car from our home to the village Grainau. We wanted to ski and get to know our surroundings better. We stayed in a very nice and cozy house with a great breakfast (Gasthaus Geigener). The weather was quite good, we skied whole the week except the two days and my darling named our vacation week assembly.
     One snowy day, we made a train trip to the nearby Tyrol village Lermoos and then we went back to Garmisch Partenkirchen, where we found a great Italian restaurant for lunch and we saw the ski springboard and slopes for the upcoming World Championships.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schliersee</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/15/schliersee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2010 20:58:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/15/schliersee/</guid>
      <description>So finally, we made one of our planned trips ( I have 37 more trips in my tourist guide :)). Although in Munich the weather was nice and sunny, 40 minutes southern by our car led to mountains covered by clouds. But it didn&amp;rsquo;t discouraged us and we set off on the path leading us around the lake Schliersee.
 The environment there was really beautiful. It is possible to rent a boat there and we also found the Wellness centre with a swimming pool, slides, sauna and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the way to Slovakia and back</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/06/on-the-way-to-slovakia-and-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 13:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/06/on-the-way-to-slovakia-and-back/</guid>
      <description>As a part of running in our new car we went to Slovakia. All the traffic jams somehow managed to escape or be removed, until we got to them. And given the rainy weather, we had no taste to stop anywhere making a break, so after six hours we arrived to our destination. Lights were turned on automatically, wipers as well as appropriate, Andrej pretty much just pressed buttons of cruise control until Bratislava and in the meanwhile I studied controlling of theair-conditioning andsurroundingbuttons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake in the Olympia park</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/07/05/lake-in-the-olympia-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2010 19:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/07/05/lake-in-the-olympia-park/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve already written about the Olympia park, but that was in November last year and at that time there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any lake but the muddy place and some people who cleaned it. Fortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s the great place for visitors due to the high tower in the centre so we had a great opportunity to go there with our friends and see the actual lake :) There were many people running around or cycling, lot of stands with ice-cream or some sweet cakes and of course many people sitting in the bier garden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zurich</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/17/zurich/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2010 18:23:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/17/zurich/</guid>
      <description>We were somehow tired enough not to go seeing night Zurich on Saturday evening, but I think it must be beautiful. We went there the next day and I really loved the atmosphere of that city. If there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any snow, I think we are in one of the coastal towns somewhere in Italy (possibly in France, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never been there). There were many narrow streets and nice colorful buildings with wooden shutters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A trip toward lakes</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/17/a-trip-toward-lakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2009 06:46:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/17/a-trip-toward-lakes/</guid>
      <description>Finally, after two and half months, I and Andrej have been together again and as we got the car for a couple of days, we decided to go for a trip somewhere. However, the parking in Munich is not the best idea and we wanted to use the car more useful, so we drove toward two lakes near Munich - Starnberg See and Walchensee. Starnberg See is the second largest lake in Bavaria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trip to Zaruby hill</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/07/06/trip-to-zaruby-hill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 13:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/07/06/trip-to-zaruby-hill/</guid>
      <description>As we have been together again for a little bit longer time than usual, we decided to go somewhere for a nice trip. This time we chose mountains Male Karpaty with the aim to go to the highest hill Zaruby (768 m). And to make this trip more interesting, we visited ruins of two castles on the road. On Saturday morning we travelled to Plavecke Podhradie, where our trip began and after 20 minutes of hiking we could observe ruins of the first castle Plavecky hrad.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>