<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travelling on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/categories/travelling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travelling on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>ajka-andrej.com powered by [Hugo](//gohugo.io). Theme inspired by [PPOffice](http://github.com/ppoffice).</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 21:13:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/categories/travelling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Autumn hoiday at the sea</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/09/30/autumn-holiday-at-the-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 21:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/09/30/autumn-holiday-at-the-sea/</guid>
      <description>This year&amp;rsquo;s summer holiday ended up as an autumn holiday. With September coming, itwas suddenly time for rain, wind and less sunshine. So I packed all the things like waterproof trousers, jackets and boots and we set off. We were outside all day long, even though it was raining. Dominik joyfully jumped in puddles and Olivia danced in the rain. With the kids on their bouncing bikes, we went through both parks (camping Italy and Union Lido), with stops on all the playgrounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vychylovka and Stará Bystrica</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/09/03/vychylovka-and-stara-bystrica/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 20:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/09/03/vychylovka-and-stara-bystrica/</guid>
      <description>When the weather is bad, you need to find a place where it&amp;rsquo;s better and so we made a trip from Stefanova, immersed in clouds, to the historical forest railway and open-air museum of Kysuce village in Vychylovka. Our children were enthusiastic about the train, sheep and playgrounds and we enjoyed &amp;ldquo;živánska&amp;rdquo; in a local restaurant :) And after a pleasant walk among the wooden houses we stopped in Stara Bystrica to see the only astronomical clock in Slovakia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vrátna valley</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/09/01/vratna-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 20:59:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/09/01/vratna-valley/</guid>
      <description>We wanted to eat some proper slovak food specialties like halušky, pirohy and šúľance, relax and relish the nature and so we made a culinary trip to Štefanova in Vrátna valley. We made a trip to a cottage on Grúň and under Chleb and on every trip we found a playground or sheep, so our children were more than satisfied.
                </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cavallino</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/09/22/cavallino/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 20:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/09/22/cavallino/</guid>
      <description>We ended this summer with a trip to Italy. This time we were in one camping park near to Venice. On the way there we passed the Alps through many tunnels and after each tunnel Olivia said: &amp;ldquo;more&amp;rdquo;. The park was like a big village with lots of trees, nicely groomed and clean. There already were less people in tents and caravans, but the camping homes were quite busy. There were mostly families with children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Half a year old</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/09/04/half-a-year-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 09:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/09/04/half-a-year-old/</guid>
      <description>Olivia managed another growth spurt (together with us). From what I read, we bore this quite well. She didn&amp;rsquo;t lose her appetite, quite the opposite. She didn&amp;rsquo;t cry too much, just started to realise the distances and occasionally gurgled, when she saw me going away from the room. But she slept less. In the evening, she always woke up after one hour of sleeping full of energy and ready to play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November Wallberg</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/11/17/november-wallberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2012 07:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/11/17/november-wallberg/</guid>
      <description>There are already many articles about this hill on our web page and I need to say that it&amp;rsquo;s one of our favourite hill. But two weeks ago, we had such a nice visit, to my great pleasure longing for trips led by a almost three years old young tourist. And so we went on trips to many places and one of them was Wallberg. It&amp;rsquo;s clear to me that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to convince Andrej to go there otherwise (certainly not in November and not at all in that snow except the sledding).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kampenwand</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/10/28/kampenwand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 19:02:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/10/28/kampenwand/</guid>
      <description>This was the only trip (not counting the local trips in the forest and cycling), which we managed to do during the summer. I planned more of them, but thanks to my incredible fatigue, I was glad that we were able to get at least here. Kampenwand itself is a rocky hill with a cross at the very top (the largest one in the Bavarian Alps), but the name is used to identify all the surrounding tourist area with lots of hiking routes, cottages and chapels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cala Ratjada</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/07/01/cala-ratjada/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 10:48:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/07/01/cala-ratjada/</guid>
      <description>This year, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t decide where to go on holiday. My usual desire for trips became unbalanced due to the work fatigue and it was replaced by a new desire (very unusual for me) to go to sea on a beautiful sandy beach and at most to make a trip to some of the local restaurants for culinary specialties. Andrej couldn&amp;rsquo;t believe his ears (after all those years with me, he has experienced many things but he only dreamed quietly about such a vacation with me when we became a couple) and a sudden panic seized him, what we&amp;rsquo;re actually going to do there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sudelfeld</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/03/11/sudelfeld/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2012 16:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/03/11/sudelfeld/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, we went skiing again. This time we chose Sudelfeld ski resort. Our colleague told us that it is a little bit small and local, but less people know about it and therefore it usually is not so crowded on Saturday. The weather was absolutely fantastic, there were really not so many people and we were quite surprised when we found that it is not as small as we heard. In addition, it is a great place for skiing with children with lots of children&amp;rsquo;s short and mild slopes and help with all lifts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spitzingsee</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/02/01/spitzingsee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 21:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/02/01/spitzingsee/</guid>
      <description>Today, we went skiing to the lake Spitzingsee. The temperature dropped to -10 and predicted sunshine showed up just before lunch, but skiing was great. Good maintained slopes and only few people caused that we already had enough around the lunch and we returned back home quite tired. I didn&amp;rsquo;t took a lot of pictures, only one panorama after which I seriously had to warm up my hands. But I hope to fix that this summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skiwelt Wilder Kaiser</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/01/26/skiwelt-wilder-kaiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 22:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/01/26/skiwelt-wilder-kaiser/</guid>
      <description>We spent last two Wednesdays skiing in neighbouring Tyrol in the ski resort Wilder Kaiser. Every time we parked in another town, we went to the highest possible place by a cable car and then we skied cross over the hills everywhere where we could get by the ski lifts. The weather was absolutely fantastic and I took some pictures as well.
                    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sledding</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/12/29/tehotenstvo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 00:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/12/29/tehotenstvo/</guid>
      <description>We went sledding during our Christmas holiday to relax and spend our time wisely :) Here are some pictures from the last year. This time, we set off earlier and so we basically had the whole track for ourselves. I tried to make some videos during the sledding ( on steeper sections it&amp;rsquo;s a bit shaky because I had to brake too). The experience was again absolutely terrific. In between, we refreshed ourselves in the panorama restaurant on the hill, warmed up on the sun and I took a panorama from that beautiful view around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wendelstein</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/09/02/wendelstein/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 22:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/09/02/wendelstein/</guid>
      <description>Finally, we went on a tour we had already planned for early summer. Somehow, it always rained or we were not at home and so I could only study our route theoretically. But last week we had an ideal weather and so we set off on the trip in the morning. We parked next to the cable-car station just outside the village Osterhofen and then we hiked three hours and three quarters up the hill Wendelstein 1838 m (at least we thought so according to a tourist guide, in fact, we went up two and half hours).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ebersberg</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/08/31/ebersberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 07:19:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/08/31/ebersberg/</guid>
      <description>Recently, we spent some time searching for a new apartment and beside this activity we discovered various places where we haven&amp;rsquo;t previously been. We were fascinated by one such a district town at very first visit and so we went there during one weekend again to get to know it a little bit more. We already get used to the plane everywhere in Munich (I don&amp;rsquo;t count those few artificial hills there) and we were very pleasantly surprised by the hilly terrain of the town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nature trip</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/10/nature-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 22:19:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/10/nature-trip/</guid>
      <description>Since urban tourism is quite difficult, and as we don&amp;rsquo;t want to destroy our visitors (we would like them to come again), we have always at hand some trip to nature. Neither last Saturday it was different and we went to our quite favourite place, on the hill Wallberg. Up and down we drove a cable-car, but then we hiked to the top of the peak (about half an hour). The chapel, which was reconstructed is already nice and finished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olympiaberg</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/10/olympiaberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 13:11:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/10/olympiaberg/</guid>
      <description>We were already several times in the Olympia park, but we somehow never got to the highest hill there. To walk on its top is not really difficult, but either the weather didn&amp;rsquo;t work out for us, or we were already tired from walking through the town so we ended up just resting near the lake below. There is a nice paved walkway leading up to the top of the hill that is great view point as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easter trip</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/04/27/easter-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 21:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/04/27/easter-trip/</guid>
      <description>Last Friday we went to Easter trip. We had a beautiful warm weather, around 25 degrees and I saw a newspaper tip for a nice trip to a waterfall. I thought that in this lovely April weather everything is melting and so there could be a lot of water. After a small survey, I found two other even bigger waterfalls near the original one. From parking places it was up to 20 minutes walk to each one and so we decided to see all of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walchensee</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/03/31/walchensee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 08:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/03/31/walchensee/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend, we went on a trip to the lake Walchensee. It&amp;rsquo;s about an hour from our home by car in a beautiful environment surrounded by the mountains. This time we didn&amp;rsquo;t go alone, but we took our visitors as well. The weather was amazing and was also pleasantly warm although, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t warm enough to melt all the snow on the hills above. Near the lake we took a cable-car and we travelled four minutes about 800 meters higher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garmisch-Classic</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/31/garmisch-classic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 20:51:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/31/garmisch-classic/</guid>
      <description>This is another option (not counting the Tyrolean Alps around the corner) to go skiing when you are in Grainau. And not only that. Cable cars operate here also in the summer and there is a wide variety of hiking trails offered by the hills.
    One of the black slopes was closed due to the preparation for the World Championships (5a on the slope plan), but we didn&amp;rsquo;t miss it at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zugspitzplatt</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/31/zugspitzplatt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 07:53:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/31/zugspitzplatt/</guid>
      <description>I must say that this place is simply wonderful. We haven&amp;rsquo;t been to Zugspitze (the highest peak in Germany, 2962m), because we somehow couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop skiing in such a beautiful weather. But we agreed that we would make this trip in the summer.
 I&amp;rsquo;ve never really thought about the name of the peak until now, when I found out that you can go just below it by train (der Zug).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holiday in Grainau</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/30/holiday-in-grainau/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2011 17:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/30/holiday-in-grainau/</guid>
      <description>This time we traveled only about an hour and a quarter by car from our home to the village Grainau. We wanted to ski and get to know our surroundings better. We stayed in a very nice and cozy house with a great breakfast (Gasthaus Geigener). The weather was quite good, we skied whole the week except the two days and my darling named our vacation week assembly.
     One snowy day, we made a train trip to the nearby Tyrol village Lermoos and then we went back to Garmisch Partenkirchen, where we found a great Italian restaurant for lunch and we saw the ski springboard and slopes for the upcoming World Championships.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skiing in Laax</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/10/skiing-in-laax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2011 08:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/10/skiing-in-laax/</guid>
      <description>This year I made several New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions (I will sometimes write about them). One of them is to ski this winter properly. Before Christmas, we decided to visit our friends in Switzerland and we were going to look at several ski resorts near Zurich. But this plan failed, because during our planned weekend heat wave arrived from Spain and at 1100 m it was suddenly 7 degrees. Finally, we opted for the more distant, but higher placed resort Laax, where we were skiing at around 2500 m at a pleasant temperature just below zero.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sledding</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/20/sledding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2010 15:11:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/20/sledding/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend, we took advantage of a good weather after a long week of snowing and went sledding. We&amp;rsquo;ve already been on the Wallberg hill for hiking before. This time we used the cable-car on the way up and we sledded down the hill.
We borrowed sleds each separately, but later we agreed that next time we&amp;rsquo;ll sled together as it requires an appropriate weight. Andrej was faster and he didn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;fly&amp;rdquo; after each bump on the road.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wallberg</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/24/wallberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2010 13:22:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/24/wallberg/</guid>
      <description>This time we went a little higher on the hill Wallberg (1722m) and so we increased the elevation to 927m. To get there, we travelled around the Tegernsee lake, which looked beautiful from above. We parked next to the cable-car station and began hiking. You can find more pictures in the gallery.
 Right at the beginning of our journey, we found out that the first cottage, where we wanted to go, was closed (on the winter version of the route) and so we decided that we would take it up with a bit steeper but shorter summer route.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schliersee</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/15/schliersee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2010 20:58:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/15/schliersee/</guid>
      <description>So finally, we made one of our planned trips ( I have 37 more trips in my tourist guide :)). Although in Munich the weather was nice and sunny, 40 minutes southern by our car led to mountains covered by clouds. But it didn&amp;rsquo;t discouraged us and we set off on the path leading us around the lake Schliersee.
 The environment there was really beautiful. It is possible to rent a boat there and we also found the Wellness centre with a swimming pool, slides, sauna and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rozbehy and Korlátka</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/07/rozbehy-and-korlatka/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2010 13:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/07/rozbehy-and-korlatka/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend, on the occasion of the nice weather and a meeting with our parentsafter Christmas, we went on a small trip. It was pretty much only a nice walking within afternoon rest, but in the warm weather it was quite weary and I think more people from our group appreciated that the road back led through the forest. From Cerová we went on the winding road up the hill into a neighbouring village Rozbehy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the way to Slovakia and back</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/06/on-the-way-to-slovakia-and-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 13:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/06/on-the-way-to-slovakia-and-back/</guid>
      <description>As a part of running in our new car we went to Slovakia. All the traffic jams somehow managed to escape or be removed, until we got to them. And given the rainy weather, we had no taste to stop anywhere making a break, so after six hours we arrived to our destination. Lights were turned on automatically, wipers as well as appropriate, Andrej pretty much just pressed buttons of cruise control until Bratislava and in the meanwhile I studied controlling of theair-conditioning andsurroundingbuttons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake in the Olympia park</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/07/05/lake-in-the-olympia-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2010 19:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/07/05/lake-in-the-olympia-park/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve already written about the Olympia park, but that was in November last year and at that time there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any lake but the muddy place and some people who cleaned it. Fortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s the great place for visitors due to the high tower in the centre so we had a great opportunity to go there with our friends and see the actual lake :) There were many people running around or cycling, lot of stands with ice-cream or some sweet cakes and of course many people sitting in the bier garden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bavaria</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/07/05/bavaria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2010 13:17:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/07/05/bavaria/</guid>
      <description>This was one of my less fortunate trip ideas, but on the other hand I don&amp;rsquo;t regret at all that I was there. The question Where? is now on the right place &amp;hellip; in the statue called Bavaria. Recently, we had a second visit here and after a day spent walking in the center and parks, we were thinking, where to go next. I read that there is a statue that was created and built as a symbol of Bavaria, it is 18 m high and it is possible to go in, upstairs and look around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Porto</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/04/13/porto/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 09:12:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/04/13/porto/</guid>
      <description>I would like to share my impressions from another country with you. I visited Portugal two weeks ago. I already knew that it is the lovely country as we went toMadeira for our honeymoon, but I found out that there is still so much to explore. My Portuguese friend also recommended me to go to south west coast for beautiful sceneries and relax, to relish sun and Atlantic ocean. So I consider it as a very nice inspiration for a future holiday This time I traveled to Braga for a Serious games conference and I spent several hours in Porto.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paris</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/04/12/paris/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 19:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/04/12/paris/</guid>
      <description>Finally, I visited Paris, the city considered as a one of the most romantic places in the world or at least in the Europe. Well, I&amp;rsquo;m sure I don&amp;rsquo;t need to go there to have a perfect romantic atmosphere, but it is a nice place, worthy of visiting. What I enjoyed the most were trees on each street and loads of small parks everywhere. Typical French buildings with little balconies with metal railings, small cafés with outdoor sections and of course bakeries with fresh baguettes made this town somehow special.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zurich</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/17/zurich/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2010 18:23:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/17/zurich/</guid>
      <description>We were somehow tired enough not to go seeing night Zurich on Saturday evening, but I think it must be beautiful. We went there the next day and I really loved the atmosphere of that city. If there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any snow, I think we are in one of the coastal towns somewhere in Italy (possibly in France, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never been there). There were many narrow streets and nice colorful buildings with wooden shutters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bern</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/16/bern/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 19:18:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/16/bern/</guid>
      <description>After Friday traveling, chatting and walking among lovely Swiss houses in our surroundings, we went to a capital city - Bern. It&amp;rsquo;s quite small but very cute and there are bears all around :)Well, I mean pictures, symbols and statues in the shape of the bear. There are many nice historical buildings and arched underpasses with small shops everywhere. There are loads of Italian restaurants, shops with chocolate and pralines and of course shops with watches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How we went to Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/16/how-we-went-to-switzerland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 17:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/16/how-we-went-to-switzerland/</guid>
      <description>Our friends &amp;ldquo;chrobaci&amp;rdquo; invited us to visit them and we simply couldn&amp;rsquo;t say no :)After a long working week, Andrej took two days off, we rent a car, checked on a google map how to get there, packed some things and set off a journey. We turned on a navigation and as it showed approximately good amount of kilometers and time of arriving, we relied on it.We came to Bodensee lake (which is really huge) and when we suddenly left the highway and stayed on the right side of the lake in Germany, we started thinking if the navigating is right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>English garden</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/25/english-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 21:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/25/english-garden/</guid>
      <description>To be honest, I have no idea why this park is called Englischer Garten (English garden). Maybe because it is well-adjusted with properly cut lawn and pretty paths. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest public parks and it&amp;rsquo;s also obviously very popular for relax and walking, doing some sports or just for sitting and reading a book. This park actually reminded me the Central Park in Manhattan, but this one is even larger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Munich</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/24/munich/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 21:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/24/munich/</guid>
      <description>I have never been to Munich before and I feel those few days I spent there weren&amp;rsquo;t enough. I love the historical flair of this city. There are no high modern glass buildings preventing the sun shine to the street, but low stylish buildings with sloping red roofs. There are loads of bakery and little kiosks with pretzels everywhere. Since I love to ramble marketplace, what I have probably inherited from my daddy, I was unbelievable happy to see one directly in the city centre called Viktualienmarkt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A trip toward lakes</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/17/a-trip-toward-lakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2009 06:46:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/17/a-trip-toward-lakes/</guid>
      <description>Finally, after two and half months, I and Andrej have been together again and as we got the car for a couple of days, we decided to go for a trip somewhere. However, the parking in Munich is not the best idea and we wanted to use the car more useful, so we drove toward two lakes near Munich - Starnberg See and Walchensee. Starnberg See is the second largest lake in Bavaria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bradford</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/10/22/bradford/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 18:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/10/22/bradford/</guid>
      <description>I visited another English town, called Bradford. I spent around three hours by travelling by train so I had enough time to find out more about the cathedral, shopping centres, main square and the University of Bradford where I went for conference.
       The town was quite nice and I had good weather as well (surprisingly :)). The only thing I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect was that I felt a little bit like I was in Near East as I met many Arabic guys and I saw many specialised shops with clothes and food typical for that countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rockefeller Centre</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/10/22/rockefeller-centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 16:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/10/22/rockefeller-centre/</guid>
      <description>My two friends were in New York at the end of September and it remained me that I have two more panorama pictures from the &amp;ldquo;big apple&amp;rdquo;. I took them at the top of the Rockefeller Centre. Although I need to say that I prefer the beautiful views from the top of hills not from buildings, these place was amazing.
 There were many people as everywhere, but we could move freely and took pictures of whatever we wanted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trip to Zaruby hill</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/07/06/trip-to-zaruby-hill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 13:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/07/06/trip-to-zaruby-hill/</guid>
      <description>As we have been together again for a little bit longer time than usual, we decided to go somewhere for a nice trip. This time we chose mountains Male Karpaty with the aim to go to the highest hill Zaruby (768 m). And to make this trip more interesting, we visited ruins of two castles on the road. On Saturday morning we travelled to Plavecke Podhradie, where our trip began and after 20 minutes of hiking we could observe ruins of the first castle Plavecky hrad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philadelphia</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/06/21/philadelphia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 20:26:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/06/21/philadelphia/</guid>
      <description>Philadelphia is the town I could write about for hours. I really enjoyed this place. We spent there four nice sunny days and I don&amp;rsquo;t regret it. Well, there were two my ideas we could avoid, otherwise everything was great. First, I didn&amp;rsquo;t listen to my brother and I chose the hotel where we stayed. It was fine, the room wasn&amp;rsquo;t too big and continental breakfast turned to bagels and cereals, but the interesting thing about it was a room window, which was oriented to the interior of the hotel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London expo</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/06/21/london-expo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 10:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/06/21/london-expo/</guid>
      <description>I went for three days business trip to London. It was really nice, sunny and quite warm weather, but I relished that only during the evenings because I spent whole days inside talking on exhibition. I have never gone by London underground before, so I was little bit curious about it. I started at Euston with the aim to go to the Excel exhibition centre, thus I spent under ground almost one hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the trip to USA</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/05/01/on-the-trip-to-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 17:52:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/05/01/on-the-trip-to-usa/</guid>
      <description>Finally, after a long time of promising, we visited Miško and Ivka in faraway America. We set off at four in the morning, so we could catch a flight from Vienna ( I&amp;rsquo;m really thankful that I have so great parents, that they got up so early and gave us a lift there). We flew with a very small planeto Dusseldorf, where we had a famous pretzel, coffee and I bought a big package of Haribogummibears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hotel Orca Praia</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/09/05/hotel-orca-praia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 23:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/09/05/hotel-orca-praia/</guid>
      <description>After one week of living in this hotel we can recommend it :). It&amp;rsquo;s built in the rock so every room is turned towards the ocean. The funny thing was that they counted floors from zero to minus ten. Good advice is to not live lower than minus eight floor because these rooms are without the balcony and you can see trees right in front of your windows instead of the ocean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Funchal</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/09/05/funchal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 23:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/09/05/funchal/</guid>
      <description>Funchal is the biggest town of Madeira and its centre was about six kilometers from our hotel which was walkable distance. There are many restaurants, shopping areas, museums and parks where you can spend lovely time. The only thing is that this town is a little bit noisy now, because they are building many hotels and block of flats everywhere. That was one of the reasons why to stay in a hotel in a quiet and peacefull place away from the town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>East Madeira</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/09/05/east-madeira/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 20:52:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/09/05/east-madeira/</guid>
      <description>One way how to get known some part of this beautiful island is to go for a bus trip and travel across the mountains and along the coast. We saw so many beautiful things, untouched nature, traditional houses, completely different land in the north part and in the south. Once you go up through the layer of clouds after the forest, mountains appear before your eyes and you feel like in a paradise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poseidon gardens</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/23/poseidon-gardens/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 11:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/23/poseidon-gardens/</guid>
      <description>We went out on a day trip to Poseidon gardens in the middle of the week. We were little bit afraid of the hot termal water in the swimming pools in such a warm weather and we had also sunburn more than it&amp;rsquo;s appropriate in the hot water :) We had concern about the weather when we saw first time the only hill on the island covered with the grey clouds in the morning, but after breakfast, swimming in the pool and reading on the sun beds we set off for the trip towards the Citara beach and Poseidon gardens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trips through the Ischia</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/23/trips-through-the-ischia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 11:19:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/23/trips-through-the-ischia/</guid>
      <description>You can make as many trips as you want on this island and you will still find some other places where to go. I can say that one week is not long enough for it. If you like hiking you need to see the vulcan which is responsible for all the thermal springs around the island. The name of the vulcan is Monte Epomeo and it is still active but it is not seen outwardly (except the springs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honeymoon</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/20/honeymoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2008 19:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/20/honeymoon/</guid>
      <description>We finally found the right place for our honeymoon. It is a wonderful tiny island in Atlantic Ocean, which belongs to Portugal. The island of Madeira is lapped by the waters of the Gulf Stream, so there is nice warm weather. There are beautiful botanic gardens, mountains and views of the ocean and many nice people with their own traditions. We spent there wonderful time and took a huge amount of pictures as well:) You can read more here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hotel Corona***</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/06/30/hotel-corona/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2008 18:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/06/30/hotel-corona/</guid>
      <description>After a long decision making we decided to stay in this hotel. We booked it even in a sale through the travel agency so the price was really good. After arriving to the hotel we met a nice lady at the reception, who was willing to explain us, where is our room, when the time for the breakfast and dinner is and she also gave us a little key from the gate to short private path towards the beach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forio</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/06/30/forio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2008 17:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/06/30/forio/</guid>
      <description>This is the town were we lived in a wonderful hotel Corona, which we can only recommend. It is said to be the most visited place by tourists on the island. It has several beaches (we saw and tried all of them), nice centre, several churches and countless streets, which are worth walking. This town is also famous by wine production and amazing thermal park Poseidon gardens.The most famous church is Soccorso&amp;rsquo;s church devoted to Santa Naria delle Neve, which can be seen in the movie Avanti!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evergreen island - Ischia</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/06/28/evergreen-island-ischia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2008 20:44:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/06/28/evergreen-island-ischia/</guid>
      <description>We spent a wonderfull week in Italy last summer. We decided to get known an evergreen thermal island Ischia and people who live there. We tasted several food specialities and relish thermal spa with plenty of thermal springs and swimming pools. The sun was shining, a pleasant wind was blowing when we rest on the beach and we felt like in paradise.This picturesque island could be also characterized by huge lemons and sweet grapes, which we tried several times.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>