<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ruins on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/ruins/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ruins on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 16:32:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/ruins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer memories</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/10/03/summer-memories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 16:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/10/03/summer-memories/</guid>
      <description>There was no time to write about summer holidays. But at least, I would like to post some photos now. Olivia wanted to mount a go kart with her grandpa and she drew a frame for it in the kindergarden. This year we managed to swim a couple of times in the swimming pool in the backyard, ride horses (I had to as well, because I was afraid that the horse was too big for Dominik) and we made a trip to Korlátko (about an hour of walking) and we walked through the Dolné diery in Vrátna valley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schliersee</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/15/schliersee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2010 20:58:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/15/schliersee/</guid>
      <description>So finally, we made one of our planned trips ( I have 37 more trips in my tourist guide :)). Although in Munich the weather was nice and sunny, 40 minutes southern by our car led to mountains covered by clouds. But it didn&amp;rsquo;t discouraged us and we set off on the path leading us around the lake Schliersee.
 The environment there was really beautiful. It is possible to rent a boat there and we also found the Wellness centre with a swimming pool, slides, sauna and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trip to Zaruby hill</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/07/06/trip-to-zaruby-hill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 13:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/07/06/trip-to-zaruby-hill/</guid>
      <description>As we have been together again for a little bit longer time than usual, we decided to go somewhere for a nice trip. This time we chose mountains Male Karpaty with the aim to go to the highest hill Zaruby (768 m). And to make this trip more interesting, we visited ruins of two castles on the road. On Saturday morning we travelled to Plavecke Podhradie, where our trip began and after 20 minutes of hiking we could observe ruins of the first castle Plavecky hrad.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>