<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dailylife on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/categories/dailylife/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dailylife on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 20:57:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/categories/dailylife/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dominik is 3 years old</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/07/28/dominik-is-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 20:57:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/07/28/dominik-is-three/</guid>
      <description>Dominik is already three years old. When we congratulated him in the morning, he only frowned at us. He accepted the fact that he has his birthday first with a cake in the afternoon. But on the next day, he celebrated proudly and enthusiastically with his friends in the nursery. Two months ago he started to ride a bicycle. He cannot start riding by himself, but then he rides great and Olivia is happy as well, because we can finally ride together at about the same speed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New in May</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/05/26/new-in-may/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 20:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/05/26/new-in-may/</guid>
      <description>Firstly, we celebrated a May festival in the nursery. Chidlren helped to prepare and paint a maypole and they learned a new song. Then, on the day of the celebration, the maypole was errected, the children garnished gingerbread hearts, made a picnic in the garden and played.
We made also a trip to the zoo in Munich. We only dressed lightly because of the warm weather and our memories of concrete surfaces without any shade in another zoo and we set off in the morning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative Easter</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/04/24/creative-easter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 20:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/04/24/creative-easter/</guid>
      <description>While we were waiting for the spring, we spent a lot of time doing creative activities. Children painted and couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait when the easter bunny finnaly comes. Once again, we visited an animal park in Poing. I think we will make this a tradition, because it&amp;rsquo;s really amazing to see all the baby animals there. Then we spent the holidays in the field (someone takes his kids to the football match, someone to the tractor).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olivia is 5 years old</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/03/10/olivia-is-five/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 14:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/03/10/olivia-is-five/</guid>
      <description>Olivia is 5 years old. She started celebrating with her grandparents in the morning and in the afternoon, she enjoyed the chocolate birthday cake with her friend. On the next day, she successfuly finished her swim course. I have already sewed a little sea horse on her swimsuit. On the last lesson, the children swam in their pyjamas to find out what it is like to swim in the clothes. Olivia did it perfectly well to my pleasure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olivia can swim</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/01/31/olivia-can-swim/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 14:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/01/31/olivia-can-swim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since October, Olivia goes swimming once a week. The goal is to get a see horse (that means, that she can swim 25 meters, she has the courage to jump into the water and she can dive and pull the ring out of the water). Last week, she managed to swim 25 metres. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dominik is two and half</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/01/14/dominik-is-two-and-half/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 14:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/01/14/dominik-is-two-and-half/</guid>
      <description>Dominik like singing. In the car, I always turn on a song he wishes and then he sings all the way home. Currently, he prefers to eat pasta in any form and corn. It&amp;rsquo;s similar to the time when he wanted to eat only bread or yogurt whole the week. Now he takes pasta from the fridge even for breakfast.
Unlike Olivia, he first does something and then he thinks about the consequences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full December</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/01/01/full-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 19:54:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/01/01/full-december/</guid>
      <description>In December, there was always a lot going on. I think that the first starting event was on Saint Martin&amp;rsquo;s day in November, when the gingerbread goats are used to be baked and the children are looking forward to lantern procession in the evening. Afterwards at home, we were still listening to the Saint Martin&amp;rsquo;s songs untill the new ones about Saint Nicholas came. In the meantime, the children began to open an Advent calendar and they also kept getting the small sweet surprises on all the courses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter for a few days</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/12/31/winter-for-a-few-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 23:21:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/12/31/winter-for-a-few-days/</guid>
      <description>This year, the winter has come only for a few days, but every moment we have made the most of it. Kids would love to shovel snow every morning and Dominik is excited about sledding (I think he does not remember it from the last year). And we built a lovely snowman.
            Your browser does not support the video tag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olivia takes pictures</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/12/30/olivia-takes-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 22:35:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/12/30/olivia-takes-pictures/</guid>
      <description>We gave Olivia a small camera in the summer so she could take photos during her holidays. Dominik was excited to take pictures as well. So far, the biggest problem is to be patient enough to take tack sharp images, but a few nice shots have been made.
             </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer memories</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/10/03/summer-memories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 16:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/10/03/summer-memories/</guid>
      <description>There was no time to write about summer holidays. But at least, I would like to post some photos now. Olivia wanted to mount a go kart with her grandpa and she drew a frame for it in the kindergarden. This year we managed to swim a couple of times in the swimming pool in the backyard, ride horses (I had to as well, because I was afraid that the horse was too big for Dominik) and we made a trip to Korlátko (about an hour of walking) and we walked through the Dolné diery in Vrátna valley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/08/15/summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 21:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/08/15/summer/</guid>
      <description>We asked Olivia what season we have right now and she as usual didn&amp;rsquo;t want to answer straight away, so we asked Dominik what he thought about it. He looked and said:&amp;ldquo;Summer&amp;rdquo;. Olivia was quite angry :) Olivia now enjoys when she can help me. She always says:&amp;ldquo;You know, I&amp;rsquo;ll help you Mom, so you have more time to play with us.&amp;rdquo; And she makes a breakfast or dinner table ready, she prepares all ingredients for cooking and she chops and mix them when needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dominik is two</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/07/02/dominik-is-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 20:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/07/02/dominik-is-two/</guid>
      <description>So Dominik is two years old. He still loves tractors, trains and excavators. He likes when he has time to do his own things and no one disturbs him but he also started to play with Olivia and he follows her in everything what she does. Dominik learned to jump into the swimming pool, he is talking more and more.
         </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two-week holiday</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/06/28/two-week-holiday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 20:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/06/28/two-week-holiday/</guid>
      <description>One week off in the kindergarden and then one more in the nursery and so we went for holidays to grandparents. The children played on all playgrounds, they ate peas, currants, cherries and strawberries all the time. Dominik used to &amp;ldquo;drive&amp;rdquo; the tractor in a barn every day. After two weeks, they asked when we would go home and when we were arriving to our home town, Dominik screamed in the car &amp;ldquo;hoooome&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last events</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/05/30/last-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 08:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/05/30/last-events/</guid>
      <description>Our Easter was one very enjoyable extended weekend full of trips. Only weather could have been warmer and less rainy. However, we visited the Wildpark in Poing and we palyed on the playgrounds. A week later, Olivia was still talking about Ivka and how she loves her and she asked when we would visit her again.
This year we joined a local tradition and were looking for Easter eggs. &amp;ldquo;Mami, the easter bunny was here&amp;rdquo; was the reaction when she found the cooked eggs in the flower pots and the garden hidden by the grandparents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In common and different</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/03/20/common-and-different/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 20:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/03/20/common-and-different/</guid>
      <description>They are really different, but one thing they have in common, each pursues their own interests and follows them. Olivia is like a manager and her assertiveness has no boundaries. When I want to pick her up from the kindergarten, she first goes to all teachers to say goodbye with a handshake (I do not know where does it come from). The best is when we are talking about how to do something, she listens to everything and then she says, &amp;ldquo;You know what we do it this way &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olivia is 4 years old</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/03/01/olivia-is-4-years-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 20:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/03/01/olivia-is-4-years-old/</guid>
      <description>Olivia talked about her birthday since summer. She couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait till she would put four candles on her birthday cake, light them and blow them out. We celebrated together, with her friends, with the grandparents and finally in the kindergarten with cakes. Luckily, everyone has birthday only once a year :). Olivia got Cubetto  (she calls him Kubo), a small robot to learn programming and improve spatial orientation in a funny way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When there is a lot of snow</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/02/01/when-there-is-alot-of-snow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 12:15:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/02/01/when-there-is-alot-of-snow/</guid>
      <description>We planned to go somewhere for the winter holidays, but it snowed so much that we changed our minds. We are every day in our garden playing with shovels or sledding on the nearby hill. And I started introducing Olivia to skiing. First, in the garden just to learn balance on her own and then on the nearby slopes, but they seemed to be too steep. Then my friend recommended me a small ski resort for children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gym</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/12/20/gym/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 20:32:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/12/20/gym/</guid>
      <description>I always try to take my children outside in any weather and every time I say we are going out they both rush to the door. But sometimes I just want to be at home, it&amp;rsquo;s raining, cold or dark early outside and then it is good to have a place where they can spend all their excess energy. So we made a gym in the basement. They can throw a ball there, slide, climb, boulder and chase each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birds and ladybugs</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/10/11/birds-and-ladybugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 20:32:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/10/11/birds-and-ladybugs/</guid>
      <description>A new school year started and Olivia finally became a kindergarten kid. Although she long longed for this moment, it took her a while to get used to a greater number of children and related noise, but now she is going to the kindergarten with enthusiasm, she brings home lots of drawings every day and she tells us what everything they did there. She also likes the music education they have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forest playground</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/09/05/forest-playground/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 09:42:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/09/05/forest-playground/</guid>
      <description>In a small town Pöring, near to us, there is a large playground on the edge of the forest. I like it very much because it&amp;rsquo;s all in a pleasant shade of trees and you can play there even when it&amp;rsquo;s hot outside or raining lightly. There is something for everyone and it&amp;rsquo;s a favorite place for birthday parties or just for a picnic. The best thing is that the children go home completely tired every time:)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dominik can walk</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/08/06/dominik-can-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2016 09:07:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/08/06/dominik-can-walk/</guid>
      <description>Dominik began to walk. He has already started doing the first steps about a month ago, but now he can walk longer, he tries it more often and he enjoys it more than crawling. Olivia likes to hold his hand and to walk with him and every time I pick him up, she reminds me that I can put him down because he is able to walk alone.
Beside walking, he likes climbing the stairs, sliding and he can ride his toddler balance bike and he has already learned to control it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blond</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/07/02/blond/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 14:59:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/07/02/blond/</guid>
      <description>Our small dark tan Dominik with blond hair and dark eyes is one year old. A week ago I would write that he is toothless, but now I discovered two teeth on the right side (not in the front as usual), and if another two same teeth grow on the other side, he will look like a vampire :). He likes walking and pushing a chair and he is able to push it even when Olivia sits on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In movement</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/05/21/in-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 22:06:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/05/21/in-movement/</guid>
      <description>Dominik is in that wonderful age when everything fascinates him and when he sees something new
(i.e. the cows in the stable) he is able to watch it intently with a wide-open mouth. He also points his finger at everything, he likes playing with a ball (he tries to throw it over himself stretching his arms out or he rolls it enthusiastically through a Lego tunnel), he spents a lot of time in Olivia&amp;rsquo;s kitchen and he is fascinated by everything that does something i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olivia rides a bike</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/04/21/olivia-rides-abike/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 20:02:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/04/21/olivia-rides-abike/</guid>
      <description>After 20 minutes &amp;hellip;
Your browser does not support the video tag.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily news</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/04/19/daily-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 20:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/04/19/daily-news/</guid>
      <description>Dominik stands wherever possible, he stands up even though there is nothing to hold.
And then he tries to get back down on the floor and he doesn&amp;rsquo;t like when he fells down. He likes playing in the sand and examining our garden and I&amp;rsquo;m very pleased that he doesn&amp;rsquo;t put everything he finds in his mouth anymore. On Olivia&amp;rsquo;s request, they sleep together in one room and it seems like they both enjoy it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 years old</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/03/16/3-years-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 21:10:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/03/16/3-years-old/</guid>
      <description>Olivia is already a big girl and she&amp;rsquo;s going to school. In the morning, she&amp;rsquo;ll play there and she&amp;rsquo;ll learn to write, because she can already read and in the afternoon mommy picks her up. She keeps saying everyone that she is three years old and she shows on her fingers how much it is. We celebrated twice; once privately with a creamy berry cake and an easel and once with Olivia&amp;rsquo;s four friends (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Different</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/02/24/different/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 12:24:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/02/24/different/</guid>
      <description>When she was as old as he she could already stand up, but she could wear the trousers he wears now when she was a little bit over a year. I find it generally interesting to watch them, how different they are.
     This year, Olivia actively helped to make her magical fairy costume for a carnival.
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Because because because what?</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/02/04/because-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 11:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/02/04/because-what/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;rsquo;s a question that I occasionally can&amp;rsquo;t answer or
I simply don&amp;rsquo;t know what Olivia tries to ask me. She asks everything; who said what, how the things work, where is what and she also invents her own theories and enjoys them. And when she talks to Dominik, he enthusiastically responds &amp;ldquo;ba ba ba&amp;rdquo; and then Olivia tells us what Dominik wants :) It&amp;rsquo;s been about a week since our over ten kilo Dominik has moved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/01/26/winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 20:22:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/01/26/winter/</guid>
      <description>This winter was somehow too short and now it looks again as in the springtime. We tried our best to make the most of it. Olivia tried to remember what the tobogganing is and Dominik trained it as well. Beside this, Olivia enjoyed the evenings of fairy tales, she began to &amp;ldquo;read&amp;rdquo; as others and she talks only about going to school.
                </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas craft</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/12/26/christmas-craft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 23:16:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/12/26/christmas-craft/</guid>
      <description>Last month we did some Christmas craft. Olivia paints enthusiastically, she likes making handprints (Dominik joined us as well and the brush tickled him so much :)), cutting the paper and gluing. So we did something creative every day and it looked somehow like this :)
                   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All purpose milk</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/10/27/all-purpose-milk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 21:58:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/10/27/all-purpose-milk/</guid>
      <description>It has fascinated me since Olivia was born, how the nature works. Small wounds, irritated skin, red patches when sweating, sore eyes or small rash … there is no need to have a wound cream or drops, just use your breast milk and everything disappears quickly. I also successfully solved Dominik&amp;rsquo;s running nose only with my breast milk. Not to mention how enthusiastically he drinks and when he is full enough he smiles at me and he gently bites me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two of them</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/10/09/two-of-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 11:58:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/10/09/two-of-them/</guid>
      <description>Time flies and you can&amp;rsquo;t do anything about it. Olivia has already learned it too. Only with Dominik, I feel like
it flies at least twice as fast. Our &amp;ldquo;little&amp;rdquo; one is 8.5 kilos and about 66 cm big and he looks like 6 months old children, he only doesn&amp;rsquo;t move so much. We started going to the gym with Olivia again. She enjoys a trampoline and climbing on a bench the most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/08/20/changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 11:49:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/08/20/changes/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what was a more significant change for Olivia, brother or moving to a new house, but in any case it slowly begins to influence her. She&amp;rsquo;s much more sensitive than before and we&amp;rsquo;re never sure how she responds. We haven&amp;rsquo;t had many opportunities to walk around the neighbourhood yet, but we tried at least a playground in the near forest and we met one wild boar. Olivia enjoys a ponies riding on a nearby farm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>He grows and grows</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/07/20/he-grows-and-grows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 18:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/07/20/he-grows-and-grows/</guid>
      <description>Domink grew by 3.5 cm in the first two weeks and he already weighs over four kilos. He begins to smile and watch what is around him. In the morning, we manage to prepare everything and go to the nursery with Olivia quite well. We still need to fine-tune the evening so that Dominik would sleep and I could undisturbed put Olivia into her bed.
         </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We run</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/06/25/we-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 10:58:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/06/25/we-run/</guid>
      <description>Lately, the best game is to run, no matter whether we are inside or outside. We take a break only while waiting for a traffic light. Besides running we play soccer or dance. Olivia likes to ride her balance bike everywhere. She is fast and lift her feet off the ground so I run and run after her. The best afterwards is to sit on the couch at home waiting for her to explain me what everything she cooks for me and let her bring it to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bed</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/05/08/bed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 09:22:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/05/08/bed/</guid>
      <description>Olivia likes the postman or better to say she realized that the cool stuff can be delivered per mail. First, she got a duvet with a pillow (I think I give them to her this weekend), then nice bedding sets with pictures of teddy bears and owls were delivered and finally, she was waiting the whole weekend for Monday, when the postman brought her a bed. Now when the door bell rings, she runs to the door and says mail is here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barbecue, painting and so on</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/05/06/barbecue-painting-and-so-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 20:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/05/06/barbecue-painting-and-so-on/</guid>
      <description>The grilling season began and this year we decided to actively participate in it. Olivia is excited about eating outside in the fresh air. She is also interested in everything our neighbours do. And when nothing interesting is happening, she draws with chalk on the balcony. She likes drawing in general and she can draw nicely a round face with eyes, mouth and nose and she is very enthusiastic about brush painting so we made a cardboard house together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/04/17/autonomous/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 12:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/04/17/autonomous/</guid>
      <description>This year, we survived the Easter holiday :) I was cold (I don&amp;rsquo;t remember when I was so sick last time) and for Olivia it was too muchgoing on with too many people and after a week she wanted to go home. But she often sings &amp;ldquo;hej hou hej hou&amp;rdquo; because that&amp;rsquo;s whather grandfather and grandma sing and after a couple of days spent with them she can go down a slide forwards by herself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter news</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/02/23/winter-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 09:52:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/02/23/winter-news/</guid>
      <description>The snow is slowly melting and we&amp;rsquo;re looking forward to the spring, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad that we had so much snow and that we could sleigh, trudge through deep snow and make shoe tracks in snow. We learned to make &amp;ldquo;whoopee&amp;rdquo; sound by tobogganing and we watched the skiers on the slope behind our town, so now Olivia knows at least what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about when we read about winter fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When it&#39;s cold outside</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/01/25/when-its-cold-outside/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 07:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/01/25/when-its-cold-outside/</guid>
      <description>After Christmas, Olivia is excited about her push bike, which we got from our colleague. First, her hands were shaking and we could see that she tries to mantain a balance with all her strength. At the beginning, we held her a little bit and helped her to master the curves. Now she can already get on the push bike herself, she rides faster and at the and of the hall she can ride backwards to the bathroom and then further on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Christmas holiday</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/01/10/the-christmas-holiday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2015 13:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/01/10/the-christmas-holiday/</guid>
      <description>Olivia started talking even more than before and we understand more and more. During the Christmas holiday, she was busy meeting loads of people, chasing cats in the yard and when there was snow we finally rode the wooden sled. The best of all was to shovel snow, then we couldn&amp;rsquo;t get her inside. And we tried to sleep and rest as much as possible.
             Your browser does not support the video tag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last two months</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/07/17/last-two-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2014 18:50:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/07/17/last-two-months/</guid>
      <description>We strengthen our immunity. I feel like one of us is always sick. Nevertheless, we enjoyed the hot summer days in the pool on the balcony, when it didn&amp;rsquo;t rain we were on the playground or otherwise we played at home. Olivia likes watering our plants on the balcony and she ate all our white currants (not to mention how much currants she ate at grandparents). Right now she is making another mental jump in her life and she learns to manage her emotions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There she grows again</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/05/17/there-she-grows-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2014 21:10:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/05/17/there-she-grows-again/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve already been working for two weeks and it&amp;rsquo;s quite a nice change. Time with my colleagues flies away so fast in the morning and in the afternoon I enjoy Olivia and I try to concentrate only on her. In the morning she runs to children in her class laughing. Currently, she takes great delight in building towers from Lego building blocks, she likes reading books and last time I found her with a TV control in her hand pretending to be on the phone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just some notes</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/04/12/just-some-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 21:34:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/04/12/just-some-notes/</guid>
      <description>This week we were at home just the two of us. Olivia is getting used to sleeping in the nursery and I have the whole morning just for myself after a long time. In the afternoon, we practically are still outside. We take a moment to shovel sand into the bucket and the remaining time we&amp;rsquo;re trying to climb on everything around. Olivia became a great helper at home. She likes to be involved in everything I do - washing the dishes, stirring while cooking, wiping her highchair after eating, hanging bib on a radiator, water the flowers, vacuuming, sweeping, unloading things from the dishwasher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nursery</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/03/20/nursery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 20:06:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/03/20/nursery/</guid>
      <description>I started going to the nursery with Olivia two weeks ago and I&amp;rsquo;m still excited about this place and the people working there. They follow Montessori principles, children are in the group regardless of age (so they are like siblings, the bigger ones have to be careful not to hurt the smaller ones who are watching them with an open mouth) and can move freely in the building visiting other children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s go</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/03/04/lets-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 20:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/03/04/lets-go/</guid>
      <description>Olivia decided to start walking. Although she already took her first steps some days ago, yesterday she stood up without our motivation and went. Today she went on practising and now she is able to walk longer distance. And in last weeks, she grew up so much that I had to sort through her clothes and she is now big enough for her little quad and so she rides it cheerfully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To read</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/02/28/to-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 14:47:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/02/28/to-read/</guid>
      <description>Last year was great, but it&amp;rsquo;s a pity that it has passed so quickly. Among other things, we attended two interesting courses with Olivia starting when she was about four months old.
One of them (here called PEKiP) was based on the idea of the Czech child psychologist Dr. Jaroslav Koch, who dealt with sensory and motor stimulation of children under one year. The main idea was that while we moms were talking about everything related to our babies watching them carefully, our children played naked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One year old</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/02/25/one-year-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 21:23:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/02/25/one-year-old/</guid>
      <description>One year ago our Olivia was born. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to believe that she was so small when I&amp;rsquo;m looking at her now. She already measures 75cm and weighs nearly 9.3kg. She always smiles and gives us hugs and kisses. Every morning, she gets up at six, we take her to our bed so I can breastfeed her, then she gives us a kiss, sits down, shows &amp;ldquo;done&amp;rdquo; with her hands and then points her finger at the door and says &amp;ldquo;ta&amp;rdquo; which means wake up, we&amp;rsquo;re going to play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parental leave</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/02/05/parental-leave/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 22:11:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/02/05/parental-leave/</guid>
      <description>Again, we enjoy a common month of parental leave. I must say that it&amp;rsquo;s great because we have just right amount of energy for our little rascal. Olivia climbed down the stairs for the first time. It took her quite a long time, but we duly praised her for that and she smiled like sunshine. She learned to slip the wooden rings on a stick and she likes to take toys out of the box and then again put them back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11 months</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/01/29/11-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 09:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/01/29/11-months/</guid>
      <description>Olivia has six teeth and she likes cleaning them whenever she sees her toothbrush. And apparently thanks to them she makes funny faces. She claps her hands when I say &amp;ldquo;clap clap&amp;rdquo; and she dances when she hears music (and she tries to dance even when standing alone). She likes throwing a ball and then catching it climbing over everything that comes in her way. She can say Mom and show Daddy whenever she hears him or is looking for him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toothy week</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/01/17/toothy-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 21:36:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/01/17/toothy-week/</guid>
      <description>Well, we really &amp;ldquo;enjoyed&amp;rdquo; last week. Olivia obviously found out that she needs other teeth after all and now it seems that they sprout out all at once. The top right one is already out. When I ask her to kiss me, she leans to me with an open mouth. She can put her hands behind her head and loves to play &amp;ldquo;baram baram buc&amp;rdquo;. When she finishes something or she doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to do it anymore she shows it&amp;rsquo;s done with her hands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sitting</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/01/04/sitting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 22:18:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/01/04/sitting/</guid>
      <description>Olivia finally sits while she is playing and it&amp;rsquo;s really nice to watch her. She can get angry when things go wrong and she turns her nose up at anything she doesn&amp;rsquo;t want. At her grandparents&amp;rsquo; house she learned to crawl up the stairs. She also went four steps down upside down and then back up snarling that it didn&amp;rsquo;t go quite well. At home she already tried it sideways, so I think it&amp;rsquo;s getting better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first Christmas</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/12/30/the-first-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 10:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/12/30/the-first-christmas/</guid>
      <description>I think Olivia doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand unwrapping Christmas gifts yet, but she likes their content very much. To my great joy she started to use sign language eg. the light is turned on, she finished eating and she is going to wash her hands, hand waving bye bye, how tall she will be and her grandma taught her to rotate her hand when she asked how she is. Successfully, she goes on a potty several times a day and enthusiastically watches flushing a toilet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Box</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/12/12/box/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 22:03:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/12/12/box/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m able to get our baby dressed only while she&amp;rsquo;s standing. I can force her to lie on her back only a very short time while I&amp;rsquo;m changing her nappy. Once she has a new one , she rolls over on her tummy, grabs the nearest toy and at the first opportunity she stands up. But she already gives us little hugs and kisses, so I cannot really blame her for anything :).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 months</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/11/25/9-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2013 12:05:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/11/25/9-months/</guid>
      <description>Olivia is fascinated by everything that causes some action i.e. switches, buttons causing the sound, she is very interested in the traffic lights and she looks curiously in the elevator. And when she is excited about something she squeals loudly (e.g. when she listens to her favorite music, when we go outside and then back home). Everything that moves is interesting as well like cars and bicycles. Recently, a painter was at our home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kids room</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/11/11/kids-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 20:50:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/11/11/kids-room/</guid>
      <description>I recently painted a tree on the wall in Olivia&amp;rsquo;s bedroom to make it cosier. I painted with watercolors so I could wash it in the worst case. But it turned out pretty well so I maybe paint there some animals later on. We already thought about moving Olivia to her own room when she stopped sleeping in the bedside crib, but there were two things that discouraged me to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 moths</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/10/26/8-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2013 18:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/10/26/8-months/</guid>
      <description>Among her friends, who she plays with, she is the only one who can stay, has a lot of hair and no teeth. She is going through another growth spurt and so it&amp;rsquo;s a little bit more difficult to put her in sleep. Most recently, we play hide and seek games and she laughs a lot and we all crawl throughout our home. Today, she was finally brave enough to crawl under the table and chair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/10/25/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2013 11:46:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/10/25/books/</guid>
      <description>In conversation, I found the most difficult to be able to look at the topic from the perspective of the other person, to learn to listen and see the other one positively. It&amp;rsquo;s called assertive communication and it has fascinated me for a long time. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to learn but I have to say that Olivia is the perfect trainer. She cannot speak, so in this sense I cannot misunderstand her or be offended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discoverer</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/10/20/discovever/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 14:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/10/20/discovever/</guid>
      <description>Olivia is not standing on her tiptoes anymore but the whole feet and she starts cruising. She just lacks some kind of a survival instinct, because sometimes while standing she stops holding the object with her hands and then she looks surprised when falling down onto her back. Once she stands up, she doesn&amp;rsquo;t really want to sit down. She only kneels or sits down when she is pretty tired and she cannot stand any longer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On her feet</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/10/13/on-her-feet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 12:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/10/13/on-her-feet/</guid>
      <description>Firstly, it seemed like she would be slithering on her belly. But it somehow didn&amp;rsquo;t impress her and she began to crawl. And after a week, when I thought she would crawl faster and I&amp;rsquo;d chase her around the house, she began to stand up (she is a bit in a hurry, isn&amp;rsquo;t she?). When she is very interested in something she can get to it very quickly, but she has more fun with searching for things that help her to stand up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 months</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/09/25/7-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 19:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/09/25/7-months/</guid>
      <description>Holidays finished and all our activities started again. Today we learned to jump/fall into the water and to swim with a swimming board. Olivia crawls nicely and moves quickly where she wants, especially when she is interested in something (like the laundry basket or slippers). We also started course for children. For the first hour, we took daddy with us to conclude his parental leave. In July, Olivia was one of the last ones, who began to rolled over and now she was the only one (except the one month older baby boy) on her knees and she crawled among the other children and put everything what she found into her mouth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some photos</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/09/18/some-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 21:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/09/18/some-photos/</guid>
      <description>Last two weeks, we were really active and we took advantage of the last summer days. Beside swimming and crawling in the grass on the hill behind our house, we went to see animals in the forest. Olivia looked at a family of a wild boar and deer and then she looked up and watched trees.       And then we traveled toward grandparents. Olivia gained allattention and she started eating incredibly lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Half a year old</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/09/04/half-a-year-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 09:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/09/04/half-a-year-old/</guid>
      <description>Olivia managed another growth spurt (together with us). From what I read, we bore this quite well. She didn&amp;rsquo;t lose her appetite, quite the opposite. She didn&amp;rsquo;t cry too much, just started to realise the distances and occasionally gurgled, when she saw me going away from the room. But she slept less. In the evening, she always woke up after one hour of sleeping full of energy and ready to play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/08/10/active/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 13:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/08/10/active/</guid>
      <description>Our little baby already weights 7kg. She smiles a lot and watches all carefully. When she hears me but doesn&amp;rsquo;t see me, she raises her head high and looks at where I am. Then when I suddenly peek out from behind the door she smiles from ear to ear. We taught her to blow, so now we can hear ppfff and fffuuu from the crib and when I look at her she is smiling at me with a questioning look in her eyes and four fingers in the mouth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baptism</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/07/28/baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2013 14:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/07/28/baptism/</guid>
      <description>Last week, we travelled with Olivia abroad for the first time. She was doing very well. She slept, played a bit, we had a little break on a blanket under the trees as well, just at the end she had enough, but so did all of us. We all dreamed about a cold shower. I was only worried whether this trip does not disturb her sleeping, but she slept even better than at home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rolling</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/07/15/rolling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 10:53:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/07/15/rolling/</guid>
      <description>Olivia began to roll on her belly a week ago. After an intensive weekend training with her grandfather and grandmother, she didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything else just tried to roll over and she was angry when it didn&amp;rsquo;t work. The next day she was rolling over and over on both sides. Rolling back to her back is more difficult, we train it but she rather falls than consciously rolls back. Basically it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter, Olivia likes to be on her belly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Name day</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/06/27/name-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 11:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/06/27/name-day/</guid>
      <description>We celebrated the Olivia&amp;rsquo;s firstname day. On her behalf, thank you for all the congratulations. She spent the morning playing with her peers (they talked with their own language, they pulled and sucked together one long chain and some of them already were able to roll and the other watched them with interest :)) In the afternoon, she played at home. Andrej brought her wooden baby gym and she was really happy about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twice as big</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/06/19/twice-as-big/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 19:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/06/19/twice-as-big/</guid>
      <description>Our little one already weights 6110 grams and so she more than doubled her weight, which she had at birth. She began to play with her feet and clap them. Previously, she already managed to turn on her side, but that was more or less by accident. Now, she is trying it consciously and when she fails, she is angry with herself. The result of her effort is that she rotates around her own head in a circle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warm</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/06/08/warm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 21:49:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/06/08/warm/</guid>
      <description>We complained that it&amp;rsquo;s raining and cold and so on Wednesday it was suddenly about 15 degrees warmer and the sun is burning and we can only go out in the evening. But the great is that we don&amp;rsquo;t have to dress Olivia so much, she just needs to get used to the higher temperature. So far she only drinks a lot and is tired of it. Since Monday, she has been having fun lying on her belly again and so we encourage her to rotate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 months</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/05/26/3-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 18:32:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/05/26/3-months/</guid>
      <description>She grows really fast. Sometimes I look at her in the morning and I feel like she grew overnight at least few inches up. And when cutting nails, I feel that while I&amp;rsquo;m cutting them on the other hand, they grow long on the first one again. She weighs just over 5.6kg and she recently puts her both hands in front of her together putting them all into her mouth. She started to drool pretty much, so I wonder, when she begins to lick everything around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/05/16/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 20:57:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/05/16/news/</guid>
      <description>Olivia has over 5kg and my back is looking forward to doing excercises starting next week. She enjoys bathing and she recentlystarted screaming when we&amp;rsquo;re taking her out from the bathwater. Now I&amp;rsquo;m only waiting for that she holds her head properly and we go to the pool. I&amp;rsquo;m very happy that she has a relationship with Andrej equivalent to me (probably up to that hungry expression on her face) and whenever she sees him she smiles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 months</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/04/23/2-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 21:29:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/04/23/2-months/</guid>
      <description>Our little Olivia is two months old. Actually, she is not very small anymore, she grew about ten centimeters up and weighs about 4.8kg. She smiles a lot, but she can curle her mouth as well when she doesn&amp;rsquo;t like something and she generally makes targeted grimaces trying to imitate us. She likes looking into the mirror and the windows, I think it&amp;rsquo;s because of the light. She got used to regular walks in a stroller and when the sunlight is disturbing her by sleeping she is able to stretch her cap under her nose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweater</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/04/21/sweater/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 11:15:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/04/21/sweater/</guid>
      <description>Well, beside the all my current activities I managed to knit againand Olivia got a new sweater with a hat. For such a small person it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take long to finish it and the outcome pleases meevery time(especially when other moms like Olivia and I can change ideas and patterns for new things with them :) ).
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Month</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/31/month/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 18:02:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/31/month/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been over a month since Olivia lives with us. I must say that she changes herself in front of our eyes daily and she grows quickly. Some of her clothes are already small and we started using a new size of diapers as well. She learned to cry and express dissatisfaction and has an incredible appetite. She smiles often looking at us with her big eyes, she makes a variety of sounds with opened mouth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pregnancy</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/18/pregnancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 20:05:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/18/pregnancy/</guid>
      <description>A little retrospective writing, but I felt I need to write about it. I thought that pregnancy and stress are mutually exclusive, but I think they attract each other. Fear is different, it seems natural to me. Whenever I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel well, the first thing that occured to me was whether the little baby in my tummy is well. But by stress I rather mean the feeling that I always had when I had to decide for something or to solve something from medical point of view and there were many of those moments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bathing</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/14/bathing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 10:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/14/bathing/</guid>
      <description>So we bathed our little baby for the first time. After a week, her umbilical cord fell away and we took her to the first walk in a stroller. We also somehow managed changing her diapers (an electric heater above the changing table is absolutely fantastic thing) and we only had to handle bathing in water. I expected many reactions, but not that she will be so satisfied. Our midwife came to help us and teach us once again some of those useful tricks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cradle</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/12/cradle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 17:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/12/cradle/</guid>
      <description>We had our first visit since there have been three of us and we got a wooden cradle. It found its place in the living room next to our couch. Our midwife was fascinated with it too when she saw it. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how long it will serve us (when our dear child beggins to jump out from it), but now it&amp;rsquo;s great for napping throughout the day. Grandparents visited us for really very short time, but Olivia looked happy in the grandma&amp;rsquo;s hands and we felt very comfortable that we didn&amp;rsquo;t have to think about how is Olivia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belly</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/05/belly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 17:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/05/belly/</guid>
      <description>I wrote the below article last week, thinking that I have enough time to do some more photos of my growing belly. But somehow I didn&amp;rsquo;t manage it and our little princess is already in the world :)
Well, we grow slowly. According to recent estimates, our baby has around 2.8 to 3 kg and falls well within the average size range, which makes me extremely happy. It&amp;rsquo;s only a shame that she doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to turn as other average children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olivia</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/02/olivia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 14:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/02/olivia/</guid>
      <description>A little bit earlier but healthy and satisfied :) I would like to introduce you our sweet little daughter Olivia.
    Birthday: 25.2.2013 18:15
Weight: 3020 g
Length: 47 cm
       </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forester&#39;s house St. Hubertus</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/12/31/foresters-house-st-hubertus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 17:19:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/12/31/foresters-house-st-hubertus/</guid>
      <description>In the summer, enjoyable place for some beer and Bavarian food, in the winter a romantic place for Advent markets and walking through the snowy forest. First time, we were here cycling in the summer (the house is in the near forest about 2km from its edge) and we met there whole families on their trips relishing forest shade and the local atmosphere.
Well, last time I accidentally found the program leaflet for the Advent time, so we parked nearby and we walked on the snowy road towards the stands with Christmas decorations and refreshments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November Wallberg</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/11/17/november-wallberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2012 07:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/11/17/november-wallberg/</guid>
      <description>There are already many articles about this hill on our web page and I need to say that it&amp;rsquo;s one of our favourite hill. But two weeks ago, we had such a nice visit, to my great pleasure longing for trips led by a almost three years old young tourist. And so we went on trips to many places and one of them was Wallberg. It&amp;rsquo;s clear to me that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to convince Andrej to go there otherwise (certainly not in November and not at all in that snow except the sledding).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New tenant</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/11/10/new-tenant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2012 18:22:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/11/10/new-tenant/</guid>
      <description>I already hadfelt like we travelled not alone on the plane to Mallorca, but it was just a feeling and I convinced myself that it&amp;rsquo;s rather unlikely to be truth. After our vacation, I was full of energy only about two days and then it went down rapidly. I slept everyday 12 hours, during the weekend even more but nevertheless I felt like a ghost. Every day in the morning, I got up terribly tired and at the work, I always received a nice careful compliment that I look horrible and I should do something about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October snow</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/10/28/october-snow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 10:48:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/10/28/october-snow/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, it started snowing. The temperature dropped to zero and we were quite pleased that we changed from summer to the winter car tires last week. Children here are having autumn holiday next week, but they can already start writing about winter fun. Well, it is said it should become a bit warmer and I hope so. It would be nice to see snow again, but first in December.
     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sudelfeld</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/03/11/sudelfeld/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2012 16:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/03/11/sudelfeld/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, we went skiing again. This time we chose Sudelfeld ski resort. Our colleague told us that it is a little bit small and local, but less people know about it and therefore it usually is not so crowded on Saturday. The weather was absolutely fantastic, there were really not so many people and we were quite surprised when we found that it is not as small as we heard. In addition, it is a great place for skiing with children with lots of children&amp;rsquo;s short and mild slopes and help with all lifts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What the last year brought</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/01/17/what-the-last-year-brought/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 22:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/01/17/what-the-last-year-brought/</guid>
      <description>It started with skiing and two good feelings. One of them was the prospect of a new year that we could finally live together (this wish came true) and the second one because I submit my PhD thesis and even defended it. Although, it took me a while till I really got rid of it, that feeling was priceless. We started going on trips to the mountains, which I missed incredibly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sledding</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/12/29/tehotenstvo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 00:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/12/29/tehotenstvo/</guid>
      <description>We went sledding during our Christmas holiday to relax and spend our time wisely :) Here are some pictures from the last year. This time, we set off earlier and so we basically had the whole track for ourselves. I tried to make some videos during the sledding ( on steeper sections it&amp;rsquo;s a bit shaky because I had to brake too). The experience was again absolutely terrific. In between, we refreshed ourselves in the panorama restaurant on the hill, warmed up on the sun and I took a panorama from that beautiful view around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autumn</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/11/21/autumn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 21:59:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/11/21/autumn/</guid>
      <description>This season is actually already at the end, but it occurred to me that I still have some photos I didn&amp;rsquo;t show you. We walked again to the local tower and on its top, because it seemed to me that an autumn view might be worth it and I was right. ( You can seethe summer view here.) Everything was so beautifully coloured. We just need to set off earlier because it becomes dark very quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/11/08/walking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 21:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/11/08/walking/</guid>
      <description>I love autumn from several reasons. It&amp;rsquo;s not so cold yet, but also not so hot anymore and so you can wrap yourself in a warm blanket and relish a cup of tea. The weather outside is just amazing and stable and the sky can be unbelievably blue. And those colours &amp;hellip; as we moved we travel about ten minutesto work through a forest and that is so wonderful look that fits well immediately after waking, but also to relax after work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind the house</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/11/03/behind-the-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 21:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/11/03/behind-the-house/</guid>
      <description>Behind the neighbour house is a narrow path that leads up to the hill. It takes around three minutes to get on the top where beautiful four huge trees grow. It&amp;rsquo;s charming view from here and with good visibility the Alps can be seen. It&amp;rsquo;s a great place where to go when you want so see a piece of nature and you&amp;rsquo;re to tired or just lazy to go anywhere further.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wiesn</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/10/26/wiesn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 18:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/10/26/wiesn/</guid>
      <description>Another Oktoberfest (or Wiesn as local people would say) behind us, and this year we didn&amp;rsquo;t miss it. Well, we didn&amp;rsquo;t join the official event in traditional clothes inside one of the huge tents, but we dived in the great atmosphere and we drank one litter of beer. We didn&amp;rsquo;t see the initial ceremony this year, because we weren&amp;rsquo;t in the mood to go to the town in a rainy weather, but we did spent some hours together with our colleagues drinking beer at Oktoberfest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ebersberg</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/08/31/ebersberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 07:19:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/08/31/ebersberg/</guid>
      <description>Recently, we spent some time searching for a new apartment and beside this activity we discovered various places where we haven&amp;rsquo;t previously been. We were fascinated by one such a district town at very first visit and so we went there during one weekend again to get to know it a little bit more. We already get used to the plane everywhere in Munich (I don&amp;rsquo;t count those few artificial hills there) and we were very pleasantly surprised by the hilly terrain of the town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Officially Doctor</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/07/28/officialy-doctor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 15:31:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/07/28/officialy-doctor/</guid>
      <description>Two years agoI would havethoughtofgraduationas somevery nicebutunrealisticdreamand a week ago I was sittingin a large hall, wearing a gown and waiting for my diploma.But let&amp;rsquo;s start from the beginning. We wentto the university in the morning. I couldpick up thegown after eight o&amp;rsquo;clock,then we scheduledbreakfastora short walk, and about ten, we wanted togointo the hall,so we would settle half an hourbefore a graduation. But we found out that there were about 400 studentsgraduating at once andtwice as many relativeseagerlywaiting for opening the door in to the hall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azalea</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/14/azalea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 11:13:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/14/azalea/</guid>
      <description>With our last visitors, a new resident of our living room arrived. It&amp;rsquo;s a small tree or rather a bush called Azalea. I read that it&amp;rsquo;s the popular plant in gardens because it likes shady places, it&amp;rsquo;s able to survive down to -29 degrees and above all it makes all the dark corners beautiful. And when it blossomed, we understood. This plant is really charming.
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nature trip</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/10/nature-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 22:19:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/10/nature-trip/</guid>
      <description>Since urban tourism is quite difficult, and as we don&amp;rsquo;t want to destroy our visitors (we would like them to come again), we have always at hand some trip to nature. Neither last Saturday it was different and we went to our quite favourite place, on the hill Wallberg. Up and down we drove a cable-car, but then we hiked to the top of the peak (about half an hour). The chapel, which was reconstructed is already nice and finished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olympiaberg</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/10/olympiaberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 13:11:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/10/olympiaberg/</guid>
      <description>We were already several times in the Olympia park, but we somehow never got to the highest hill there. To walk on its top is not really difficult, but either the weather didn&amp;rsquo;t work out for us, or we were already tired from walking through the town so we ended up just resting near the lake below. There is a nice paved walkway leading up to the top of the hill that is great view point as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the city centre</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/09/in-the-city-centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 13:57:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/09/in-the-city-centre/</guid>
      <description>Once again, we went to the town centre to show our weekend visitors (Andrej&amp;rsquo;s parents) how it looks like here and where we actually live. We travelled by all sorts of trains (S-Bahn and U-Bahn and tram), we walked through the shopping street and stores and we looked at the ringing tower of the new town hall at eleven. We overcame the altitude difference from a minus fourth floor of the underground to around 290m high tower in Olympia Park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/02/congratulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 11:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/02/congratulations/</guid>
      <description>So we became the proud aunt and uncle not only of our beautiful niece Kika but also our newbornnephew Kubko.We would like to wish all the best to the happy parents. May all your days be happy and joyful. In this occasion I drew a little picture just for you.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relax on the balcony</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/04/30/relax-on-the-bacony/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 16:24:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/04/30/relax-on-the-bacony/</guid>
      <description>We were talking about buying something on the balcony last summer, especially when I moved a chair from a living room to the balcony and back several times. Something that would be used for sitting there in the morning to enjoy breakfast in the air and in the evening to drink wine in the shade. But we somehow had to address to many things and no time left to develop this idea further.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defence</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/03/01/defence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 19:12:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/03/01/defence/</guid>
      <description>Finally, I have an explanation, why I and my dear Andrej had disappeared from Skype since Friday. I flew to England and Andrej was offline, so he didn&amp;rsquo;t have to explain where I was. On Monday I had my final oral examination for my PhD and so I spent a long weekend before it by consulting everything with my supervisors, preparing a presentation and reading again and again my work and related papers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A dumpling</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/17/a-dumpling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 11:08:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/17/a-dumpling/</guid>
      <description>Generally, a man, who has lived abroad for longer time, usually finds out that he lacks some food or ingredient, which he would otherwise get on every corner in his native country, but in a foreign country there is no rumour or even hearing about it. In England, I somehow got used to the fact that poppy seeds are considered as dangerous drugs, the proper bread could be found in a Polish shop, cheese selection was a little bit limited and the overall problem was to find anything not low fat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/30/christams/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2010 19:23:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/30/christams/</guid>
      <description>This year we decorated our first common Christmas tree. We bought lights, decorations and gifts together and we had an ideal Christmas atmosphere. We even found out that it is possible to buy a fresh carp here. Although we celebrated Christmas in Slovakia, we left two wrapped gifts under our tree at home, so we could unpack them afterwards. I was expecting anything but a sewing machine. I haven&amp;rsquo;t even dreamed about it (well, maybe I thought about it sometimes that it would be useful).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sledding</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/20/sledding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2010 15:11:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/20/sledding/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend, we took advantage of a good weather after a long week of snowing and went sledding. We&amp;rsquo;ve already been on the Wallberg hill for hiking before. This time we used the cable-car on the way up and we sledded down the hill.
We borrowed sleds each separately, but later we agreed that next time we&amp;rsquo;ll sled together as it requires an appropriate weight. Andrej was faster and he didn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;fly&amp;rdquo; after each bump on the road.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saint Nicholas</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/10/saint-nicholas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2010 10:31:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/10/saint-nicholas/</guid>
      <description>This year&amp;rsquo;s St. Nicholas evening we played an interesting game called A white elephant gift exchange with another about 40 people. There was St. Nicholas personally near the Christmas tree too obey the rules. :) Shortly, the point of the game is to bring some inexpensive (can be humorous) present nicely wraped. The bigger amount of people play the game is funnier. Everyone obtains one number that determines his present choice order and the same number are inserted into some bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking in the park</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/07/walking-in-the-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 13:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/07/walking-in-the-park/</guid>
      <description>Walking in the park in winter, especially when there is snow everywhere, is absolutely fantastic. Although only until the sunset, because then it starts freezing properly and it is better to hide even in the subway. As I haven&amp;rsquo;t been in Englischer Garten at the time of snow, we went there during the last weekend. Originally, we wanted to go sledging on the nearby hill, but the season was just opened and so we concluded that there would be too many people anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas markets</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/07/christmas-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 12:20:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/07/christmas-markets/</guid>
      <description>During the weekend, we went to the Christmas markets. There are quite a lot of them in Munich. Basically, each Munich neighborhood has its own market. We went directly to the Marienplatz in the centre. There were many stands decorated with green boughs and colorful lights. They offered many things, among others, wooden ornaments and toys, candles and Christmas hats. I was really impressed by one stand that offered all sorts of wooden things ( cutting boards, spatula, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/01/advent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 13:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/01/advent/</guid>
      <description>After three years, this year&amp;rsquo;s advent is special for us. Finally, we don&amp;rsquo;t plan Christmas as a common holiday after long months, when we haven&amp;rsquo;t seen each other. We actually live together, enjoy snow and we&amp;rsquo;re not stressed whether I&amp;rsquo;ll be stuck somewhere at the airport due to bad weather.
  Finally, I got rid of the school and writing of my thesis (although I&amp;rsquo;ll certainly begin to think about my defense in the next year) and I started to enjoy winter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mushrooms</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/10/12/mushrooms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 11:09:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/10/12/mushrooms/</guid>
      <description>Finally, we managed to go to gather mushrooms, what we dreamed about all the summer. We dressed properly, put hats on our heads, equipped ourselves with baskets and knives and set off into the forest. Besides youthful mushrooms peeping out of the ground we found also lots of old, mouldy or dried mushrooms and we obviously came at the end of the mushroom season, but we still managed to gather a nice amount of healthy ones and when I consider three-hour walk through the forest, we were very satisfied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Once again in Slovakia</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/10/12/once-again-in-slovakia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 09:01:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/10/12/once-again-in-slovakia/</guid>
      <description>Once again, we travelled to Slovakia to see our friends and family, to gather some mushrooms and to enjoy a feast in Cerova, but especially to go to the Andrej&amp;rsquo;s brother wedding. The wedding took place in Castel Pension in Mierovo. Although I don&amp;rsquo;t know how the old manor house looked like before, I think its reconstruction was really successful. I was especially enchanted by a garden, which despite its relatively small dimension looked very spacious and thanks to various nooks with a touch of autumn very cozy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oktoberfest</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/10/06/oktoberfest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 14:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/10/06/oktoberfest/</guid>
      <description>anniversary of the Oktoberfest is over and people in traditional costumes are slowly but surely disappearing from the streets and the subway, so people like us dressed only in jeans and T-shirt don&amp;rsquo;t look like tourists anymore.  Although we haven&amp;rsquo;t been in the beer tent on the Theresienwiese, we didn&amp;rsquo;t miss parade at the launch of this year&amp;rsquo;s festivities. There were horse drawn carts with barrels of beer and venison, but also agricultural machinery and many brass bands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aphids</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/20/aphids/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2010 12:34:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/20/aphids/</guid>
      <description>I know that these little critters are also part of nature, but when someone starts eating plants grown with love by you, it sucks. I recently wrote that we bought a few plants in our appartment. There was also basil among them, my very favorite ingredient in cooking. It was absolutely great, until aphids appeared on the leaves. Theoretically, I could simply spray it with some plant spray against them, but we bought it as an organic plant, so it came to me as a very strange idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potatoes and other</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/06/potatoes-and-other/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 16:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/06/potatoes-and-other/</guid>
      <description>Since we have lived in Munich, we eat more meat, wholemeal bread, vegetables and fruit. On Sunday, everything except a bakery and Biergarten is closed and so on the way from the church we always enjoy the fresh bread rolls and when the weather is nice we spend the afternoon somewhere out in the park. Given the prevalence of organic and bio products in the supermarkets, it happens quite often that these kinds of fruits or vegetables or eggs from free range hens wander to our basket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the way to Slovakia and back</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/06/on-the-way-to-slovakia-and-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 13:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/06/on-the-way-to-slovakia-and-back/</guid>
      <description>As a part of running in our new car we went to Slovakia. All the traffic jams somehow managed to escape or be removed, until we got to them. And given the rainy weather, we had no taste to stop anywhere making a break, so after six hours we arrived to our destination. Lights were turned on automatically, wipers as well as appropriate, Andrej pretty much just pressed buttons of cruise control until Bratislava and in the meanwhile I studied controlling of theair-conditioning andsurroundingbuttons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Megi</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/07/25/megi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2010 15:51:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/07/25/megi/</guid>
      <description>nullSo finally, we have a new car, our Megi (renault Megane Grandtour). Currently happily relaxing in the garage, but we&amp;rsquo;ve already managed to drive a little bit pressing at least half of the buttons inside trying to figure out what they are good for :). Now, we only hope that it will serve us well and we will experience many safety kilometres.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake in the Olympia park</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/07/05/lake-in-the-olympia-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2010 19:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/07/05/lake-in-the-olympia-park/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve already written about the Olympia park, but that was in November last year and at that time there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any lake but the muddy place and some people who cleaned it. Fortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s the great place for visitors due to the high tower in the centre so we had a great opportunity to go there with our friends and see the actual lake :) There were many people running around or cycling, lot of stands with ice-cream or some sweet cakes and of course many people sitting in the bier garden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bavaria</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/07/05/bavaria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2010 13:17:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/07/05/bavaria/</guid>
      <description>This was one of my less fortunate trip ideas, but on the other hand I don&amp;rsquo;t regret at all that I was there. The question Where? is now on the right place &amp;hellip; in the statue called Bavaria. Recently, we had a second visit here and after a day spent walking in the center and parks, we were thinking, where to go next. I read that there is a statue that was created and built as a symbol of Bavaria, it is 18 m high and it is possible to go in, upstairs and look around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry field</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/07/05/strawberry-field/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2010 12:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/07/05/strawberry-field/</guid>
      <description>We somehow found out that we have a strawberry field near our house. Just cross the street with a basket in your hand, pick all the big juicy sweet strawberries, pay to the lady in the booth and look forward to the strawberry cake :) That was our plan last saturday morning and it was successful.
      We had about five kilos of strawberries, but we managed to eat all of them and make a dream strawberry cake as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surfers</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/04/29/surfers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 08:04:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/04/29/surfers/</guid>
      <description>We had our first visitors here last weekend. Our friends came to see us and of course all the beauties of Munich. On Sunday we went for walk to Englischer Garten. The weather was excellent, sunny and very warm. We choose a different path as the first time to better know the park for future visitors and we came to the stream Eisbach (ice stream). Well, we&amp;rsquo;ve read about one place in the park, where people use to surf, but we&amp;rsquo;ve never seen this place before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green friends</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/04/18/green-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2010 13:03:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/04/18/green-friends/</guid>
      <description>It was warm and sunshine weather yeasterday, so we went for a walk and finally finished in a huge greenhouse. We spent there a couple of hours and bought some green friends, which joined us in our home :)
    All of them should have (according to scientists) some sort of super power to absorb ill substances from the air in the room and make it better. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how we could compare it with the previous air in our apartment, but our living room looks definitely better now :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PS Portugal</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/04/18/ps-portugal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2010 11:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/04/18/ps-portugal/</guid>
      <description>There is something I forgot to write about Portugal. I brought two presents for my dear husband from this country. A little good luck rooster and a white Port wine. Well, the rooster should be black originally, but nowadays it is painted in many different colours. It is symbol of luck and justice when you fight for it and there is an interesting legend connected to one innocent Portuguese man who was released from hanging for crime thanks to a one rooster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laval Virtual</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/04/12/laval-virtual/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 20:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/04/12/laval-virtual/</guid>
      <description>The reason why I came to Laval wasinternational conference about virtual and augmented reality with about 200 people. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why this event was held in this town, somewhere in the centre of France in very countryside. It was something to think about even for French visitors, at least for those few who spoke to me in english. On the other hand, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t probably have other reason to go there, so I suggest it was kind of propagation of this locality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent videos</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/03/04/recent-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2010 20:25:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/03/04/recent-videos/</guid>
      <description>Here are some new videos I made from my application. Enjoy the baby feeding :)
[youtube]http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=579DGUiK0I4[/youtube]
Your browser does not support the video tag.  Your browser does not support the video tag.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How we went to Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/16/how-we-went-to-switzerland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 17:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/16/how-we-went-to-switzerland/</guid>
      <description>Our friends &amp;ldquo;chrobaci&amp;rdquo; invited us to visit them and we simply couldn&amp;rsquo;t say no :)After a long working week, Andrej took two days off, we rent a car, checked on a google map how to get there, packed some things and set off a journey. We turned on a navigation and as it showed approximately good amount of kilometers and time of arriving, we relied on it.We came to Bodensee lake (which is really huge) and when we suddenly left the highway and stayed on the right side of the lake in Germany, we started thinking if the navigating is right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Only 1:15h per person!</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/09/only-115h-per-person/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 13:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/09/only-115h-per-person/</guid>
      <description>Do you also know that great type of advertisements, which always offer something with words &amp;ldquo;from &amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo; ? Than you think about it more or you read that small letters at the bottom of the flyer and find out the conditions under which you will belong to the group of happy ones with that great price only &amp;ldquo;from&amp;rdquo; :)And so it occurred to me to write something similar. Would you like to relax, get out from your very well known place and spend i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Before and after</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/08/before-and-after/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2010 15:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/08/before-and-after/</guid>
      <description>Well, I think we settled down. We still miss some furniture like a sofa, but otherwise we can say that our home is finally livable :). The christmas time was wonderful, we met our friends and family again and eventually we spent some time with our little cute niece. But beside relaxing, we also thought a lot about decorating of our new apartment. When we finally came home, we spent a week by tidying, mounting the furniture and unpacking all the things we had.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calendar</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/04/calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 13:02:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/04/calendar/</guid>
      <description>Well, creating of this calendar is a long story and I really mean long. The main problem was I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any way how to link all the pages together, so it would look like a proper calendar. Finally I found the way how, but that is another story and a lesson for the future. If you think about companies, which offer a creating of the calendar and your only task is to send them pictures, forget about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5th of November</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/03/5th-of-november/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2010 20:58:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/03/5th-of-november/</guid>
      <description>Well, I know that this date was quite long time ago and you probably don&amp;rsquo;t even remember it, but British people used to say &amp;ldquo;remember, remember fifth of November&amp;rdquo;. And there is a special reason why, which I found funny, when I first heard about it. A long time ago, in seventeenth century, several catholic conspirators including Guy Fawks (the main &amp;ldquo;hero&amp;rdquo;) wanted to destroy the House of Parliament in England.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/12/12/winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2009 20:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/12/12/winter/</guid>
      <description>My lovely husband sent me again several pictures from our flat surrounding and honestly, I was a little bit jealous. I wish I were there and could build a snowman :)That narrow path is going toward S-Bahn.
           </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/12/06/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2009 17:20:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/12/06/home/</guid>
      <description>Well, home is a special word. This word should denotes the place where you feel comfortable, where you have all your belongings and possibly you live there with your loved ones. It is that nice place where you go after work, where you return from the vacation or visit. After more than two years of living in England and travelling I have things everywhere, my family, husband and friends are on different places and mostly not very close to one another and I am not sure where I felt the most comfortable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where to go with visitors</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/25/where-to-go-with-visitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 15:42:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/25/where-to-go-with-visitors/</guid>
      <description>We were thinking about where to go in Munich. We had a nice weather and 3-days ticket for travelling, so I took the map and was looking for some interesting places in the wider centre of the Munich. Since I wanted to take some impresive pictures, we went to the Nymphenburg castle.
Well the castle is really impresive, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure about the pictures. As it is the beginning of the winter, all the statues were covered by the wooden boxes, fountains were not working and in general it was obviously a good time to repair everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Munich</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/24/munich/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 21:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/24/munich/</guid>
      <description>I have never been to Munich before and I feel those few days I spent there weren&amp;rsquo;t enough. I love the historical flair of this city. There are no high modern glass buildings preventing the sun shine to the street, but low stylish buildings with sloping red roofs. There are loads of bakery and little kiosks with pretzels everywhere. Since I love to ramble marketplace, what I have probably inherited from my daddy, I was unbelievable happy to see one directly in the city centre called Viktualienmarkt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pub quiz</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/02/pub-quiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 18:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/02/pub-quiz/</guid>
      <description>Well, I don&amp;rsquo;t celebrate Halloween, because firstly it&amp;rsquo;s an American feast and secondly I think that All saints day is about something else and we have much better tradition of thinking about our relatives. As every year, I honestly completely forgot about it, when someone knocked on our house door. When it was repeated second time by another little cute child dressed as a little pumpkin, my house-mate went to shop and bought a bowl full of sweets and candy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IKEA lighting seminar</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/10/25/ikea-lighting-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2009 15:50:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/10/25/ikea-lighting-seminar/</guid>
      <description>I attended another IKEA seminar. This time, it was about furnishing with light, from needs to task solutions.
   First, I though I would miss the beginning of the seminar because my train was delayed as usual, but I finally managed to be on time and I relished nice English breakfast at the top floor of IKEA. We had very nice presentation about the role of light, different light sources and examples how to use light in different rooms for various purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembrance</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/10/23/remembrance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2009 13:37:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/10/23/remembrance/</guid>
      <description>I was looking for some photos in my huge database of pictures :)and i found several interesting pictures, which have probably not been seen by anyone except me and Andrej and which remain me a lot of nice things. They are all somehow related to our wedding. As I came home just one week before our wedding, I could only listen who send a new wedding card with best wishes. Therefore, when I was in Slovakia I put all of them together so I could also see them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Autumn</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/10/22/the-autumn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 20:11:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/10/22/the-autumn/</guid>
      <description>To say &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s autumn&amp;rdquo; is not really up to date information, especially when at some places in Slovakia is already snowing. But I think this part of year is the most beautiful in England with the most stable weather as well and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help myself taking some lovely pictures.
     Above the fourth tree from right side in the second row of windows is approximately the place where I work :).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D illusion</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/07/08/3d-illusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2009 08:55:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/07/08/3d-illusion/</guid>
      <description>I had a lot of time to think about new features in the virtual baby project during the London expo. There were many people who tried the application and gave me a nice feedback. Well, I got some ideas how to improve whole thing. One of the biggest problem in the environment was that the user miss the depth, so it&amp;rsquo;s sometimes difficult to say where the spoon is in the space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London expo</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/06/21/london-expo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 10:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/06/21/london-expo/</guid>
      <description>I went for three days business trip to London. It was really nice, sunny and quite warm weather, but I relished that only during the evenings because I spent whole days inside talking on exhibition. I have never gone by London underground before, so I was little bit curious about it. I started at Euston with the aim to go to the Excel exhibition centre, thus I spent under ground almost one hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I talked to prince</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/05/08/i-talked-to-prince/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2009 18:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/05/08/i-talked-to-prince/</guid>
      <description>Well, it sounds like from fairytale, but I talked to real prince :)Prince Andrew, the Duke of York visited our Digital Lab to see what researchers are developing. He was very nice and smiling all the time. He watched all the prepared demos and listened to individual researchers. I helped to my supervisor to set up everything for demonstration and I stayed with him as crowd and support with no aim to speak about anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ikea seminar</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/02/27/ikea-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2009 16:09:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/02/27/ikea-seminar/</guid>
      <description>As an Ikea family member, I&amp;rsquo;ve received an email about the kitchen seminar with free breakfast provided. I was wondering if I could learn something new, what would be useful for designing of our future kitchen, so I decided to apply for it. The seminar was on Sunday morning. The Ikea was closed, there were no customers at that time. There were just couple of people standing outside, waiting for one guy who opened the door for us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>England</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/02/16/england/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 22:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/02/16/england/</guid>
      <description>I have already lived in England for one and half year and I haven&amp;rsquo;t written anything about it yet. Well, I decided to write more about how it is to live in this country. First I need to say that it&amp;rsquo;s quite nice evergreen country with temperature around 15 degrees almost all the year. What is really fascinating, the weather can be changed several times over the one day. I have one warning for summer lovers; you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t come here :) But it will be a paradise for those who desperately love raining and clouds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snowing</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/02/04/snowing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 23:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/02/04/snowing/</guid>
      <description>I love white winter especially white Christmas :) , but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see any snow even at home last year. The winter in UK is usually quite mild with around 5 degrees above zero and it&amp;rsquo;s raining all the time. So I basically said bye to snow, when I traveled back to England after the Christmas time. At that time I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that I would have one week like in paradise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Videos</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/09/04/videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2008 21:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/09/04/videos/</guid>
      <description>Since we planned to celebrate our wedding properly, we oganized barbecue one day before our big day. We started to drink as well to be in a good condition for the next day (i&amp;rsquo;m joking :) ). My lovely aunt took charge of preparing the meat (she is really good in it), but we couldn&amp;rsquo;t find the matches so Andrej&amp;rsquo;s father helped her with the fire (in not very traditional way, as you can see below, but it really worked).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honeymoon</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/20/honeymoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2008 19:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/20/honeymoon/</guid>
      <description>We finally found the right place for our honeymoon. It is a wonderful tiny island in Atlantic Ocean, which belongs to Portugal. The island of Madeira is lapped by the waters of the Gulf Stream, so there is nice warm weather. There are beautiful botanic gardens, mountains and views of the ocean and many nice people with their own traditions. We spent there wonderful time and took a huge amount of pictures as well:) You can read more here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wedding announcement</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/10/wedding-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2008 08:32:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/10/wedding-announcement/</guid>
      <description>Here are our wedding announcements. The green one for boys and the pink version for girls :)
     Translation: We like each other, so we are getting married.
16th of August 2008 at 4pm in Virgin Mary&amp;rsquo;s roman catholic church in Senica (Slovakia).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where and when?</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/06/20/where-and-when/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2008 19:47:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/06/20/where-and-when/</guid>
      <description>nullYou would like to congratulate us, breathlessly watch the whole ceremony, bite your nails nervouslly and wait if we will say correct names or just run into the church and shout some mysterious reason why we can&amp;rsquo;t be married and you don&amp;rsquo;t know where and when to come? Well, we have prepared this article specially for you and you can find here all the necessary information.
We&amp;rsquo;ll agree with love to join our lives on 16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/06/20/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2008 18:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/06/20/introduction/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;We like each other, so we got married.&amp;rdquo; To be married or not? That&amp;rsquo;s the question :) and you need to answer it for yourself but after several weeks of marriage we can say that it&amp;rsquo;s even better than before. Andrej is only complaining that I drink his coffee, beer, wine or whatever and he always needs another one, but nothing else has changed :) We belong to each other and we&amp;rsquo;ll live happily ever after.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>