<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Virtualbaby on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/virtualbaby/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Virtualbaby on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2010 20:25:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/virtualbaby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent videos</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/03/04/recent-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2010 20:25:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/03/04/recent-videos/</guid>
      <description>Here are some new videos I made from my application. Enjoy the baby feeding :)
[youtube]http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=579DGUiK0I4[/youtube]
Your browser does not support the video tag.  Your browser does not support the video tag.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D illusion</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/07/08/3d-illusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2009 08:55:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/07/08/3d-illusion/</guid>
      <description>I had a lot of time to think about new features in the virtual baby project during the London expo. There were many people who tried the application and gave me a nice feedback. Well, I got some ideas how to improve whole thing. One of the biggest problem in the environment was that the user miss the depth, so it&amp;rsquo;s sometimes difficult to say where the spoon is in the space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London expo</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/06/21/london-expo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 10:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/06/21/london-expo/</guid>
      <description>I went for three days business trip to London. It was really nice, sunny and quite warm weather, but I relished that only during the evenings because I spent whole days inside talking on exhibition. I have never gone by London underground before, so I was little bit curious about it. I started at Euston with the aim to go to the Excel exhibition centre, thus I spent under ground almost one hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I talked to prince</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/05/08/i-talked-to-prince/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2009 18:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/05/08/i-talked-to-prince/</guid>
      <description>Well, it sounds like from fairytale, but I talked to real prince :)Prince Andrew, the Duke of York visited our Digital Lab to see what researchers are developing. He was very nice and smiling all the time. He watched all the prepared demos and listened to individual researchers. I helped to my supervisor to set up everything for demonstration and I stayed with him as crowd and support with no aim to speak about anything.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>