<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sea on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/sea/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sea on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 21:03:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/sea/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>By the sea</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/07/30/by-the-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 21:03:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/07/30/by-the-sea/</guid>
      <description>We have already forgotten that we were at the sea, but Dominik is still talking about the big bucket pouring water into the pool. Finally, both our kids swam in the sea and were anxiously watching little crabs running at the bottom. Olivia took part in all creative activities (she made bracelets, paper fish and octopus, and she painted a litttle rabbit) and in the meantime, Dominik was exploring the swimming pools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autumn holiday at the sea</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/09/30/autumn-holiday-at-the-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 21:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/09/30/autumn-holiday-at-the-sea/</guid>
      <description>This year&amp;rsquo;s summer holiday ended up as an autumn holiday. With September coming, itwas suddenly time for rain, wind and less sunshine. So I packed all the things like waterproof trousers, jackets and boots and we set off. We were outside all day long, even though it was raining. Dominik joyfully jumped in puddles and Olivia danced in the rain. With the kids on their bouncing bikes, we went through both parks (camping Italy and Union Lido), with stops on all the playgrounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cavallino</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/09/22/cavallino/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 20:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/09/22/cavallino/</guid>
      <description>We ended this summer with a trip to Italy. This time we were in one camping park near to Venice. On the way there we passed the Alps through many tunnels and after each tunnel Olivia said: &amp;ldquo;more&amp;rdquo;. The park was like a big village with lots of trees, nicely groomed and clean. There already were less people in tents and caravans, but the camping homes were quite busy. There were mostly families with children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cala Ratjada</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/07/01/cala-ratjada/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 10:48:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/07/01/cala-ratjada/</guid>
      <description>This year, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t decide where to go on holiday. My usual desire for trips became unbalanced due to the work fatigue and it was replaced by a new desire (very unusual for me) to go to sea on a beautiful sandy beach and at most to make a trip to some of the local restaurants for culinary specialties. Andrej couldn&amp;rsquo;t believe his ears (after all those years with me, he has experienced many things but he only dreamed quietly about such a vacation with me when we became a couple) and a sudden panic seized him, what we&amp;rsquo;re actually going to do there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Porto</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/04/13/porto/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 09:12:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/04/13/porto/</guid>
      <description>I would like to share my impressions from another country with you. I visited Portugal two weeks ago. I already knew that it is the lovely country as we went toMadeira for our honeymoon, but I found out that there is still so much to explore. My Portuguese friend also recommended me to go to south west coast for beautiful sceneries and relax, to relish sun and Atlantic ocean. So I consider it as a very nice inspiration for a future holiday This time I traveled to Braga for a Serious games conference and I spent several hours in Porto.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poseidon gardens</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/23/poseidon-gardens/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 11:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/23/poseidon-gardens/</guid>
      <description>We went out on a day trip to Poseidon gardens in the middle of the week. We were little bit afraid of the hot termal water in the swimming pools in such a warm weather and we had also sunburn more than it&amp;rsquo;s appropriate in the hot water :) We had concern about the weather when we saw first time the only hill on the island covered with the grey clouds in the morning, but after breakfast, swimming in the pool and reading on the sun beds we set off for the trip towards the Citara beach and Poseidon gardens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trips through the Ischia</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/23/trips-through-the-ischia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 11:19:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/23/trips-through-the-ischia/</guid>
      <description>You can make as many trips as you want on this island and you will still find some other places where to go. I can say that one week is not long enough for it. If you like hiking you need to see the vulcan which is responsible for all the thermal springs around the island. The name of the vulcan is Monte Epomeo and it is still active but it is not seen outwardly (except the springs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honeymoon</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/20/honeymoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2008 19:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/20/honeymoon/</guid>
      <description>We finally found the right place for our honeymoon. It is a wonderful tiny island in Atlantic Ocean, which belongs to Portugal. The island of Madeira is lapped by the waters of the Gulf Stream, so there is nice warm weather. There are beautiful botanic gardens, mountains and views of the ocean and many nice people with their own traditions. We spent there wonderful time and took a huge amount of pictures as well:) You can read more here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forio</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/06/30/forio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2008 17:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/06/30/forio/</guid>
      <description>This is the town were we lived in a wonderful hotel Corona, which we can only recommend. It is said to be the most visited place by tourists on the island. It has several beaches (we saw and tried all of them), nice centre, several churches and countless streets, which are worth walking. This town is also famous by wine production and amazing thermal park Poseidon gardens.The most famous church is Soccorso&amp;rsquo;s church devoted to Santa Naria delle Neve, which can be seen in the movie Avanti!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evergreen island - Ischia</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/06/28/evergreen-island-ischia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2008 20:44:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/06/28/evergreen-island-ischia/</guid>
      <description>We spent a wonderfull week in Italy last summer. We decided to get known an evergreen thermal island Ischia and people who live there. We tasted several food specialities and relish thermal spa with plenty of thermal springs and swimming pools. The sun was shining, a pleasant wind was blowing when we rest on the beach and we felt like in paradise.This picturesque island could be also characterized by huge lemons and sweet grapes, which we tried several times.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>