<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sweet on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/sweet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sweet on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>ajka-andrej.com powered by [Hugo](//gohugo.io). Theme inspired by [PPOffice](http://github.com/ppoffice).</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 21:51:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/sweet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kaiserschmarrn (imperial smithereens)</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/11/07/kaiserschmarrn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 21:51:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/11/07/kaiserschmarrn/</guid>
      <description>We discovered this sweet meal at Wallberg. First time, we ordered it just to try what it tastes like (since then only on purpose :)). Then I looked for some good recipe and how to prepare it and now I use this slightly modified recipe from the LandLeben magazine.
     Ingredients: {{ 220 g flour (plain one used for pancakes) 8 egg yolks 8 egg whites 400 ml milk (or in combination with whipped cream) 2 tbsp sugar pinch of salt butter to bake a handful of raisins (can be soaked in rum) icing sugar for decoration applesauce for dipping }} Instructions: Mix the egg yolks with sugar and salt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nut sticks</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/12/22/nut-sticks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2011 23:23:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/12/22/nut-sticks/</guid>
      <description>This is one of those recipes, which confirmsthat beauty is in simplicity.It&amp;rsquo;s fast, easy and the result is very tasty. Thanks to my colleague&amp;rsquo;s wife for this wonderful recipe.
      Ingredients: {{ pastry (ready to use sheet can be bought) 150g ground walnuts or almonds 75g sugar 1 egg Amaretto (almond liquor) }} Instructions: Preheat the oven to 200 C or gas mark 6. Prepare the baking paper (a rectangle that fits your baking tray).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple-poppy strudel</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/11/08/apple-poppy-strudel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 23:05:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/11/08/apple-poppy-strudel/</guid>
      <description>A strudel is one of my most favourite cakes.The best thing about it is that it can be prepared as quick as it can be eaten. Well, it&amp;rsquo;s a bit of cheating because I don&amp;rsquo;t count the making of a pastry. Making the proper strudel dough as my grandma used to make, by slogging it on the table and pulling it so that she got a paper-thin cloth, is only my secret desire, which I&amp;rsquo;ll be maybe able to fulfil at some point in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate-banana muffins</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/11/01/chocolate-banana-muffins/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 12:15:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/11/01/chocolate-banana-muffins/</guid>
      <description>This recipe I have to spread further because it&amp;rsquo;s amazing. I got it from my supervisor&amp;rsquo;s wife in England. She made them for me and Andrej when we visited them during my graduation. I think we both felt in love with these great muffins, so here is the recipe:
  Ingredients (for 12 muffins): {{ 2 and half small ripe bananas or 2 bigger ones 125ml sunflower oil 2 eggs 100g brown sugar 225g plain flour 3 tbsp cocoa powder 1 tsp baking powder }} Instructions: Preheat the oven to 200 C (150 C for fan oven) or gas mark 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Countess&#39;s cake</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/11/countess-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/11/countess-cake/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is from my mummy. I like apple cakes and pies in general, but this combines also some nuts, raisins ans cinnamon and it&amp;rsquo;s just really tasty.
 Ingredients:
{{ 450g plain flour 125g Butter/margarine 1tsp baking powder 200g icing sugar 4 yolks 1tsp lemon zest 1tbsp cacao powder }}
Filling:
{{ 7 smaller apples, seadless 2tsp vanilla sugar 2tbsp granulated sugar 70-100g chopped walnuts 70-100g raisins ground cinnamon 4 egg white }}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fruit muffins</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/15/fruit-muffins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/15/fruit-muffins/</guid>
      <description>Muffins are those cakes, perfect for guests, which are very tasty,look great and it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to bake them. I have two simple recipes that work great for me. One is from my English friend Kate and the other one is from one book about muffins I bought in England. I use one of them when I have some frozen berries and the second one for sweet fresh fruit or dried fruit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apples in the dressing gown</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/02/16/apples-in-the-dressing-gown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 14:56:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/02/16/apples-in-the-dressing-gown/</guid>
      <description>My husband is not really very enthusiast for cakes eating and it&amp;rsquo;s sometimes very difficult to bake a good cake for him. Once we were skiing at Snow Paradise Velka Raca in Slovakia. It was lovely day, not too many people around and we were pretty tired and hungry, so we decided to sit down in one of the local buffet. We bought sausages with bread, tea and coffe and then we noticed cute baked &amp;ldquo;parcels&amp;rdquo; sprinkled with ice sugar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bábovka (sponge cake)</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/01/14/babovka/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2009 17:37:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/01/14/babovka/</guid>
      <description>Well, I promised to give some recipes to several people, so I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that it&amp;rsquo;ll be much easier to have a special category in blogs just for that :)The first one is more about baking than cooking, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure you&amp;rsquo;ll love it specially with coffee or hot chocolate for breakfast. The original name is bábovka and it is kind of sponge cake. It is usually baked in a round form with a hole in the centre, so the cake has a nice shape and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to slice it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>