<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Usa on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/usa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Usa on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>ajka-andrej.com powered by [Hugo](//gohugo.io). Theme inspired by [PPOffice](http://github.com/ppoffice).</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 16:49:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/usa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rockefeller Centre</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/10/22/rockefeller-centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 16:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/10/22/rockefeller-centre/</guid>
      <description>My two friends were in New York at the end of September and it remained me that I have two more panorama pictures from the &amp;ldquo;big apple&amp;rdquo;. I took them at the top of the Rockefeller Centre. Although I need to say that I prefer the beautiful views from the top of hills not from buildings, these place was amazing.
 There were many people as everywhere, but we could move freely and took pictures of whatever we wanted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philadelphia</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/06/21/philadelphia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 20:26:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/06/21/philadelphia/</guid>
      <description>Philadelphia is the town I could write about for hours. I really enjoyed this place. We spent there four nice sunny days and I don&amp;rsquo;t regret it. Well, there were two my ideas we could avoid, otherwise everything was great. First, I didn&amp;rsquo;t listen to my brother and I chose the hotel where we stayed. It was fine, the room wasn&amp;rsquo;t too big and continental breakfast turned to bagels and cereals, but the interesting thing about it was a room window, which was oriented to the interior of the hotel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the trip to USA</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/05/01/on-the-trip-to-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 17:52:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/05/01/on-the-trip-to-usa/</guid>
      <description>Finally, after a long time of promising, we visited Miško and Ivka in faraway America. We set off at four in the morning, so we could catch a flight from Vienna ( I&amp;rsquo;m really thankful that I have so great parents, that they got up so early and gave us a lift there). We flew with a very small planeto Dusseldorf, where we had a famous pretzel, coffee and I bought a big package of Haribogummibears.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>