<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Park on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/park/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Park on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 21:51:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/park/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind the house</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/11/03/behind-the-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 21:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/11/03/behind-the-house/</guid>
      <description>Behind the neighbour house is a narrow path that leads up to the hill. It takes around three minutes to get on the top where beautiful four huge trees grow. It&amp;rsquo;s charming view from here and with good visibility the Alps can be seen. It&amp;rsquo;s a great place where to go when you want so see a piece of nature and you&amp;rsquo;re to tired or just lazy to go anywhere further.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olympiaberg</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/10/olympiaberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 13:11:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/10/olympiaberg/</guid>
      <description>We were already several times in the Olympia park, but we somehow never got to the highest hill there. To walk on its top is not really difficult, but either the weather didn&amp;rsquo;t work out for us, or we were already tired from walking through the town so we ended up just resting near the lake below. There is a nice paved walkway leading up to the top of the hill that is great view point as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking in the park</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/07/walking-in-the-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 13:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/07/walking-in-the-park/</guid>
      <description>Walking in the park in winter, especially when there is snow everywhere, is absolutely fantastic. Although only until the sunset, because then it starts freezing properly and it is better to hide even in the subway. As I haven&amp;rsquo;t been in Englischer Garten at the time of snow, we went there during the last weekend. Originally, we wanted to go sledging on the nearby hill, but the season was just opened and so we concluded that there would be too many people anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>English garden</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/25/english-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 21:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/25/english-garden/</guid>
      <description>To be honest, I have no idea why this park is called Englischer Garten (English garden). Maybe because it is well-adjusted with properly cut lawn and pretty paths. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest public parks and it&amp;rsquo;s also obviously very popular for relax and walking, doing some sports or just for sitting and reading a book. This park actually reminded me the Central Park in Manhattan, but this one is even larger.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>