<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>England on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/england/</link>
    <description>Recent content in England on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 19:12:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/england/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Defence</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/03/01/defence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 19:12:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/03/01/defence/</guid>
      <description>Finally, I have an explanation, why I and my dear Andrej had disappeared from Skype since Friday. I flew to England and Andrej was offline, so he didn&amp;rsquo;t have to explain where I was. On Monday I had my final oral examination for my PhD and so I spent a long weekend before it by consulting everything with my supervisors, preparing a presentation and reading again and again my work and related papers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5th of November</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/03/5th-of-november/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2010 20:58:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/03/5th-of-november/</guid>
      <description>Well, I know that this date was quite long time ago and you probably don&amp;rsquo;t even remember it, but British people used to say &amp;ldquo;remember, remember fifth of November&amp;rdquo;. And there is a special reason why, which I found funny, when I first heard about it. A long time ago, in seventeenth century, several catholic conspirators including Guy Fawks (the main &amp;ldquo;hero&amp;rdquo;) wanted to destroy the House of Parliament in England.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pub quiz</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/02/pub-quiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 18:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/02/pub-quiz/</guid>
      <description>Well, I don&amp;rsquo;t celebrate Halloween, because firstly it&amp;rsquo;s an American feast and secondly I think that All saints day is about something else and we have much better tradition of thinking about our relatives. As every year, I honestly completely forgot about it, when someone knocked on our house door. When it was repeated second time by another little cute child dressed as a little pumpkin, my house-mate went to shop and bought a bowl full of sweets and candy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Autumn</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/10/22/the-autumn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 20:11:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/10/22/the-autumn/</guid>
      <description>To say &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s autumn&amp;rdquo; is not really up to date information, especially when at some places in Slovakia is already snowing. But I think this part of year is the most beautiful in England with the most stable weather as well and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help myself taking some lovely pictures.
     Above the fourth tree from right side in the second row of windows is approximately the place where I work :).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bradford</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/10/22/bradford/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 18:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/10/22/bradford/</guid>
      <description>I visited another English town, called Bradford. I spent around three hours by travelling by train so I had enough time to find out more about the cathedral, shopping centres, main square and the University of Bradford where I went for conference.
       The town was quite nice and I had good weather as well (surprisingly :)). The only thing I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect was that I felt a little bit like I was in Near East as I met many Arabic guys and I saw many specialised shops with clothes and food typical for that countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London expo</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/06/21/london-expo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 10:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/06/21/london-expo/</guid>
      <description>I went for three days business trip to London. It was really nice, sunny and quite warm weather, but I relished that only during the evenings because I spent whole days inside talking on exhibition. I have never gone by London underground before, so I was little bit curious about it. I started at Euston with the aim to go to the Excel exhibition centre, thus I spent under ground almost one hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I talked to prince</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/05/08/i-talked-to-prince/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2009 18:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/05/08/i-talked-to-prince/</guid>
      <description>Well, it sounds like from fairytale, but I talked to real prince :)Prince Andrew, the Duke of York visited our Digital Lab to see what researchers are developing. He was very nice and smiling all the time. He watched all the prepared demos and listened to individual researchers. I helped to my supervisor to set up everything for demonstration and I stayed with him as crowd and support with no aim to speak about anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>England</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/02/16/england/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 22:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/02/16/england/</guid>
      <description>I have already lived in England for one and half year and I haven&amp;rsquo;t written anything about it yet. Well, I decided to write more about how it is to live in this country. First I need to say that it&amp;rsquo;s quite nice evergreen country with temperature around 15 degrees almost all the year. What is really fascinating, the weather can be changed several times over the one day. I have one warning for summer lovers; you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t come here :) But it will be a paradise for those who desperately love raining and clouds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snowing</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/02/04/snowing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 23:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/02/04/snowing/</guid>
      <description>I love white winter especially white Christmas :) , but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see any snow even at home last year. The winter in UK is usually quite mild with around 5 degrees above zero and it&amp;rsquo;s raining all the time. So I basically said bye to snow, when I traveled back to England after the Christmas time. At that time I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that I would have one week like in paradise.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>