<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>England on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/england/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in England on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>ajka-andrej.com powered by [Hugo](//gohugo.io). Theme inspired by [PPOffice](http://github.com/ppoffice).</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/england/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Defence</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/03/01/defence</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 19:12:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/03/01/defence</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally, I have an explanation, why I and my dear Andrej had disappeared from Skype since Friday. I
flew to England and Andrej was offline, so he didn&amp;rsquo;t have to explain where I was. On Monday I had my final oral examination for my PhD and so I spent a long weekend before it by
consulting everything with my supervisors, preparing a presentation and reading again and again my
work and related papers. As England must be always somehow unique, this examination is also special
comparing with other countries and I finally understand why it is called defence. It is not just a
formal matter, in which the student presents his work to mass audience with safe title in his
pocket. A thesis is read by two experts in the field, one internal and one external. They read it
in the details and write up all sorts of comments and send report to the university. You and your
supervisors do not have access to this information and you can only guess what their opinion on
your work is, what they are interested in and you spend some days by reading their papers so you
learn about them as much as possible. Your final examination is a discussion with these two guys.
One advisor of examiners must be present as a witness, but has no right to intervene in defence. In
essence, there may be your supervisors present as well, but as they cannot intervene neither, they
usually stay in their office nervously stepping two hours, which is usual time of the defence.
There are four types of the results you can get. The first one is that you pass without any changes
that needed to be done, but that is very rare case, because the examiners always find a typo in the
work that needs to be corrected. The second option are minor changes. That means that something
small has to be rewritten or added, some mistakes need to be corrected. The third option are major
changes. This is more problematic, as you usually have to perform some new experiment or study. But
it is still not a disaster, because when you finish it and add it to your work you will pass. It
just costs a lot of time. The last option is to not pass. Well, your supervisor should tell you
when he/she thinks that your work is not worthy PhD yet, but it also happens. The defence is all
about communication and your skills to convince them about what you have done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;article-gallery-photos2&#34;&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/praca.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/praca_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
   &lt;/div&gt;



On Monday morning I had such a strange mood and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop smiling. I chatted with my
supervisor about things like what is my contribution to knowledge, the main hypothesis and how
could be my work applied in reality and extended to other applications. Then I fed myself with some
sandwich. I ate sweet biscuits and drunk cocoa to calm down. I drank enormous amount of water and I
still felt dehydrated. In the afternoon, I started trembling until the advisor of examiners came to
pick me up. After a short presentation of the main points of my work, the examiners started asking
all possible kind of questions, but luckily I could answer all of them. And then we went through
whole thesis in detail, examining all the objectives, experiments, statistics, etc. that were used.
Thanks to glazed room I could sometimes see one of my supervisors drinking hot chocolate trying to
see what is going on in our room and then another one how he was occasionally looking out from his
office if we finished or not. My defence lasted three hours and ten minutes. Although I had really
good feeling about it, I felt exhausted after all that talking and explaining. Then I waited 20
minutes outside until they decided what the verdict was. I passed with minor changes and they
thanked me for a nice discussion. My supervisors looked incredibly happy and I drank another litre
of water. I celebrated the result with my colleagues, we had a nice dinner and in the evening I
felt asleep at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that&amp;rsquo;s the weekend summary. Currently I am with my dear husband and I enjoy that feeling when
I realise that it already is behind me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5th of November</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/03/5th-of-november</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2010 20:58:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/03/5th-of-november</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I know that this date was quite long time ago and you probably don&amp;rsquo;t even remember it, but
British people used to say &amp;ldquo;remember, remember fifth of November&amp;rdquo;. And there is a special reason
why, which I found funny, when I first heard about it. A long time ago, in seventeenth century, several catholic conspirators including Guy Fawks (the main
&amp;ldquo;hero&amp;rdquo;) wanted to destroy the House of Parliament in England. They somehow managed to place massive
amount of gunpowder in an undercroft underneath the House of Lords. But they were betrayed before
they could let it explode. Finally, all the conspirators were discovered and executed. British
people call this night Bonfire night and they celebrate that the House of Parliament stands still
on its place.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;div class=&#34;article-gallery-photos2&#34;&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3088.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3088_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3089.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3089_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3090.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3090_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3091.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3091_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
   &lt;/div&gt;




&lt;p&gt;During this night there are fireworks everywhere. My housemates told me that there is also tradition
to build bonfire on which these &amp;ldquo;guys&amp;rdquo; are burnt symbolically, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t so usual nowadays.
Traditional food is a jacket potato. It is the big baked potato (in jacket) cut into two halves
with filling in the middle. Typical filling is beans in tomato sauce and you can sprinkle the whole
potato with grated cheese.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;div class=&#34;article-gallery-photos2&#34;&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3142.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3142_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3143.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3143_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3144.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3144_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3157.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3157_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
   &lt;/div&gt;




&lt;p&gt;The last Bonfire night was great. We made our own little firework in the garden, ate the jacket
potatoes and had just nice time. And then we discovered the beauty of the combination of sparkles
with DSLR camera :) So we draw many things and our names in the air and I really recommend this
activity :)&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;div class=&#34;article-gallery-photos2&#34;&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3183.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3183_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3186.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3186_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3192.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3192_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3204.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/IMG_3204_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
   &lt;/div&gt;



</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pub quiz</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/02/pub-quiz</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 18:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/02/pub-quiz</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I don&amp;rsquo;t celebrate Halloween, because firstly it&amp;rsquo;s an American feast and secondly I think that
All saints day is about something else and we have much better tradition of thinking about our
relatives. As every year, I honestly completely forgot about it, when someone knocked on our house
door. When it was repeated second time by another little cute child dressed as a little pumpkin, my
house-mate went to shop and bought a bowl full of sweets and candy. Then we had some more visitors
and I thought the feast was over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day after, on All saints day, we went to the pub in Coventry. We drunk cider and enjoyed
conversation and watching several people dressed as Dracula or something covered with blood etc.
But I figured out the actual reason why we went to the pub on Sunday evening only later. There is a
very english tradition to do the pub quiz on every Sunday or also on Tuesday in the most of pubs. I
felt like a really stupid foreigner when I said to my friends that I have never heard about it
before (and they were staring at me little bit weirdly as well :)). So we waited till some guy
walked around with questionnaire forms and papers with pictures and then we listened carefully to
questions and tried to fill the answers. This quiz was special, because it was all about some
creatures and horror movies. One group of questions was about to compare different couple of men
and try to guess who was &amp;ldquo;bigger&amp;rdquo; killer. We also tried to figured out some creatures acting in
some movies from the pictures. I can honestly say that I had no idea about at least half of the
questions, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t alone :)and it was quite fun anyway. Well, I learned again something new
and traditional.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Autumn</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/10/22/the-autumn</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 20:11:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/10/22/the-autumn</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To say &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s autumn&amp;rdquo; is not really up to date information, especially when at some places in
Slovakia is already snowing. But I think this part of year is the most beautiful in England with
the most stable weather as well and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help myself taking some lovely pictures.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;div class=&#34;article-gallery-photos2&#34;&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/campus/IMG_0014.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/campus/IMG_0014_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/campus/IMG_0015.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/campus/IMG_0015_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/campus/IMG_0016.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/campus/IMG_0016_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/campus/IMG_0017.JPG&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/campus/IMG_0017.JPG&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
   &lt;/div&gt;




&lt;p&gt;Above the fourth tree from right side in the second row of windows is approximately the place where
I work :). The reason why I took picture of that little tree is that is somehow special. It is
memorial tree and we planted it in the middle of October near our building since it were two years
our colleague and friend tragically passed away.It happened at very beginning when I came here, so
I didn&amp;rsquo;t have opportunity to know him very well, but he was nice guy and it is a pity he is no
longer among us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bradford</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/10/22/bradford</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 18:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/10/22/bradford</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I visited another English town, called Bradford. I spent around three hours by travelling by train
so I had enough time to find out more about the cathedral, shopping centres, main square and the
University of Bradford where I went for conference.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;div class=&#34;article-gallery-photos2&#34;&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/gallery/england/bradford/IMG_0003.JPG&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/gallery/england/bradford/IMG_0003.JPG&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/gallery/england/bradford/IMG_0001.JPG&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/gallery/england/bradford/IMG_0001.JPG&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/gallery/england/bradford/IMG_0002.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/gallery/england/bradford/IMG_0002_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/gallery/england/bradford/IMG_0005.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/gallery/england/bradford/IMG_0005_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/gallery/england/bradford/IMG_0007.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/gallery/england/bradford/IMG_0007_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/gallery/england/bradford/IMG_0004.JPG&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/gallery/england/bradford/IMG_0004.JPG&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
   &lt;/div&gt;




&lt;p&gt;The town was quite nice and I had good weather as well (surprisingly :)). The only thing I didn&amp;rsquo;t
expect was that I felt a little bit like I was in Near East as I met many Arabic guys and I saw
many specialised shops with clothes and food typical for that countries. I only found later that
English people call this town a new Pakistan. The nice advantage for tourists is a free bus, which
makes the circuit around the town centre and stops on every important place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London expo</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/06/21/london-expo</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 10:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/06/21/london-expo</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I went for three days business trip to London. It was really nice, sunny and quite warm weather, but
I relished that only during the evenings because I spent whole days inside talking on exhibition. I have never gone by London underground before, so I was little bit curious about it. I started at
Euston with the aim to go to the Excel exhibition centre, thus I spent under ground almost one
hour. Considering the underground in New York, the London one seemed to be very tiny with small
corridors and too many people, especially in Friday afternoon. I regret a bit tall people, who need
to travel by round-ceiling trains under the ground daily, where the only comfortable place for them
is in the middle of a wagon. The good side was that it was clean everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;article-gallery-photos2&#34;&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/18062009020-e1303843164427.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/18062009020-e1303843164427_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/DSC_00044.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/DSC_00044_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/DSC_00045.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/DSC_00045_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/DSC_00048.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/DSC_00048_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/DSC_00049.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/DSC_00049_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
   &lt;/div&gt;



The Excel centre is in the outskirts of London. It is very quiet area near the river with several
hotels and blocks of flats, where the rent is the same as mine but per week instead of month. The
Excel centre was a busy place with several exhibitions running at the same time and plenty of fast
food places. Considering that we were on NHS expo about health living I found quite funny, when all
the participants went ahead for lunch to fast food stands.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I talked to prince</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/05/08/i-talked-to-prince</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2009 18:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/05/08/i-talked-to-prince</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it sounds like from fairytale, but I talked to real prince :)Prince Andrew, the Duke of York
visited our Digital Lab to see what researchers are developing. He was very nice and smiling all the time. He watched all the prepared demos and listened to
individual researchers. I helped to my supervisor to set up everything for demonstration and I
stayed with him as crowd and support with no aim to speak about anything. But when the prince came
and my supervisor showed him the project about the virtual baby feeding I&amp;rsquo;m working on, he wanted
me to speak about it by myself. It made me really happy that he didn&amp;rsquo;t pay attention just to big
professors, but also to ordinary students like me :)&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;div class=&#34;article-gallery-photos2&#34;&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/05/IMG_1408.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/05/IMG_1408_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/05/IMG_1455.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/05/IMG_1455_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/05/IMG_1456.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/05/IMG_1456_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/05/IMG_1458.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/05/IMG_1458_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
   &lt;/div&gt;



</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>England</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/02/16/england</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 22:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/02/16/england</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have already lived in &lt;a title=&#34;England&#34;
href=&#34;http://www.ajka-andrej.com/gallery/england/&#34;&gt;England&lt;/a&gt; for one and half year and I haven&amp;rsquo;t
written anything about it yet. Well, I decided to write more about how it is to live in this
country. First I need to say that it&amp;rsquo;s quite nice evergreen country with temperature around 15 degrees almost
all the year. What is really fascinating, the weather can be changed several times over the one
day. I have one warning for summer lovers; you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t come here :) But it will be a paradise for
those who desperately love raining and clouds. Speaking of weather &amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s always good thing to
talk about among friends here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;article-gallery-photos2&#34;&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/campus/img-18.JPG&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/campus/img-18.JPG&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/campus/img-21.JPG&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/campus/img-21.JPG&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
   &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;article-gallery-photos2&#34;&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/coventry/IMG_0150.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/coventry/IMG_0150_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
   &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first came here I was enchantment with the environment. There is beautiful green grass
everywhere and every house has facade from typical bricks. Even Tesco looks nice not like ugly box
in my home country. Well, you can also say that every house looks the same, which is true, but some
of them are really nice. People are nice and helpful, but little bit reserved. They are crazy in
wearing clothes. They are either conservative or they are able to combine everything together. But
the common thing is that people are used to cold, they usually don&amp;rsquo;t wear socks and wear just kind
of open shoes even in snowy weather. Hm &amp;hellip; I would like to be so hardy sometimes. Anyway, if you
really want to know, what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about, just go for clubbing during the winter, sit down in
the club with the glass of good wine, watch and enjoy :)You would need to be English to understand.
After a while you will find out that most of the days during the year is cloudy weather, when
everything is grey and it&amp;rsquo;s really difficult to get up in the morning and you will need to learn
many ways how to make yourself happy.The worst combination is cold day with drizzling, when you can
feel the weather under your skin. Even it would be better to stay in the warm bed covered by the
duvet, you need to go out and fight with melancholy, which surrounds you. On the other side, when
the sun is shining, you are perfectly happy and you relish that. I have never been so happy from
the sun than here.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;div class=&#34;article-gallery-photos2&#34;&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/york/IMG_0249.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/york/IMG_0249_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/york/IMG_0255.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/york/IMG_0255_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/leamingtonspa/IMG_0140.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/leamingtonspa/IMG_0140_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/birmingham/IMG_0020.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/birmingham/IMG_0020_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
   &lt;/div&gt;




&lt;p&gt;Another interesting thing is food. Typical english food is fish and chips with peas, what is
basically saying that the food is not really strong side of this country. When I came here I was
desperate from bread, flour, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find anything similar to tvaroh (it&amp;rsquo;s not the same as
cottage cheese) and bryndza and I still don&amp;rsquo;t like too much the taste of milk here. But to defense,
I found huge amount of species, fruit, vegetables and fresh herbs and fish and I can say that I eat
much healthier than before and I do love salmon prepared in any way. You just need to know what to
choose. There are sausages, beans in tomato sauce, bacon and chips everywhere. You can sometimes
find perfect sandwich. I love one in the University House - turkey with salad in crunchy ciabatta.
The food is also influenced by many cultures, so there are many chinese, italian, indian, spanish,
polish etc. restaurants. But I need to say that home made english food is great and I do love all
the muffins and cakes. Oh, if you are familiar with the slovak meaning of the word puding, it&amp;rsquo;s
completely different from english pudding. They are able to name pudding every kind of sponge cake.
If you are looking for the desert I mentioned firstly it&amp;rsquo;s more like custard. This country is
interesting in many ways and it&amp;rsquo;s definitely worth to come here, but as a tourist. I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine
to live here permanently. It&amp;rsquo;s good experience, but it&amp;rsquo;s too different from the rest of Europe. I&amp;rsquo;m
probably biased because I live here without my lovely husband, but I heard the same opinion from
too many people here, so I believe that it&amp;rsquo;s true. Well, come and try :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snowing</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/02/04/snowing</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 23:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/02/04/snowing</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love white winter especially white Christmas :) , but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see any snow even at home last
year. The winter in UK is usually quite mild with around 5 degrees above zero and it&amp;rsquo;s raining all
the time. So I basically said bye to snow, when I traveled back to England after the Christmas time. At that
time I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that I would have one week like in paradise. There were a lot of news about
heavy snowing causing problems, several schools were closed and we have received some emails to be
careful on the way home, but I was really happy when I could see everything covered by snow one
morning and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t alone. MyEnglishhouse-mateswere happy too. Everything was white and you could
listen to snowy crunching as you walked and see many people building snowmen. There were a lot of
people who took pictures of their friends making snowy angels on the ground. Well it&amp;rsquo;s not everyday
but it made me happy at least for a while :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;article-gallery-photos2&#34;&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/coventry/IMG_0229.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/coventry/IMG_0229_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/coventry/IMG_0240.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/coventry/IMG_0240_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
   &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;img class=&#34;ngg-singlepic ngg-left&#34;
src=&#34;http://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/coventry/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_0229.jpg&#34;
alt=&#34;IMG_0229&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;article-gallery-photos2&#34;&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/coventry/IMG_0241.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/coventry/IMG_0241_thumb.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
        &lt;a style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34; class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/coventry/IMG_0006.JPG&#34; rel=&#34;group1&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ajka-andrej.com/wp-content/gallery/england/coventry/IMG_0006.JPG&#34; itemprop=&#34;image&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; height=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        
   &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>