<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Switzerland on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/switzerland/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Switzerland on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 09:47:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/switzerland/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Half a year old</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/09/04/half-a-year-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 09:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/09/04/half-a-year-old/</guid>
      <description>Olivia managed another growth spurt (together with us). From what I read, we bore this quite well. She didn&amp;rsquo;t lose her appetite, quite the opposite. She didn&amp;rsquo;t cry too much, just started to realise the distances and occasionally gurgled, when she saw me going away from the room. But she slept less. In the evening, she always woke up after one hour of sleeping full of energy and ready to play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skiing in Laax</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/10/skiing-in-laax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2011 08:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/10/skiing-in-laax/</guid>
      <description>This year I made several New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions (I will sometimes write about them). One of them is to ski this winter properly. Before Christmas, we decided to visit our friends in Switzerland and we were going to look at several ski resorts near Zurich. But this plan failed, because during our planned weekend heat wave arrived from Spain and at 1100 m it was suddenly 7 degrees. Finally, we opted for the more distant, but higher placed resort Laax, where we were skiing at around 2500 m at a pleasant temperature just below zero.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zurich</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/17/zurich/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2010 18:23:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/17/zurich/</guid>
      <description>We were somehow tired enough not to go seeing night Zurich on Saturday evening, but I think it must be beautiful. We went there the next day and I really loved the atmosphere of that city. If there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any snow, I think we are in one of the coastal towns somewhere in Italy (possibly in France, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never been there). There were many narrow streets and nice colorful buildings with wooden shutters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bern</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/16/bern/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 19:18:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/16/bern/</guid>
      <description>After Friday traveling, chatting and walking among lovely Swiss houses in our surroundings, we went to a capital city - Bern. It&amp;rsquo;s quite small but very cute and there are bears all around :)Well, I mean pictures, symbols and statues in the shape of the bear. There are many nice historical buildings and arched underpasses with small shops everywhere. There are loads of Italian restaurants, shops with chocolate and pralines and of course shops with watches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How we went to Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/16/how-we-went-to-switzerland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 17:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/02/16/how-we-went-to-switzerland/</guid>
      <description>Our friends &amp;ldquo;chrobaci&amp;rdquo; invited us to visit them and we simply couldn&amp;rsquo;t say no :)After a long working week, Andrej took two days off, we rent a car, checked on a google map how to get there, packed some things and set off a journey. We turned on a navigation and as it showed approximately good amount of kilometers and time of arriving, we relied on it.We came to Bodensee lake (which is really huge) and when we suddenly left the highway and stayed on the right side of the lake in Germany, we started thinking if the navigating is right.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>