<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Savoury on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/savoury/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Savoury on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 May 2012 22:15:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/savoury/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinach and ricotta tortellini</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/05/12/spinach-and-ricotta-tortellini/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2012 22:15:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/05/12/spinach-and-ricotta-tortellini/</guid>
      <description>Last time I wrote how to make a pasta dough and I dreamed about the tortellini. Than I tried to make this lovely pasta again and considering a very tasty result, I bring this recipe to you :) Make the filling first, than prepare the dough according to the instructions here (this way the dough will not becomedry while you preparing the other things.), but use thickness 9 for the final dough sheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crustless spinach quiche</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/03/crustless-spinach-quiche/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 14:04:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/03/crustless-spinach-quiche/</guid>
      <description>This is one of those recipes, which are really easy to prepare and it is also a nice opportunity for the spinach to be spent :). I did many changes to the original recipe. However, I think there are still loads of possibilities for improvements and adaptation to different tastes.
   Ingredients (for 24cm baking form): (general stuff) {{ 1&amp;frasl;2 cup flour 1&amp;frasl;2 cup creme fraiche (I usually use the whole 200g package) 1 cup milk (I use finely shredded potatoes for the richer version instead) 4 eggs butter for greasing }} (to taste) It can be whatever you like - chopped zucchini, tomatoes, salami, broccoli, cauliflower &amp;hellip; The mass all together should fit into 1 and 1&amp;frasl;2 cup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lasagna with minced meat</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/07/11/lasagna-with-minced-meat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2009 20:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/07/11/lasagna-with-minced-meat/</guid>
      <description>My house mate who loves cooking of pasta inspired me with a new mixture of spices, so I tried it in Lasagna with minced meat.
              **Ingredients: ** {{ 2 spring onions, chopped 1 onion, finely chopped &amp;gt;3 garlic cloves, minced 450g minced meat 350g tomato sauce 2 chopped tomatoes or some cherry tomatoes cut in half 200g eidam cheese, grated 12 pieces of uncooked Lasagna pasta black pepper, salt 1tsp of each - basil, fennel seeds, coriander, mint</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>