<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wedding on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/wedding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wedding on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2008 21:55:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/wedding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Videos</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/09/04/videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2008 21:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/09/04/videos/</guid>
      <description>Since we planned to celebrate our wedding properly, we oganized barbecue one day before our big day. We started to drink as well to be in a good condition for the next day (i&amp;rsquo;m joking :) ). My lovely aunt took charge of preparing the meat (she is really good in it), but we couldn&amp;rsquo;t find the matches so Andrej&amp;rsquo;s father helped her with the fire (in not very traditional way, as you can see below, but it really worked).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honeymoon</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/20/honeymoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2008 19:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/20/honeymoon/</guid>
      <description>We finally found the right place for our honeymoon. It is a wonderful tiny island in Atlantic Ocean, which belongs to Portugal. The island of Madeira is lapped by the waters of the Gulf Stream, so there is nice warm weather. There are beautiful botanic gardens, mountains and views of the ocean and many nice people with their own traditions. We spent there wonderful time and took a huge amount of pictures as well:) You can read more here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wedding announcement</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/10/wedding-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2008 08:32:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/10/wedding-announcement/</guid>
      <description>Here are our wedding announcements. The green one for boys and the pink version for girls :)
     Translation: We like each other, so we are getting married.
16th of August 2008 at 4pm in Virgin Mary&amp;rsquo;s roman catholic church in Senica (Slovakia).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>