<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Germany on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/germany/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Germany on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 17:19:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/germany/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Forester&#39;s house St. Hubertus</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/12/31/foresters-house-st-hubertus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 17:19:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/12/31/foresters-house-st-hubertus/</guid>
      <description>In the summer, enjoyable place for some beer and Bavarian food, in the winter a romantic place for Advent markets and walking through the snowy forest. First time, we were here cycling in the summer (the house is in the near forest about 2km from its edge) and we met there whole families on their trips relishing forest shade and the local atmosphere.
Well, last time I accidentally found the program leaflet for the Advent time, so we parked nearby and we walked on the snowy road towards the stands with Christmas decorations and refreshments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November Wallberg</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/11/17/november-wallberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2012 07:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/11/17/november-wallberg/</guid>
      <description>There are already many articles about this hill on our web page and I need to say that it&amp;rsquo;s one of our favourite hill. But two weeks ago, we had such a nice visit, to my great pleasure longing for trips led by a almost three years old young tourist. And so we went on trips to many places and one of them was Wallberg. It&amp;rsquo;s clear to me that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to convince Andrej to go there otherwise (certainly not in November and not at all in that snow except the sledding).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kampenwand</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/10/28/kampenwand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 19:02:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/10/28/kampenwand/</guid>
      <description>This was the only trip (not counting the local trips in the forest and cycling), which we managed to do during the summer. I planned more of them, but thanks to my incredible fatigue, I was glad that we were able to get at least here. Kampenwand itself is a rocky hill with a cross at the very top (the largest one in the Bavarian Alps), but the name is used to identify all the surrounding tourist area with lots of hiking routes, cottages and chapels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October snow</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/10/28/october-snow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 10:48:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/10/28/october-snow/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, it started snowing. The temperature dropped to zero and we were quite pleased that we changed from summer to the winter car tires last week. Children here are having autumn holiday next week, but they can already start writing about winter fun. Well, it is said it should become a bit warmer and I hope so. It would be nice to see snow again, but first in December.
     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sudelfeld</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/03/11/sudelfeld/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2012 16:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/03/11/sudelfeld/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, we went skiing again. This time we chose Sudelfeld ski resort. Our colleague told us that it is a little bit small and local, but less people know about it and therefore it usually is not so crowded on Saturday. The weather was absolutely fantastic, there were really not so many people and we were quite surprised when we found that it is not as small as we heard. In addition, it is a great place for skiing with children with lots of children&amp;rsquo;s short and mild slopes and help with all lifts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spitzingsee</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/02/01/spitzingsee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 21:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/02/01/spitzingsee/</guid>
      <description>Today, we went skiing to the lake Spitzingsee. The temperature dropped to -10 and predicted sunshine showed up just before lunch, but skiing was great. Good maintained slopes and only few people caused that we already had enough around the lunch and we returned back home quite tired. I didn&amp;rsquo;t took a lot of pictures, only one panorama after which I seriously had to warm up my hands. But I hope to fix that this summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sledding</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/12/29/tehotenstvo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 00:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/12/29/tehotenstvo/</guid>
      <description>We went sledding during our Christmas holiday to relax and spend our time wisely :) Here are some pictures from the last year. This time, we set off earlier and so we basically had the whole track for ourselves. I tried to make some videos during the sledding ( on steeper sections it&amp;rsquo;s a bit shaky because I had to brake too). The experience was again absolutely terrific. In between, we refreshed ourselves in the panorama restaurant on the hill, warmed up on the sun and I took a panorama from that beautiful view around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autumn</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/11/21/autumn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 21:59:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/11/21/autumn/</guid>
      <description>This season is actually already at the end, but it occurred to me that I still have some photos I didn&amp;rsquo;t show you. We walked again to the local tower and on its top, because it seemed to me that an autumn view might be worth it and I was right. ( You can seethe summer view here.) Everything was so beautifully coloured. We just need to set off earlier because it becomes dark very quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/11/08/walking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 21:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/11/08/walking/</guid>
      <description>I love autumn from several reasons. It&amp;rsquo;s not so cold yet, but also not so hot anymore and so you can wrap yourself in a warm blanket and relish a cup of tea. The weather outside is just amazing and stable and the sky can be unbelievably blue. And those colours &amp;hellip; as we moved we travel about ten minutesto work through a forest and that is so wonderful look that fits well immediately after waking, but also to relax after work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind the house</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/11/03/behind-the-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 21:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/11/03/behind-the-house/</guid>
      <description>Behind the neighbour house is a narrow path that leads up to the hill. It takes around three minutes to get on the top where beautiful four huge trees grow. It&amp;rsquo;s charming view from here and with good visibility the Alps can be seen. It&amp;rsquo;s a great place where to go when you want so see a piece of nature and you&amp;rsquo;re to tired or just lazy to go anywhere further.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wiesn</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/10/26/wiesn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 18:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/10/26/wiesn/</guid>
      <description>Another Oktoberfest (or Wiesn as local people would say) behind us, and this year we didn&amp;rsquo;t miss it. Well, we didn&amp;rsquo;t join the official event in traditional clothes inside one of the huge tents, but we dived in the great atmosphere and we drank one litter of beer. We didn&amp;rsquo;t see the initial ceremony this year, because we weren&amp;rsquo;t in the mood to go to the town in a rainy weather, but we did spent some hours together with our colleagues drinking beer at Oktoberfest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wendelstein</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/09/02/wendelstein/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 22:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/09/02/wendelstein/</guid>
      <description>Finally, we went on a tour we had already planned for early summer. Somehow, it always rained or we were not at home and so I could only study our route theoretically. But last week we had an ideal weather and so we set off on the trip in the morning. We parked next to the cable-car station just outside the village Osterhofen and then we hiked three hours and three quarters up the hill Wendelstein 1838 m (at least we thought so according to a tourist guide, in fact, we went up two and half hours).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ebersberg</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/08/31/ebersberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 07:19:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/08/31/ebersberg/</guid>
      <description>Recently, we spent some time searching for a new apartment and beside this activity we discovered various places where we haven&amp;rsquo;t previously been. We were fascinated by one such a district town at very first visit and so we went there during one weekend again to get to know it a little bit more. We already get used to the plane everywhere in Munich (I don&amp;rsquo;t count those few artificial hills there) and we were very pleasantly surprised by the hilly terrain of the town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nature trip</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/10/nature-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 22:19:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/10/nature-trip/</guid>
      <description>Since urban tourism is quite difficult, and as we don&amp;rsquo;t want to destroy our visitors (we would like them to come again), we have always at hand some trip to nature. Neither last Saturday it was different and we went to our quite favourite place, on the hill Wallberg. Up and down we drove a cable-car, but then we hiked to the top of the peak (about half an hour). The chapel, which was reconstructed is already nice and finished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easter trip</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/04/27/easter-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 21:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/04/27/easter-trip/</guid>
      <description>Last Friday we went to Easter trip. We had a beautiful warm weather, around 25 degrees and I saw a newspaper tip for a nice trip to a waterfall. I thought that in this lovely April weather everything is melting and so there could be a lot of water. After a small survey, I found two other even bigger waterfalls near the original one. From parking places it was up to 20 minutes walk to each one and so we decided to see all of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walchensee</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/03/31/walchensee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 08:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/03/31/walchensee/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend, we went on a trip to the lake Walchensee. It&amp;rsquo;s about an hour from our home by car in a beautiful environment surrounded by the mountains. This time we didn&amp;rsquo;t go alone, but we took our visitors as well. The weather was amazing and was also pleasantly warm although, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t warm enough to melt all the snow on the hills above. Near the lake we took a cable-car and we travelled four minutes about 800 meters higher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garmisch-Classic</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/31/garmisch-classic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 20:51:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/31/garmisch-classic/</guid>
      <description>This is another option (not counting the Tyrolean Alps around the corner) to go skiing when you are in Grainau. And not only that. Cable cars operate here also in the summer and there is a wide variety of hiking trails offered by the hills.
    One of the black slopes was closed due to the preparation for the World Championships (5a on the slope plan), but we didn&amp;rsquo;t miss it at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zugspitzplatt</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/31/zugspitzplatt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 07:53:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/31/zugspitzplatt/</guid>
      <description>I must say that this place is simply wonderful. We haven&amp;rsquo;t been to Zugspitze (the highest peak in Germany, 2962m), because we somehow couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop skiing in such a beautiful weather. But we agreed that we would make this trip in the summer.
 I&amp;rsquo;ve never really thought about the name of the peak until now, when I found out that you can go just below it by train (der Zug).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holiday in Grainau</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/30/holiday-in-grainau/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2011 17:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/30/holiday-in-grainau/</guid>
      <description>This time we traveled only about an hour and a quarter by car from our home to the village Grainau. We wanted to ski and get to know our surroundings better. We stayed in a very nice and cozy house with a great breakfast (Gasthaus Geigener). The weather was quite good, we skied whole the week except the two days and my darling named our vacation week assembly.
     One snowy day, we made a train trip to the nearby Tyrol village Lermoos and then we went back to Garmisch Partenkirchen, where we found a great Italian restaurant for lunch and we saw the ski springboard and slopes for the upcoming World Championships.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sledding</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/20/sledding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2010 15:11:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/20/sledding/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend, we took advantage of a good weather after a long week of snowing and went sledding. We&amp;rsquo;ve already been on the Wallberg hill for hiking before. This time we used the cable-car on the way up and we sledded down the hill.
We borrowed sleds each separately, but later we agreed that next time we&amp;rsquo;ll sled together as it requires an appropriate weight. Andrej was faster and he didn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;fly&amp;rdquo; after each bump on the road.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking in the park</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/07/walking-in-the-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 13:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/07/walking-in-the-park/</guid>
      <description>Walking in the park in winter, especially when there is snow everywhere, is absolutely fantastic. Although only until the sunset, because then it starts freezing properly and it is better to hide even in the subway. As I haven&amp;rsquo;t been in Englischer Garten at the time of snow, we went there during the last weekend. Originally, we wanted to go sledging on the nearby hill, but the season was just opened and so we concluded that there would be too many people anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas markets</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/07/christmas-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 12:20:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/07/christmas-markets/</guid>
      <description>During the weekend, we went to the Christmas markets. There are quite a lot of them in Munich. Basically, each Munich neighborhood has its own market. We went directly to the Marienplatz in the centre. There were many stands decorated with green boughs and colorful lights. They offered many things, among others, wooden ornaments and toys, candles and Christmas hats. I was really impressed by one stand that offered all sorts of wooden things ( cutting boards, spatula, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oktoberfest</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/10/06/oktoberfest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 14:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/10/06/oktoberfest/</guid>
      <description>anniversary of the Oktoberfest is over and people in traditional costumes are slowly but surely disappearing from the streets and the subway, so people like us dressed only in jeans and T-shirt don&amp;rsquo;t look like tourists anymore.  Although we haven&amp;rsquo;t been in the beer tent on the Theresienwiese, we didn&amp;rsquo;t miss parade at the launch of this year&amp;rsquo;s festivities. There were horse drawn carts with barrels of beer and venison, but also agricultural machinery and many brass bands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wallberg</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/24/wallberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2010 13:22:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/24/wallberg/</guid>
      <description>This time we went a little higher on the hill Wallberg (1722m) and so we increased the elevation to 927m. To get there, we travelled around the Tegernsee lake, which looked beautiful from above. We parked next to the cable-car station and began hiking. You can find more pictures in the gallery.
 Right at the beginning of our journey, we found out that the first cottage, where we wanted to go, was closed (on the winter version of the route) and so we decided that we would take it up with a bit steeper but shorter summer route.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schliersee</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/15/schliersee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2010 20:58:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/15/schliersee/</guid>
      <description>So finally, we made one of our planned trips ( I have 37 more trips in my tourist guide :)). Although in Munich the weather was nice and sunny, 40 minutes southern by our car led to mountains covered by clouds. But it didn&amp;rsquo;t discouraged us and we set off on the path leading us around the lake Schliersee.
 The environment there was really beautiful. It is possible to rent a boat there and we also found the Wellness centre with a swimming pool, slides, sauna and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake in the Olympia park</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/07/05/lake-in-the-olympia-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2010 19:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/07/05/lake-in-the-olympia-park/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve already written about the Olympia park, but that was in November last year and at that time there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any lake but the muddy place and some people who cleaned it. Fortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s the great place for visitors due to the high tower in the centre so we had a great opportunity to go there with our friends and see the actual lake :) There were many people running around or cycling, lot of stands with ice-cream or some sweet cakes and of course many people sitting in the bier garden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bavaria</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/07/05/bavaria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2010 13:17:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/07/05/bavaria/</guid>
      <description>This was one of my less fortunate trip ideas, but on the other hand I don&amp;rsquo;t regret at all that I was there. The question Where? is now on the right place &amp;hellip; in the statue called Bavaria. Recently, we had a second visit here and after a day spent walking in the center and parks, we were thinking, where to go next. I read that there is a statue that was created and built as a symbol of Bavaria, it is 18 m high and it is possible to go in, upstairs and look around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>English garden</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/25/english-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 21:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/25/english-garden/</guid>
      <description>To be honest, I have no idea why this park is called Englischer Garten (English garden). Maybe because it is well-adjusted with properly cut lawn and pretty paths. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest public parks and it&amp;rsquo;s also obviously very popular for relax and walking, doing some sports or just for sitting and reading a book. This park actually reminded me the Central Park in Manhattan, but this one is even larger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Munich</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/24/munich/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 21:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/24/munich/</guid>
      <description>I have never been to Munich before and I feel those few days I spent there weren&amp;rsquo;t enough. I love the historical flair of this city. There are no high modern glass buildings preventing the sun shine to the street, but low stylish buildings with sloping red roofs. There are loads of bakery and little kiosks with pretzels everywhere. Since I love to ramble marketplace, what I have probably inherited from my daddy, I was unbelievable happy to see one directly in the city centre called Viktualienmarkt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A trip toward lakes</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/17/a-trip-toward-lakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2009 06:46:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/17/a-trip-toward-lakes/</guid>
      <description>Finally, after two and half months, I and Andrej have been together again and as we got the car for a couple of days, we decided to go for a trip somewhere. However, the parking in Munich is not the best idea and we wanted to use the car more useful, so we drove toward two lakes near Munich - Starnberg See and Walchensee. Starnberg See is the second largest lake in Bavaria.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>