<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Slovakia on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/slovakia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Slovakia on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 16:32:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/slovakia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer memories</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/10/03/summer-memories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 16:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/10/03/summer-memories/</guid>
      <description>There was no time to write about summer holidays. But at least, I would like to post some photos now. Olivia wanted to mount a go kart with her grandpa and she drew a frame for it in the kindergarden. This year we managed to swim a couple of times in the swimming pool in the backyard, ride horses (I had to as well, because I was afraid that the horse was too big for Dominik) and we made a trip to Korlátko (about an hour of walking) and we walked through the Dolné diery in Vrátna valley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vychylovka and Stará Bystrica</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/09/03/vychylovka-and-stara-bystrica/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 20:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/09/03/vychylovka-and-stara-bystrica/</guid>
      <description>When the weather is bad, you need to find a place where it&amp;rsquo;s better and so we made a trip from Stefanova, immersed in clouds, to the historical forest railway and open-air museum of Kysuce village in Vychylovka. Our children were enthusiastic about the train, sheep and playgrounds and we enjoyed &amp;ldquo;živánska&amp;rdquo; in a local restaurant :) And after a pleasant walk among the wooden houses we stopped in Stara Bystrica to see the only astronomical clock in Slovakia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vrátna valley</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/09/01/vratna-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 20:59:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/09/01/vratna-valley/</guid>
      <description>We wanted to eat some proper slovak food specialties like halušky, pirohy and šúľance, relax and relish the nature and so we made a culinary trip to Štefanova in Vrátna valley. We made a trip to a cottage on Grúň and under Chleb and on every trip we found a playground or sheep, so our children were more than satisfied.
                </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Christmas holiday</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/01/10/the-christmas-holiday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2015 13:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/01/10/the-christmas-holiday/</guid>
      <description>Olivia started talking even more than before and we understand more and more. During the Christmas holiday, she was busy meeting loads of people, chasing cats in the yard and when there was snow we finally rode the wooden sled. The best of all was to shovel snow, then we couldn&amp;rsquo;t get her inside. And we tried to sleep and rest as much as possible.
             Your browser does not support the video tag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mushrooms</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/10/12/mushrooms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 11:09:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/10/12/mushrooms/</guid>
      <description>Finally, we managed to go to gather mushrooms, what we dreamed about all the summer. We dressed properly, put hats on our heads, equipped ourselves with baskets and knives and set off into the forest. Besides youthful mushrooms peeping out of the ground we found also lots of old, mouldy or dried mushrooms and we obviously came at the end of the mushroom season, but we still managed to gather a nice amount of healthy ones and when I consider three-hour walk through the forest, we were very satisfied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Once again in Slovakia</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/10/12/once-again-in-slovakia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 09:01:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/10/12/once-again-in-slovakia/</guid>
      <description>Once again, we travelled to Slovakia to see our friends and family, to gather some mushrooms and to enjoy a feast in Cerova, but especially to go to the Andrej&amp;rsquo;s brother wedding. The wedding took place in Castel Pension in Mierovo. Although I don&amp;rsquo;t know how the old manor house looked like before, I think its reconstruction was really successful. I was especially enchanted by a garden, which despite its relatively small dimension looked very spacious and thanks to various nooks with a touch of autumn very cozy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rozbehy and Korlátka</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/07/rozbehy-and-korlatka/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2010 13:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/07/rozbehy-and-korlatka/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend, on the occasion of the nice weather and a meeting with our parentsafter Christmas, we went on a small trip. It was pretty much only a nice walking within afternoon rest, but in the warm weather it was quite weary and I think more people from our group appreciated that the road back led through the forest. From Cerová we went on the winding road up the hill into a neighbouring village Rozbehy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potatoes and other</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/06/potatoes-and-other/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 16:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/06/potatoes-and-other/</guid>
      <description>Since we have lived in Munich, we eat more meat, wholemeal bread, vegetables and fruit. On Sunday, everything except a bakery and Biergarten is closed and so on the way from the church we always enjoy the fresh bread rolls and when the weather is nice we spend the afternoon somewhere out in the park. Given the prevalence of organic and bio products in the supermarkets, it happens quite often that these kinds of fruits or vegetables or eggs from free range hens wander to our basket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trip to Zaruby hill</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/07/06/trip-to-zaruby-hill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 13:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/07/06/trip-to-zaruby-hill/</guid>
      <description>As we have been together again for a little bit longer time than usual, we decided to go somewhere for a nice trip. This time we chose mountains Male Karpaty with the aim to go to the highest hill Zaruby (768 m). And to make this trip more interesting, we visited ruins of two castles on the road. On Saturday morning we travelled to Plavecke Podhradie, where our trip began and after 20 minutes of hiking we could observe ruins of the first castle Plavecky hrad.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>