<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Olivia on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/olivia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Olivia on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 22:10:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/olivia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kindergarden kids</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/10/26/kindergarden-kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 22:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/10/26/kindergarden-kids/</guid>
      <description>We have two kindergarden kids. Dominik joined Olivia in her lady bug group and he likes it very much. He enjoys music lessons and a big excavator in a sandbox. He already found a new friend, the same tractor enthusiast loving all the machines. Inspired by him, we sewed a tractor on Dominik&amp;rsquo;s gym bag and we bought slippers with the car pictures on them. The only thing Dominik resists is to sleep after the lunch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New in May</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/05/26/new-in-may/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 20:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/05/26/new-in-may/</guid>
      <description>Firstly, we celebrated a May festival in the nursery. Chidlren helped to prepare and paint a maypole and they learned a new song. Then, on the day of the celebration, the maypole was errected, the children garnished gingerbread hearts, made a picnic in the garden and played.
We made also a trip to the zoo in Munich. We only dressed lightly because of the warm weather and our memories of concrete surfaces without any shade in another zoo and we set off in the morning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative Easter</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/04/24/creative-easter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 20:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/04/24/creative-easter/</guid>
      <description>While we were waiting for the spring, we spent a lot of time doing creative activities. Children painted and couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait when the easter bunny finnaly comes. Once again, we visited an animal park in Poing. I think we will make this a tradition, because it&amp;rsquo;s really amazing to see all the baby animals there. Then we spent the holidays in the field (someone takes his kids to the football match, someone to the tractor).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olivia is 5 years old</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/03/10/olivia-is-five/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 14:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/03/10/olivia-is-five/</guid>
      <description>Olivia is 5 years old. She started celebrating with her grandparents in the morning and in the afternoon, she enjoyed the chocolate birthday cake with her friend. On the next day, she successfuly finished her swim course. I have already sewed a little sea horse on her swimsuit. On the last lesson, the children swam in their pyjamas to find out what it is like to swim in the clothes. Olivia did it perfectly well to my pleasure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olivia can swim</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/01/31/olivia-can-swim/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 14:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/01/31/olivia-can-swim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since October, Olivia goes swimming once a week. The goal is to get a see horse (that means, that she can swim 25 meters, she has the courage to jump into the water and she can dive and pull the ring out of the water). Last week, she managed to swim 25 metres. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full December</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/01/01/full-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 19:54:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/01/01/full-december/</guid>
      <description>In December, there was always a lot going on. I think that the first starting event was on Saint Martin&amp;rsquo;s day in November, when the gingerbread goats are used to be baked and the children are looking forward to lantern procession in the evening. Afterwards at home, we were still listening to the Saint Martin&amp;rsquo;s songs untill the new ones about Saint Nicholas came. In the meantime, the children began to open an Advent calendar and they also kept getting the small sweet surprises on all the courses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter for a few days</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/12/31/winter-for-a-few-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 23:21:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/12/31/winter-for-a-few-days/</guid>
      <description>This year, the winter has come only for a few days, but every moment we have made the most of it. Kids would love to shovel snow every morning and Dominik is excited about sledding (I think he does not remember it from the last year). And we built a lovely snowman.
            Your browser does not support the video tag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olivia takes pictures</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/12/30/olivia-takes-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 22:35:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/12/30/olivia-takes-pictures/</guid>
      <description>We gave Olivia a small camera in the summer so she could take photos during her holidays. Dominik was excited to take pictures as well. So far, the biggest problem is to be patient enough to take tack sharp images, but a few nice shots have been made.
             </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/08/15/summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 21:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/08/15/summer/</guid>
      <description>We asked Olivia what season we have right now and she as usual didn&amp;rsquo;t want to answer straight away, so we asked Dominik what he thought about it. He looked and said:&amp;ldquo;Summer&amp;rdquo;. Olivia was quite angry :) Olivia now enjoys when she can help me. She always says:&amp;ldquo;You know, I&amp;rsquo;ll help you Mom, so you have more time to play with us.&amp;rdquo; And she makes a breakfast or dinner table ready, she prepares all ingredients for cooking and she chops and mix them when needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two-week holiday</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/06/28/two-week-holiday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 20:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/06/28/two-week-holiday/</guid>
      <description>One week off in the kindergarden and then one more in the nursery and so we went for holidays to grandparents. The children played on all playgrounds, they ate peas, currants, cherries and strawberries all the time. Dominik used to &amp;ldquo;drive&amp;rdquo; the tractor in a barn every day. After two weeks, they asked when we would go home and when we were arriving to our home town, Dominik screamed in the car &amp;ldquo;hoooome&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last events</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/05/30/last-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 08:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/05/30/last-events/</guid>
      <description>Our Easter was one very enjoyable extended weekend full of trips. Only weather could have been warmer and less rainy. However, we visited the Wildpark in Poing and we palyed on the playgrounds. A week later, Olivia was still talking about Ivka and how she loves her and she asked when we would visit her again.
This year we joined a local tradition and were looking for Easter eggs. &amp;ldquo;Mami, the easter bunny was here&amp;rdquo; was the reaction when she found the cooked eggs in the flower pots and the garden hidden by the grandparents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In common and different</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/03/20/common-and-different/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 20:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/03/20/common-and-different/</guid>
      <description>They are really different, but one thing they have in common, each pursues their own interests and follows them. Olivia is like a manager and her assertiveness has no boundaries. When I want to pick her up from the kindergarten, she first goes to all teachers to say goodbye with a handshake (I do not know where does it come from). The best is when we are talking about how to do something, she listens to everything and then she says, &amp;ldquo;You know what we do it this way &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olivia is 4 years old</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/03/01/olivia-is-4-years-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 20:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/03/01/olivia-is-4-years-old/</guid>
      <description>Olivia talked about her birthday since summer. She couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait till she would put four candles on her birthday cake, light them and blow them out. We celebrated together, with her friends, with the grandparents and finally in the kindergarten with cakes. Luckily, everyone has birthday only once a year :). Olivia got Cubetto  (she calls him Kubo), a small robot to learn programming and improve spatial orientation in a funny way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When there is a lot of snow</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/02/01/when-there-is-alot-of-snow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 12:15:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/02/01/when-there-is-alot-of-snow/</guid>
      <description>We planned to go somewhere for the winter holidays, but it snowed so much that we changed our minds. We are every day in our garden playing with shovels or sledding on the nearby hill. And I started introducing Olivia to skiing. First, in the garden just to learn balance on her own and then on the nearby slopes, but they seemed to be too steep. Then my friend recommended me a small ski resort for children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gym</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/12/20/gym/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 20:32:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/12/20/gym/</guid>
      <description>I always try to take my children outside in any weather and every time I say we are going out they both rush to the door. But sometimes I just want to be at home, it&amp;rsquo;s raining, cold or dark early outside and then it is good to have a place where they can spend all their excess energy. So we made a gym in the basement. They can throw a ball there, slide, climb, boulder and chase each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birds and ladybugs</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/10/11/birds-and-ladybugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 20:32:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/10/11/birds-and-ladybugs/</guid>
      <description>A new school year started and Olivia finally became a kindergarten kid. Although she long longed for this moment, it took her a while to get used to a greater number of children and related noise, but now she is going to the kindergarten with enthusiasm, she brings home lots of drawings every day and she tells us what everything they did there. She also likes the music education they have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 years old</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/03/16/3-years-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 21:10:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/03/16/3-years-old/</guid>
      <description>Olivia is already a big girl and she&amp;rsquo;s going to school. In the morning, she&amp;rsquo;ll play there and she&amp;rsquo;ll learn to write, because she can already read and in the afternoon mommy picks her up. She keeps saying everyone that she is three years old and she shows on her fingers how much it is. We celebrated twice; once privately with a creamy berry cake and an easel and once with Olivia&amp;rsquo;s four friends (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two of them</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/10/09/two-of-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 11:58:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/10/09/two-of-them/</guid>
      <description>Time flies and you can&amp;rsquo;t do anything about it. Olivia has already learned it too. Only with Dominik, I feel like
it flies at least twice as fast. Our &amp;ldquo;little&amp;rdquo; one is 8.5 kilos and about 66 cm big and he looks like 6 months old children, he only doesn&amp;rsquo;t move so much. We started going to the gym with Olivia again. She enjoys a trampoline and climbing on a bench the most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>He grows and grows</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/07/20/he-grows-and-grows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 18:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/07/20/he-grows-and-grows/</guid>
      <description>Domink grew by 3.5 cm in the first two weeks and he already weighs over four kilos. He begins to smile and watch what is around him. In the morning, we manage to prepare everything and go to the nursery with Olivia quite well. We still need to fine-tune the evening so that Dominik would sleep and I could undisturbed put Olivia into her bed.
         </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We run</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/06/25/we-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 10:58:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/06/25/we-run/</guid>
      <description>Lately, the best game is to run, no matter whether we are inside or outside. We take a break only while waiting for a traffic light. Besides running we play soccer or dance. Olivia likes to ride her balance bike everywhere. She is fast and lift her feet off the ground so I run and run after her. The best afterwards is to sit on the couch at home waiting for her to explain me what everything she cooks for me and let her bring it to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter news</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/02/23/winter-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 09:52:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/02/23/winter-news/</guid>
      <description>The snow is slowly melting and we&amp;rsquo;re looking forward to the spring, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad that we had so much snow and that we could sleigh, trudge through deep snow and make shoe tracks in snow. We learned to make &amp;ldquo;whoopee&amp;rdquo; sound by tobogganing and we watched the skiers on the slope behind our town, so now Olivia knows at least what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about when we read about winter fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last two months</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/07/17/last-two-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2014 18:50:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/07/17/last-two-months/</guid>
      <description>We strengthen our immunity. I feel like one of us is always sick. Nevertheless, we enjoyed the hot summer days in the pool on the balcony, when it didn&amp;rsquo;t rain we were on the playground or otherwise we played at home. Olivia likes watering our plants on the balcony and she ate all our white currants (not to mention how much currants she ate at grandparents). Right now she is making another mental jump in her life and she learns to manage her emotions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There she grows again</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/05/17/there-she-grows-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2014 21:10:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/05/17/there-she-grows-again/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve already been working for two weeks and it&amp;rsquo;s quite a nice change. Time with my colleagues flies away so fast in the morning and in the afternoon I enjoy Olivia and I try to concentrate only on her. In the morning she runs to children in her class laughing. Currently, she takes great delight in building towers from Lego building blocks, she likes reading books and last time I found her with a TV control in her hand pretending to be on the phone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just some notes</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/04/12/just-some-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 21:34:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/04/12/just-some-notes/</guid>
      <description>This week we were at home just the two of us. Olivia is getting used to sleeping in the nursery and I have the whole morning just for myself after a long time. In the afternoon, we practically are still outside. We take a moment to shovel sand into the bucket and the remaining time we&amp;rsquo;re trying to climb on everything around. Olivia became a great helper at home. She likes to be involved in everything I do - washing the dishes, stirring while cooking, wiping her highchair after eating, hanging bib on a radiator, water the flowers, vacuuming, sweeping, unloading things from the dishwasher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nursery</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/03/20/nursery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 20:06:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/03/20/nursery/</guid>
      <description>I started going to the nursery with Olivia two weeks ago and I&amp;rsquo;m still excited about this place and the people working there. They follow Montessori principles, children are in the group regardless of age (so they are like siblings, the bigger ones have to be careful not to hurt the smaller ones who are watching them with an open mouth) and can move freely in the building visiting other children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s go</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/03/04/lets-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 20:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/03/04/lets-go/</guid>
      <description>Olivia decided to start walking. Although she already took her first steps some days ago, yesterday she stood up without our motivation and went. Today she went on practising and now she is able to walk longer distance. And in last weeks, she grew up so much that I had to sort through her clothes and she is now big enough for her little quad and so she rides it cheerfully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One year old</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/02/25/one-year-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 21:23:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/02/25/one-year-old/</guid>
      <description>One year ago our Olivia was born. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to believe that she was so small when I&amp;rsquo;m looking at her now. She already measures 75cm and weighs nearly 9.3kg. She always smiles and gives us hugs and kisses. Every morning, she gets up at six, we take her to our bed so I can breastfeed her, then she gives us a kiss, sits down, shows &amp;ldquo;done&amp;rdquo; with her hands and then points her finger at the door and says &amp;ldquo;ta&amp;rdquo; which means wake up, we&amp;rsquo;re going to play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parental leave</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/02/05/parental-leave/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 22:11:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/02/05/parental-leave/</guid>
      <description>Again, we enjoy a common month of parental leave. I must say that it&amp;rsquo;s great because we have just right amount of energy for our little rascal. Olivia climbed down the stairs for the first time. It took her quite a long time, but we duly praised her for that and she smiled like sunshine. She learned to slip the wooden rings on a stick and she likes to take toys out of the box and then again put them back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11 months</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/01/29/11-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 09:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/01/29/11-months/</guid>
      <description>Olivia has six teeth and she likes cleaning them whenever she sees her toothbrush. And apparently thanks to them she makes funny faces. She claps her hands when I say &amp;ldquo;clap clap&amp;rdquo; and she dances when she hears music (and she tries to dance even when standing alone). She likes throwing a ball and then catching it climbing over everything that comes in her way. She can say Mom and show Daddy whenever she hears him or is looking for him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toothy week</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/01/17/toothy-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 21:36:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/01/17/toothy-week/</guid>
      <description>Well, we really &amp;ldquo;enjoyed&amp;rdquo; last week. Olivia obviously found out that she needs other teeth after all and now it seems that they sprout out all at once. The top right one is already out. When I ask her to kiss me, she leans to me with an open mouth. She can put her hands behind her head and loves to play &amp;ldquo;baram baram buc&amp;rdquo;. When she finishes something or she doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to do it anymore she shows it&amp;rsquo;s done with her hands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sitting</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/01/04/sitting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 22:18:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2014/01/04/sitting/</guid>
      <description>Olivia finally sits while she is playing and it&amp;rsquo;s really nice to watch her. She can get angry when things go wrong and she turns her nose up at anything she doesn&amp;rsquo;t want. At her grandparents&amp;rsquo; house she learned to crawl up the stairs. She also went four steps down upside down and then back up snarling that it didn&amp;rsquo;t go quite well. At home she already tried it sideways, so I think it&amp;rsquo;s getting better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first Christmas</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/12/30/the-first-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 10:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/12/30/the-first-christmas/</guid>
      <description>I think Olivia doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand unwrapping Christmas gifts yet, but she likes their content very much. To my great joy she started to use sign language eg. the light is turned on, she finished eating and she is going to wash her hands, hand waving bye bye, how tall she will be and her grandma taught her to rotate her hand when she asked how she is. Successfully, she goes on a potty several times a day and enthusiastically watches flushing a toilet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Box</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/12/12/box/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 22:03:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/12/12/box/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m able to get our baby dressed only while she&amp;rsquo;s standing. I can force her to lie on her back only a very short time while I&amp;rsquo;m changing her nappy. Once she has a new one , she rolls over on her tummy, grabs the nearest toy and at the first opportunity she stands up. But she already gives us little hugs and kisses, so I cannot really blame her for anything :).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 months</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/11/25/9-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2013 12:05:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/11/25/9-months/</guid>
      <description>Olivia is fascinated by everything that causes some action i.e. switches, buttons causing the sound, she is very interested in the traffic lights and she looks curiously in the elevator. And when she is excited about something she squeals loudly (e.g. when she listens to her favorite music, when we go outside and then back home). Everything that moves is interesting as well like cars and bicycles. Recently, a painter was at our home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kids room</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/11/11/kids-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 20:50:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/11/11/kids-room/</guid>
      <description>I recently painted a tree on the wall in Olivia&amp;rsquo;s bedroom to make it cosier. I painted with watercolors so I could wash it in the worst case. But it turned out pretty well so I maybe paint there some animals later on. We already thought about moving Olivia to her own room when she stopped sleeping in the bedside crib, but there were two things that discouraged me to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 moths</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/10/26/8-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2013 18:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/10/26/8-months/</guid>
      <description>Among her friends, who she plays with, she is the only one who can stay, has a lot of hair and no teeth. She is going through another growth spurt and so it&amp;rsquo;s a little bit more difficult to put her in sleep. Most recently, we play hide and seek games and she laughs a lot and we all crawl throughout our home. Today, she was finally brave enough to crawl under the table and chair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discoverer</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/10/20/discovever/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 14:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/10/20/discovever/</guid>
      <description>Olivia is not standing on her tiptoes anymore but the whole feet and she starts cruising. She just lacks some kind of a survival instinct, because sometimes while standing she stops holding the object with her hands and then she looks surprised when falling down onto her back. Once she stands up, she doesn&amp;rsquo;t really want to sit down. She only kneels or sits down when she is pretty tired and she cannot stand any longer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On her feet</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/10/13/on-her-feet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 12:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/10/13/on-her-feet/</guid>
      <description>Firstly, it seemed like she would be slithering on her belly. But it somehow didn&amp;rsquo;t impress her and she began to crawl. And after a week, when I thought she would crawl faster and I&amp;rsquo;d chase her around the house, she began to stand up (she is a bit in a hurry, isn&amp;rsquo;t she?). When she is very interested in something she can get to it very quickly, but she has more fun with searching for things that help her to stand up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 months</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/09/25/7-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 19:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/09/25/7-months/</guid>
      <description>Holidays finished and all our activities started again. Today we learned to jump/fall into the water and to swim with a swimming board. Olivia crawls nicely and moves quickly where she wants, especially when she is interested in something (like the laundry basket or slippers). We also started course for children. For the first hour, we took daddy with us to conclude his parental leave. In July, Olivia was one of the last ones, who began to rolled over and now she was the only one (except the one month older baby boy) on her knees and she crawled among the other children and put everything what she found into her mouth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some photos</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/09/18/some-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 21:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/09/18/some-photos/</guid>
      <description>Last two weeks, we were really active and we took advantage of the last summer days. Beside swimming and crawling in the grass on the hill behind our house, we went to see animals in the forest. Olivia looked at a family of a wild boar and deer and then she looked up and watched trees.       And then we traveled toward grandparents. Olivia gained allattention and she started eating incredibly lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Half a year old</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/09/04/half-a-year-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 09:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/09/04/half-a-year-old/</guid>
      <description>Olivia managed another growth spurt (together with us). From what I read, we bore this quite well. She didn&amp;rsquo;t lose her appetite, quite the opposite. She didn&amp;rsquo;t cry too much, just started to realise the distances and occasionally gurgled, when she saw me going away from the room. But she slept less. In the evening, she always woke up after one hour of sleeping full of energy and ready to play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/08/10/active/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 13:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/08/10/active/</guid>
      <description>Our little baby already weights 7kg. She smiles a lot and watches all carefully. When she hears me but doesn&amp;rsquo;t see me, she raises her head high and looks at where I am. Then when I suddenly peek out from behind the door she smiles from ear to ear. We taught her to blow, so now we can hear ppfff and fffuuu from the crib and when I look at her she is smiling at me with a questioning look in her eyes and four fingers in the mouth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baptism</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/07/28/baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2013 14:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/07/28/baptism/</guid>
      <description>Last week, we travelled with Olivia abroad for the first time. She was doing very well. She slept, played a bit, we had a little break on a blanket under the trees as well, just at the end she had enough, but so did all of us. We all dreamed about a cold shower. I was only worried whether this trip does not disturb her sleeping, but she slept even better than at home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rolling</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/07/15/rolling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 10:53:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/07/15/rolling/</guid>
      <description>Olivia began to roll on her belly a week ago. After an intensive weekend training with her grandfather and grandmother, she didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything else just tried to roll over and she was angry when it didn&amp;rsquo;t work. The next day she was rolling over and over on both sides. Rolling back to her back is more difficult, we train it but she rather falls than consciously rolls back. Basically it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter, Olivia likes to be on her belly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Name day</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/06/27/name-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 11:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/06/27/name-day/</guid>
      <description>We celebrated the Olivia&amp;rsquo;s firstname day. On her behalf, thank you for all the congratulations. She spent the morning playing with her peers (they talked with their own language, they pulled and sucked together one long chain and some of them already were able to roll and the other watched them with interest :)) In the afternoon, she played at home. Andrej brought her wooden baby gym and she was really happy about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twice as big</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/06/19/twice-as-big/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 19:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/06/19/twice-as-big/</guid>
      <description>Our little one already weights 6110 grams and so she more than doubled her weight, which she had at birth. She began to play with her feet and clap them. Previously, she already managed to turn on her side, but that was more or less by accident. Now, she is trying it consciously and when she fails, she is angry with herself. The result of her effort is that she rotates around her own head in a circle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warm</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/06/08/warm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 21:49:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/06/08/warm/</guid>
      <description>We complained that it&amp;rsquo;s raining and cold and so on Wednesday it was suddenly about 15 degrees warmer and the sun is burning and we can only go out in the evening. But the great is that we don&amp;rsquo;t have to dress Olivia so much, she just needs to get used to the higher temperature. So far she only drinks a lot and is tired of it. Since Monday, she has been having fun lying on her belly again and so we encourage her to rotate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 months</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/05/26/3-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 18:32:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/05/26/3-months/</guid>
      <description>She grows really fast. Sometimes I look at her in the morning and I feel like she grew overnight at least few inches up. And when cutting nails, I feel that while I&amp;rsquo;m cutting them on the other hand, they grow long on the first one again. She weighs just over 5.6kg and she recently puts her both hands in front of her together putting them all into her mouth. She started to drool pretty much, so I wonder, when she begins to lick everything around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/05/16/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 20:57:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/05/16/news/</guid>
      <description>Olivia has over 5kg and my back is looking forward to doing excercises starting next week. She enjoys bathing and she recentlystarted screaming when we&amp;rsquo;re taking her out from the bathwater. Now I&amp;rsquo;m only waiting for that she holds her head properly and we go to the pool. I&amp;rsquo;m very happy that she has a relationship with Andrej equivalent to me (probably up to that hungry expression on her face) and whenever she sees him she smiles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 months</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/04/23/2-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 21:29:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/04/23/2-months/</guid>
      <description>Our little Olivia is two months old. Actually, she is not very small anymore, she grew about ten centimeters up and weighs about 4.8kg. She smiles a lot, but she can curle her mouth as well when she doesn&amp;rsquo;t like something and she generally makes targeted grimaces trying to imitate us. She likes looking into the mirror and the windows, I think it&amp;rsquo;s because of the light. She got used to regular walks in a stroller and when the sunlight is disturbing her by sleeping she is able to stretch her cap under her nose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweater</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/04/21/sweater/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 11:15:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/04/21/sweater/</guid>
      <description>Well, beside the all my current activities I managed to knit againand Olivia got a new sweater with a hat. For such a small person it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take long to finish it and the outcome pleases meevery time(especially when other moms like Olivia and I can change ideas and patterns for new things with them :) ).
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Month</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/31/month/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 18:02:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/31/month/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been over a month since Olivia lives with us. I must say that she changes herself in front of our eyes daily and she grows quickly. Some of her clothes are already small and we started using a new size of diapers as well. She learned to cry and express dissatisfaction and has an incredible appetite. She smiles often looking at us with her big eyes, she makes a variety of sounds with opened mouth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pregnancy</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/18/pregnancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 20:05:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/18/pregnancy/</guid>
      <description>A little retrospective writing, but I felt I need to write about it. I thought that pregnancy and stress are mutually exclusive, but I think they attract each other. Fear is different, it seems natural to me. Whenever I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel well, the first thing that occured to me was whether the little baby in my tummy is well. But by stress I rather mean the feeling that I always had when I had to decide for something or to solve something from medical point of view and there were many of those moments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bathing</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/14/bathing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 10:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/14/bathing/</guid>
      <description>So we bathed our little baby for the first time. After a week, her umbilical cord fell away and we took her to the first walk in a stroller. We also somehow managed changing her diapers (an electric heater above the changing table is absolutely fantastic thing) and we only had to handle bathing in water. I expected many reactions, but not that she will be so satisfied. Our midwife came to help us and teach us once again some of those useful tricks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cradle</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/12/cradle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 17:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/12/cradle/</guid>
      <description>We had our first visit since there have been three of us and we got a wooden cradle. It found its place in the living room next to our couch. Our midwife was fascinated with it too when she saw it. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how long it will serve us (when our dear child beggins to jump out from it), but now it&amp;rsquo;s great for napping throughout the day. Grandparents visited us for really very short time, but Olivia looked happy in the grandma&amp;rsquo;s hands and we felt very comfortable that we didn&amp;rsquo;t have to think about how is Olivia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belly</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/05/belly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 17:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/05/belly/</guid>
      <description>I wrote the below article last week, thinking that I have enough time to do some more photos of my growing belly. But somehow I didn&amp;rsquo;t manage it and our little princess is already in the world :)
Well, we grow slowly. According to recent estimates, our baby has around 2.8 to 3 kg and falls well within the average size range, which makes me extremely happy. It&amp;rsquo;s only a shame that she doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to turn as other average children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olivia</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/02/olivia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 14:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2013/03/02/olivia/</guid>
      <description>A little bit earlier but healthy and satisfied :) I would like to introduce you our sweet little daughter Olivia.
    Birthday: 25.2.2013 18:15
Weight: 3020 g
Length: 47 cm
       </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>