<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Munich on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/munich/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Munich on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 18:54:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/munich/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Wiesn</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/10/26/wiesn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 18:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/10/26/wiesn/</guid>
      <description>Another Oktoberfest (or Wiesn as local people would say) behind us, and this year we didn&amp;rsquo;t miss it. Well, we didn&amp;rsquo;t join the official event in traditional clothes inside one of the huge tents, but we dived in the great atmosphere and we drank one litter of beer. We didn&amp;rsquo;t see the initial ceremony this year, because we weren&amp;rsquo;t in the mood to go to the town in a rainy weather, but we did spent some hours together with our colleagues drinking beer at Oktoberfest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olympiaberg</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/10/olympiaberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 13:11:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/10/olympiaberg/</guid>
      <description>We were already several times in the Olympia park, but we somehow never got to the highest hill there. To walk on its top is not really difficult, but either the weather didn&amp;rsquo;t work out for us, or we were already tired from walking through the town so we ended up just resting near the lake below. There is a nice paved walkway leading up to the top of the hill that is great view point as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the city centre</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/09/in-the-city-centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 13:57:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/09/in-the-city-centre/</guid>
      <description>Once again, we went to the town centre to show our weekend visitors (Andrej&amp;rsquo;s parents) how it looks like here and where we actually live. We travelled by all sorts of trains (S-Bahn and U-Bahn and tram), we walked through the shopping street and stores and we looked at the ringing tower of the new town hall at eleven. We overcame the altitude difference from a minus fourth floor of the underground to around 290m high tower in Olympia Park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking in the park</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/07/walking-in-the-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 13:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/07/walking-in-the-park/</guid>
      <description>Walking in the park in winter, especially when there is snow everywhere, is absolutely fantastic. Although only until the sunset, because then it starts freezing properly and it is better to hide even in the subway. As I haven&amp;rsquo;t been in Englischer Garten at the time of snow, we went there during the last weekend. Originally, we wanted to go sledging on the nearby hill, but the season was just opened and so we concluded that there would be too many people anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas markets</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/07/christmas-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 12:20:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/12/07/christmas-markets/</guid>
      <description>During the weekend, we went to the Christmas markets. There are quite a lot of them in Munich. Basically, each Munich neighborhood has its own market. We went directly to the Marienplatz in the centre. There were many stands decorated with green boughs and colorful lights. They offered many things, among others, wooden ornaments and toys, candles and Christmas hats. I was really impressed by one stand that offered all sorts of wooden things ( cutting boards, spatula, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oktoberfest</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/10/06/oktoberfest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 14:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/10/06/oktoberfest/</guid>
      <description>anniversary of the Oktoberfest is over and people in traditional costumes are slowly but surely disappearing from the streets and the subway, so people like us dressed only in jeans and T-shirt don&amp;rsquo;t look like tourists anymore.  Although we haven&amp;rsquo;t been in the beer tent on the Theresienwiese, we didn&amp;rsquo;t miss parade at the launch of this year&amp;rsquo;s festivities. There were horse drawn carts with barrels of beer and venison, but also agricultural machinery and many brass bands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake in the Olympia park</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/07/05/lake-in-the-olympia-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2010 19:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/07/05/lake-in-the-olympia-park/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve already written about the Olympia park, but that was in November last year and at that time there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any lake but the muddy place and some people who cleaned it. Fortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s the great place for visitors due to the high tower in the centre so we had a great opportunity to go there with our friends and see the actual lake :) There were many people running around or cycling, lot of stands with ice-cream or some sweet cakes and of course many people sitting in the bier garden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bavaria</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/07/05/bavaria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2010 13:17:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/07/05/bavaria/</guid>
      <description>This was one of my less fortunate trip ideas, but on the other hand I don&amp;rsquo;t regret at all that I was there. The question Where? is now on the right place &amp;hellip; in the statue called Bavaria. Recently, we had a second visit here and after a day spent walking in the center and parks, we were thinking, where to go next. I read that there is a statue that was created and built as a symbol of Bavaria, it is 18 m high and it is possible to go in, upstairs and look around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surfers</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/04/29/surfers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 08:04:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/04/29/surfers/</guid>
      <description>We had our first visitors here last weekend. Our friends came to see us and of course all the beauties of Munich. On Sunday we went for walk to Englischer Garten. The weather was excellent, sunny and very warm. We choose a different path as the first time to better know the park for future visitors and we came to the stream Eisbach (ice stream). Well, we&amp;rsquo;ve read about one place in the park, where people use to surf, but we&amp;rsquo;ve never seen this place before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/12/12/winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2009 20:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/12/12/winter/</guid>
      <description>My lovely husband sent me again several pictures from our flat surrounding and honestly, I was a little bit jealous. I wish I were there and could build a snowman :)That narrow path is going toward S-Bahn.
           </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>English garden</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/25/english-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 21:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/25/english-garden/</guid>
      <description>To be honest, I have no idea why this park is called Englischer Garten (English garden). Maybe because it is well-adjusted with properly cut lawn and pretty paths. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest public parks and it&amp;rsquo;s also obviously very popular for relax and walking, doing some sports or just for sitting and reading a book. This park actually reminded me the Central Park in Manhattan, but this one is even larger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where to go with visitors</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/25/where-to-go-with-visitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 15:42:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/25/where-to-go-with-visitors/</guid>
      <description>We were thinking about where to go in Munich. We had a nice weather and 3-days ticket for travelling, so I took the map and was looking for some interesting places in the wider centre of the Munich. Since I wanted to take some impresive pictures, we went to the Nymphenburg castle.
Well the castle is really impresive, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure about the pictures. As it is the beginning of the winter, all the statues were covered by the wooden boxes, fountains were not working and in general it was obviously a good time to repair everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Munich</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/24/munich/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 21:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/11/24/munich/</guid>
      <description>I have never been to Munich before and I feel those few days I spent there weren&amp;rsquo;t enough. I love the historical flair of this city. There are no high modern glass buildings preventing the sun shine to the street, but low stylish buildings with sloping red roofs. There are loads of bakery and little kiosks with pretzels everywhere. Since I love to ramble marketplace, what I have probably inherited from my daddy, I was unbelievable happy to see one directly in the city centre called Viktualienmarkt.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>