<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beach on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/beach/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Beach on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 10:48:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/beach/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cala Ratjada</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/07/01/cala-ratjada/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 10:48:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/07/01/cala-ratjada/</guid>
      <description>This year, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t decide where to go on holiday. My usual desire for trips became unbalanced due to the work fatigue and it was replaced by a new desire (very unusual for me) to go to sea on a beautiful sandy beach and at most to make a trip to some of the local restaurants for culinary specialties. Andrej couldn&amp;rsquo;t believe his ears (after all those years with me, he has experienced many things but he only dreamed quietly about such a vacation with me when we became a couple) and a sudden panic seized him, what we&amp;rsquo;re actually going to do there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poseidon gardens</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/23/poseidon-gardens/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 11:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/23/poseidon-gardens/</guid>
      <description>We went out on a day trip to Poseidon gardens in the middle of the week. We were little bit afraid of the hot termal water in the swimming pools in such a warm weather and we had also sunburn more than it&amp;rsquo;s appropriate in the hot water :) We had concern about the weather when we saw first time the only hill on the island covered with the grey clouds in the morning, but after breakfast, swimming in the pool and reading on the sun beds we set off for the trip towards the Citara beach and Poseidon gardens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forio</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/06/30/forio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2008 17:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/06/30/forio/</guid>
      <description>This is the town were we lived in a wonderful hotel Corona, which we can only recommend. It is said to be the most visited place by tourists on the island. It has several beaches (we saw and tried all of them), nice centre, several churches and countless streets, which are worth walking. This town is also famous by wine production and amazing thermal park Poseidon gardens.The most famous church is Soccorso&amp;rsquo;s church devoted to Santa Naria delle Neve, which can be seen in the movie Avanti!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>