<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dominik on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/dominik/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dominik on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>ajka-andrej.com powered by [Hugo](//gohugo.io). Theme inspired by [PPOffice](http://github.com/ppoffice).</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 14:06:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/dominik/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dominik is two and half</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/01/14/dominik-is-two-and-half/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 14:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/01/14/dominik-is-two-and-half/</guid>
      <description>Dominik like singing. In the car, I always turn on a song he wishes and then he sings all the way home. Currently, he prefers to eat pasta in any form and corn. It&amp;rsquo;s similar to the time when he wanted to eat only bread or yogurt whole the week. Now he takes pasta from the fridge even for breakfast.
Unlike Olivia, he first does something and then he thinks about the consequences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full December</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/01/01/full-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 19:54:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/01/01/full-december/</guid>
      <description>In December, there was always a lot going on. I think that the first starting event was on Saint Martin&amp;rsquo;s day in November, when the gingerbread goats are used to be baked and the children are looking forward to lantern procession in the evening. Afterwards at home, we were still listening to the Saint Martin&amp;rsquo;s songs untill the new ones about Saint Nicholas came. In the meantime, the children began to open an Advent calendar and they also kept getting the small sweet surprises on all the courses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter for a few days</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/12/31/winter-for-a-few-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 23:21:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/12/31/winter-for-a-few-days/</guid>
      <description>This year, the winter has come only for a few days, but every moment we have made the most of it. Kids would love to shovel snow every morning and Dominik is excited about sledding (I think he does not remember it from the last year). And we built a lovely snowman.
            Your browser does not support the video tag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olivia takes pictures</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/12/30/olivia-takes-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 22:35:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/12/30/olivia-takes-pictures/</guid>
      <description>We gave Olivia a small camera in the summer so she could take photos during her holidays. Dominik was excited to take pictures as well. So far, the biggest problem is to be patient enough to take tack sharp images, but a few nice shots have been made.
             </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/08/15/summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 21:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/08/15/summer/</guid>
      <description>We asked Olivia what season we have right now and she as usual didn&amp;rsquo;t want to answer straight away, so we asked Dominik what he thought about it. He looked and said:&amp;ldquo;Summer&amp;rdquo;. Olivia was quite angry :) Olivia now enjoys when she can help me. She always says:&amp;ldquo;You know, I&amp;rsquo;ll help you Mom, so you have more time to play with us.&amp;rdquo; And she makes a breakfast or dinner table ready, she prepares all ingredients for cooking and she chops and mix them when needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dominik is two</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/07/02/dominik-is-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 20:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/07/02/dominik-is-two/</guid>
      <description>So Dominik is two years old. He still loves tractors, trains and excavators. He likes when he has time to do his own things and no one disturbs him but he also started to play with Olivia and he follows her in everything what she does. Dominik learned to jump into the swimming pool, he is talking more and more.
         </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two-week holiday</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/06/28/two-week-holiday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 20:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/06/28/two-week-holiday/</guid>
      <description>One week off in the kindergarden and then one more in the nursery and so we went for holidays to grandparents. The children played on all playgrounds, they ate peas, currants, cherries and strawberries all the time. Dominik used to &amp;ldquo;drive&amp;rdquo; the tractor in a barn every day. After two weeks, they asked when we would go home and when we were arriving to our home town, Dominik screamed in the car &amp;ldquo;hoooome&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last events</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/05/30/last-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 08:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/05/30/last-events/</guid>
      <description>Our Easter was one very enjoyable extended weekend full of trips. Only weather could have been warmer and less rainy. However, we visited the Wildpark in Poing and we palyed on the playgrounds. A week later, Olivia was still talking about Ivka and how she loves her and she asked when we would visit her again.
This year we joined a local tradition and were looking for Easter eggs. &amp;ldquo;Mami, the easter bunny was here&amp;rdquo; was the reaction when she found the cooked eggs in the flower pots and the garden hidden by the grandparents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In common and different</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/03/20/common-and-different/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 20:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/03/20/common-and-different/</guid>
      <description>They are really different, but one thing they have in common, each pursues their own interests and follows them. Olivia is like a manager and her assertiveness has no boundaries. When I want to pick her up from the kindergarten, she first goes to all teachers to say goodbye with a handshake (I do not know where does it come from). The best is when we are talking about how to do something, she listens to everything and then she says, &amp;ldquo;You know what we do it this way &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When there is a lot of snow</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/02/01/when-there-is-alot-of-snow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 12:15:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/02/01/when-there-is-alot-of-snow/</guid>
      <description>We planned to go somewhere for the winter holidays, but it snowed so much that we changed our minds. We are every day in our garden playing with shovels or sledding on the nearby hill. And I started introducing Olivia to skiing. First, in the garden just to learn balance on her own and then on the nearby slopes, but they seemed to be too steep. Then my friend recommended me a small ski resort for children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gym</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/12/20/gym/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 20:32:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/12/20/gym/</guid>
      <description>I always try to take my children outside in any weather and every time I say we are going out they both rush to the door. But sometimes I just want to be at home, it&amp;rsquo;s raining, cold or dark early outside and then it is good to have a place where they can spend all their excess energy. So we made a gym in the basement. They can throw a ball there, slide, climb, boulder and chase each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birds and ladybugs</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/10/11/birds-and-ladybugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 20:32:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/10/11/birds-and-ladybugs/</guid>
      <description>A new school year started and Olivia finally became a kindergarten kid. Although she long longed for this moment, it took her a while to get used to a greater number of children and related noise, but now she is going to the kindergarten with enthusiasm, she brings home lots of drawings every day and she tells us what everything they did there. She also likes the music education they have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two of them</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/10/09/two-of-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 11:58:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/10/09/two-of-them/</guid>
      <description>Time flies and you can&amp;rsquo;t do anything about it. Olivia has already learned it too. Only with Dominik, I feel like
it flies at least twice as fast. Our &amp;ldquo;little&amp;rdquo; one is 8.5 kilos and about 66 cm big and he looks like 6 months old children, he only doesn&amp;rsquo;t move so much. We started going to the gym with Olivia again. She enjoys a trampoline and climbing on a bench the most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>He grows and grows</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/07/20/he-grows-and-grows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 18:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2015/07/20/he-grows-and-grows/</guid>
      <description>Domink grew by 3.5 cm in the first two weeks and he already weighs over four kilos. He begins to smile and watch what is around him. In the morning, we manage to prepare everything and go to the nursery with Olivia quite well. We still need to fine-tune the evening so that Dominik would sleep and I could undisturbed put Olivia into her bed.
         </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>