<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Skiing on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/skiing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Skiing on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2012 16:15:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/skiing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sudelfeld</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/03/11/sudelfeld/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2012 16:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/03/11/sudelfeld/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, we went skiing again. This time we chose Sudelfeld ski resort. Our colleague told us that it is a little bit small and local, but less people know about it and therefore it usually is not so crowded on Saturday. The weather was absolutely fantastic, there were really not so many people and we were quite surprised when we found that it is not as small as we heard. In addition, it is a great place for skiing with children with lots of children&amp;rsquo;s short and mild slopes and help with all lifts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spitzingsee</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/02/01/spitzingsee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 21:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/02/01/spitzingsee/</guid>
      <description>Today, we went skiing to the lake Spitzingsee. The temperature dropped to -10 and predicted sunshine showed up just before lunch, but skiing was great. Good maintained slopes and only few people caused that we already had enough around the lunch and we returned back home quite tired. I didn&amp;rsquo;t took a lot of pictures, only one panorama after which I seriously had to warm up my hands. But I hope to fix that this summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skiwelt Wilder Kaiser</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/01/26/skiwelt-wilder-kaiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 22:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/01/26/skiwelt-wilder-kaiser/</guid>
      <description>We spent last two Wednesdays skiing in neighbouring Tyrol in the ski resort Wilder Kaiser. Every time we parked in another town, we went to the highest possible place by a cable car and then we skied cross over the hills everywhere where we could get by the ski lifts. The weather was absolutely fantastic and I took some pictures as well.
                    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garmisch-Classic</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/31/garmisch-classic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 20:51:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/31/garmisch-classic/</guid>
      <description>This is another option (not counting the Tyrolean Alps around the corner) to go skiing when you are in Grainau. And not only that. Cable cars operate here also in the summer and there is a wide variety of hiking trails offered by the hills.
    One of the black slopes was closed due to the preparation for the World Championships (5a on the slope plan), but we didn&amp;rsquo;t miss it at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zugspitzplatt</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/31/zugspitzplatt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 07:53:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/31/zugspitzplatt/</guid>
      <description>I must say that this place is simply wonderful. We haven&amp;rsquo;t been to Zugspitze (the highest peak in Germany, 2962m), because we somehow couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop skiing in such a beautiful weather. But we agreed that we would make this trip in the summer.
 I&amp;rsquo;ve never really thought about the name of the peak until now, when I found out that you can go just below it by train (der Zug).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holiday in Grainau</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/30/holiday-in-grainau/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2011 17:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/30/holiday-in-grainau/</guid>
      <description>This time we traveled only about an hour and a quarter by car from our home to the village Grainau. We wanted to ski and get to know our surroundings better. We stayed in a very nice and cozy house with a great breakfast (Gasthaus Geigener). The weather was quite good, we skied whole the week except the two days and my darling named our vacation week assembly.
     One snowy day, we made a train trip to the nearby Tyrol village Lermoos and then we went back to Garmisch Partenkirchen, where we found a great Italian restaurant for lunch and we saw the ski springboard and slopes for the upcoming World Championships.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skiing in Laax</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/10/skiing-in-laax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2011 08:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/01/10/skiing-in-laax/</guid>
      <description>This year I made several New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions (I will sometimes write about them). One of them is to ski this winter properly. Before Christmas, we decided to visit our friends in Switzerland and we were going to look at several ski resorts near Zurich. But this plan failed, because during our planned weekend heat wave arrived from Spain and at 1100 m it was suddenly 7 degrees. Finally, we opted for the more distant, but higher placed resort Laax, where we were skiing at around 2500 m at a pleasant temperature just below zero.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>