<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portugal on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/portugal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portugal on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>ajka-andrej.com powered by [Hugo](//gohugo.io). Theme inspired by [PPOffice](http://github.com/ppoffice).</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 09:12:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/portugal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Porto</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/04/13/porto/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 09:12:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/04/13/porto/</guid>
      <description>I would like to share my impressions from another country with you. I visited Portugal two weeks ago. I already knew that it is the lovely country as we went toMadeira for our honeymoon, but I found out that there is still so much to explore. My Portuguese friend also recommended me to go to south west coast for beautiful sceneries and relax, to relish sun and Atlantic ocean. So I consider it as a very nice inspiration for a future holiday This time I traveled to Braga for a Serious games conference and I spent several hours in Porto.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hotel Orca Praia</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/09/05/hotel-orca-praia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 23:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/09/05/hotel-orca-praia/</guid>
      <description>After one week of living in this hotel we can recommend it :). It&amp;rsquo;s built in the rock so every room is turned towards the ocean. The funny thing was that they counted floors from zero to minus ten. Good advice is to not live lower than minus eight floor because these rooms are without the balcony and you can see trees right in front of your windows instead of the ocean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Funchal</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/09/05/funchal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 23:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/09/05/funchal/</guid>
      <description>Funchal is the biggest town of Madeira and its centre was about six kilometers from our hotel which was walkable distance. There are many restaurants, shopping areas, museums and parks where you can spend lovely time. The only thing is that this town is a little bit noisy now, because they are building many hotels and block of flats everywhere. That was one of the reasons why to stay in a hotel in a quiet and peacefull place away from the town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>East Madeira</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/09/05/east-madeira/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 20:52:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/09/05/east-madeira/</guid>
      <description>One way how to get known some part of this beautiful island is to go for a bus trip and travel across the mountains and along the coast. We saw so many beautiful things, untouched nature, traditional houses, completely different land in the north part and in the south. Once you go up through the layer of clouds after the forest, mountains appear before your eyes and you feel like in a paradise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honeymoon</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/20/honeymoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2008 19:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/20/honeymoon/</guid>
      <description>We finally found the right place for our honeymoon. It is a wonderful tiny island in Atlantic Ocean, which belongs to Portugal. The island of Madeira is lapped by the waters of the Gulf Stream, so there is nice warm weather. There are beautiful botanic gardens, mountains and views of the ocean and many nice people with their own traditions. We spent there wonderful time and took a huge amount of pictures as well:) You can read more here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>