<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hiking on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/hiking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hiking on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 20:49:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/hiking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Trips around Terchova</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/08/24/trips-around-terchova/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 20:49:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2018/08/24/trips-around-terchova/</guid>
      <description>After two years, we travelled to Terchova again. We went to the town lookout Terchova heart (we learned it&amp;rsquo;s name later from a guide of the Terchova train) and it gives a wonderful view of the town and the surrounding hills.
 We made again a trip to Vychylovka, Dominik still enjoyed the historical train and the local sheep. Then we rode a cable car from Vratna uphill and hiked over the Chleb hill, Steny (Walls) and Poludňový grúň to the cottage on Grúň.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vrátna valley</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/09/01/vratna-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 20:59:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2016/09/01/vratna-valley/</guid>
      <description>We wanted to eat some proper slovak food specialties like halušky, pirohy and šúľance, relax and relish the nature and so we made a culinary trip to Štefanova in Vrátna valley. We made a trip to a cottage on Grúň and under Chleb and on every trip we found a playground or sheep, so our children were more than satisfied.
                </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November Wallberg</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/11/17/november-wallberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2012 07:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/11/17/november-wallberg/</guid>
      <description>There are already many articles about this hill on our web page and I need to say that it&amp;rsquo;s one of our favourite hill. But two weeks ago, we had such a nice visit, to my great pleasure longing for trips led by a almost three years old young tourist. And so we went on trips to many places and one of them was Wallberg. It&amp;rsquo;s clear to me that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to convince Andrej to go there otherwise (certainly not in November and not at all in that snow except the sledding).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kampenwand</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/10/28/kampenwand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 19:02:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2012/10/28/kampenwand/</guid>
      <description>This was the only trip (not counting the local trips in the forest and cycling), which we managed to do during the summer. I planned more of them, but thanks to my incredible fatigue, I was glad that we were able to get at least here. Kampenwand itself is a rocky hill with a cross at the very top (the largest one in the Bavarian Alps), but the name is used to identify all the surrounding tourist area with lots of hiking routes, cottages and chapels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wendelstein</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/09/02/wendelstein/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 22:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/09/02/wendelstein/</guid>
      <description>Finally, we went on a tour we had already planned for early summer. Somehow, it always rained or we were not at home and so I could only study our route theoretically. But last week we had an ideal weather and so we set off on the trip in the morning. We parked next to the cable-car station just outside the village Osterhofen and then we hiked three hours and three quarters up the hill Wendelstein 1838 m (at least we thought so according to a tourist guide, in fact, we went up two and half hours).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nature trip</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/10/nature-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 22:19:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/05/10/nature-trip/</guid>
      <description>Since urban tourism is quite difficult, and as we don&amp;rsquo;t want to destroy our visitors (we would like them to come again), we have always at hand some trip to nature. Neither last Saturday it was different and we went to our quite favourite place, on the hill Wallberg. Up and down we drove a cable-car, but then we hiked to the top of the peak (about half an hour). The chapel, which was reconstructed is already nice and finished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easter trip</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/04/27/easter-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 21:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2011/04/27/easter-trip/</guid>
      <description>Last Friday we went to Easter trip. We had a beautiful warm weather, around 25 degrees and I saw a newspaper tip for a nice trip to a waterfall. I thought that in this lovely April weather everything is melting and so there could be a lot of water. After a small survey, I found two other even bigger waterfalls near the original one. From parking places it was up to 20 minutes walk to each one and so we decided to see all of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wallberg</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/24/wallberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2010 13:22:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/24/wallberg/</guid>
      <description>This time we went a little higher on the hill Wallberg (1722m) and so we increased the elevation to 927m. To get there, we travelled around the Tegernsee lake, which looked beautiful from above. We parked next to the cable-car station and began hiking. You can find more pictures in the gallery.
 Right at the beginning of our journey, we found out that the first cottage, where we wanted to go, was closed (on the winter version of the route) and so we decided that we would take it up with a bit steeper but shorter summer route.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trip to Zaruby hill</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/07/06/trip-to-zaruby-hill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 13:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2009/07/06/trip-to-zaruby-hill/</guid>
      <description>As we have been together again for a little bit longer time than usual, we decided to go somewhere for a nice trip. This time we chose mountains Male Karpaty with the aim to go to the highest hill Zaruby (768 m). And to make this trip more interesting, we visited ruins of two castles on the road. On Saturday morning we travelled to Plavecke Podhradie, where our trip began and after 20 minutes of hiking we could observe ruins of the first castle Plavecky hrad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trips through the Ischia</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/23/trips-through-the-ischia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 11:19:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2008/07/23/trips-through-the-ischia/</guid>
      <description>You can make as many trips as you want on this island and you will still find some other places where to go. I can say that one week is not long enough for it. If you like hiking you need to see the vulcan which is responsible for all the thermal springs around the island. The name of the vulcan is Monte Epomeo and it is still active but it is not seen outwardly (except the springs).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>