<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cerova on Ajka&#43;Andrej</title>
    <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/cerova/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cerova on Ajka&#43;Andrej</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 16:32:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ajka-andrej.com/tags/cerova/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer memories</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/10/03/summer-memories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 16:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2017/10/03/summer-memories/</guid>
      <description>There was no time to write about summer holidays. But at least, I would like to post some photos now. Olivia wanted to mount a go kart with her grandpa and she drew a frame for it in the kindergarden. This year we managed to swim a couple of times in the swimming pool in the backyard, ride horses (I had to as well, because I was afraid that the horse was too big for Dominik) and we made a trip to Korlátko (about an hour of walking) and we walked through the Dolné diery in Vrátna valley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mushrooms</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/10/12/mushrooms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 11:09:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/10/12/mushrooms/</guid>
      <description>Finally, we managed to go to gather mushrooms, what we dreamed about all the summer. We dressed properly, put hats on our heads, equipped ourselves with baskets and knives and set off into the forest. Besides youthful mushrooms peeping out of the ground we found also lots of old, mouldy or dried mushrooms and we obviously came at the end of the mushroom season, but we still managed to gather a nice amount of healthy ones and when I consider three-hour walk through the forest, we were very satisfied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rozbehy and Korlátka</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/07/rozbehy-and-korlatka/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2010 13:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/07/rozbehy-and-korlatka/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend, on the occasion of the nice weather and a meeting with our parentsafter Christmas, we went on a small trip. It was pretty much only a nice walking within afternoon rest, but in the warm weather it was quite weary and I think more people from our group appreciated that the road back led through the forest. From Cerová we went on the winding road up the hill into a neighbouring village Rozbehy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potatoes and other</title>
      <link>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/06/potatoes-and-other/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 16:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajka-andrej.com/2010/08/06/potatoes-and-other/</guid>
      <description>Since we have lived in Munich, we eat more meat, wholemeal bread, vegetables and fruit. On Sunday, everything except a bakery and Biergarten is closed and so on the way from the church we always enjoy the fresh bread rolls and when the weather is nice we spend the afternoon somewhere out in the park. Given the prevalence of organic and bio products in the supermarkets, it happens quite often that these kinds of fruits or vegetables or eggs from free range hens wander to our basket.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>